You know, there's nothing like
the experience of raising your first dog.
The simple joy of walking side by side
with your buddy...
...out in the fresh air, throwing a stick.
Spending some quiet time,
just you and your very best friend.
Of course, that wasn't my experience.
That kid's not even me.
That's me.
And that crazy hound I'm chasing
is Marley, the world's worst dog.
Sorry.
Or so I thought.
But our story begins
before Marley was born...
...four years before,
on my wedding day...
...which happened to be the day
of the worst freak spring blizzard...
...in the history of southern Michigan,
the same day our car broke down.
But we didn't care.
Oh, God, that feels so good.
So, what do you think that means,
a blizzard on your wedding day?
Is that good luck? Is that bad luck?
I think it's good luck.
-How did I get you?
-What?
Honestly, how did I--?
How did I get that lucky?
Well, you know...
...I get asked that question all the time.
Come on. Are you kidding, honey?
You're part of the plan.
-The plan?
-My plan.
Step one, meet an incredibly sweet,
smart, sexy man.
Done. Step two?
Marry you instead.
Then step three--
-I don't think I can take any more.
-You don't want to hear step three?
-What's step three?
-It's easy.
-Be gentle.
-Move someplace warmer.
I knew you were gonna say that.
-Okay.
-Thank you.
-All right, you know you got this, right?
-Oh, yeah. I got it.
-Who are you?
-I'm John Grogan?
No, you're John frigging Grogan,
who's about to get a job as a reporter...
...for a major metropolitan newspaper.
-I don't feel like getting out of the car.
-Well, you have to.
-Why don't we drive around the block?
-No, baby. Come on, get out of the car.
Get out.
-Now, who am I again?
-Oh, please.
-Sebastian says you won some award?
-Mitchy. Yeah, I have a Mitchy.
It's like a Pulitzer,
but from western Michigan.
A Mitchy.
So tell me, what made you leave
the estimable Kalamazoo Gazette?
Well, as you know, Sebastian and I
were in college together, and he--
He was always saying
how great South Florida is...
...and that maybe my wife and I
might enjoy it here...
...so we decided to come down here.
-Are you a comedian too?
-Excuse me?
Like your friend over here?
-No.
-He's walking a very thin line.
It's a good thing he knows how to write.
So your wife is Jenny Havens?
Yes. Jenny Grogan, because
we're married. She took my name.
-She get the job at the Post?
-Yes, she did.
-Why didn't they want you over there?
-Well, I didn't apply.
Jenny's more of a feature writer,
and I'm more of a straight news writer.
I thought this would be a better fit
for that.
Think you're better
than the journalism-school graduates...
...that came here looking for work
this morning?
I don't know if I'm better. I--
What I do know is that I have a tendency
to surprise myself.
Ten years ago I was doing bong hits
and playing "Donkey Kong."
I never dreamed I'd get into college,
but I did, and I graduated with honors.
And I never thought I'd get a job
at a real newspaper, but I did.
And I certainly never thought I'd get a girl
like Jenny Havens to marry me...
...but I did.
So?
They already got a guy
on the Metro desk.
-Yeah.
-I'm sorry, honey.
So they're putting me on a little thing
they like to call "Desert Storm."
-You got the job?
-Got the job.
You got the job, baby.
Oh, John Grogan, I knew it.
I just knew it.
Okay, look. Watch this. Look.
See what happens? Job: done.
-So, what's next? Lunch?
-House.
--that can transmit
remote television pictures...
...of Iraqi ships and other targets.
Did you get to the quote
about the speed bumps yet?
-"If they save even one life--"
-"It would be worth it.
And with that,
Janet Dickerson's eyes filled with tears."
Filled with tears.
-Do you like that or is it too corny?
-Yeah.
-No.
-Is it a little over-the-top?
Hey, honey, what happened
to the Desert Storm piece?
That's it. The injured girl's dad's
in Kuwait. Is that not in there?
I think they cut that.
They even--
They spelled your name wrong.
-"John Gorgan."
-You're kidding.
-Let me see that. Are you joking?
-Forget it.
You know what? It's good. It's really
good. It's got the facts, it's got color.
-It's a really solid piece.
-Thanks.
I tried to breathe some life into it,
you know?
Yes.
I like this article.
I'm almost done with yours.
This idea of voting machines
sounds really efficient.
When you get to the next page...
...you'll see that I talk
about what could happen.
-Oh, okay, I see, it continues.
-Yeah.
But actually,
the rest of it is really just okay.
-It's actually kind of boring.
-No, no, it's-- I'm enjoying this.
They really gave you a lot of space.
Oh, damn. Killed another one.
How am I ever supposed to take care
of a kid if I can't even keep a plant alive?
Well, what did you expect, man?
You bought a house.
-A house with a spare room.
-What's the matter with a spare room?
It's empty, John,
that's what's wrong with it.
And you know what else is empty?
-Her womb.
-I'm worried Jenny's at like step seven.
-What?
She's got her whole life organized
and planned out according to these steps.
Okay, that's scary. Unbelievable.
You want my advice?
Get her, like, a bird
or a puppy or something.
What, like a parakeet?
Something other than you
that she has to take care of.
You got a kid, you're a dad.
You're not you anymore.
-You got a dog, you're a master.
-Master.
-You're still a guy.
-Still got a life.
-Exactly.
-And a dog.
Yeah, but you've stopped her clock
for a few years.
-I never had a dog.
-Nothing to it.
Feed them, walk them,
let them out now and again.
But it doesn't really matter.
You're not gonna take care of it, Jenny is.
-Sebastian!
-Yo.
Your travel's been approved.
Hit the road.
-Where are you going?
-I'm going to Colombia.
I got a guy down there that says
he can put me next to Pablo Escobar.
I'm doing a piece.
I follow a single coca leaf
from the jungle to the streets of Miami.
Sounds like a good idea.
You gotta be careful down there--
Gorgan!
-Grogan.
-Grodin. A fire at the county dump.
-Methane leak.
-Methane?
Yeah, I want two paragraphs
for the blotter.
Methane.
Woodward and Bernstein,
eat your heart out.
What kind of dog?
-You remember Caroline?
-The nurse?
She was a nursery-school teacher,
I don't know.
Anyway, she had this great dog, Daisy.
-It was a Labradoodle.
-"Labradoodle"?
-Maybe a Labrador.
-All right, get her a Labrador.
Supposed to be just like kids,
only easier to train.
"Labradoodle"? Come on.
-This does not smell like an IHOP.
-We got a little surprise first.
Here we go.
Now, I want you to walk right here,
my dear.
Okay.
-Come on.
-Oh, God.
-Okay.
-Are you Grogan?
-Yes.
-Expected you an hour ago.
You're gonna like this. Step up.
It's all right. Okay?
-Sorry about the mess.
-Okay.
-And the noise. And the smell.
-What's happening?
Come on.
-Can I look?
-No, no. Almost, almost.
-Okay. Okay, ready?
-Really?
One, two, three, go.
-Happy birthday.
-What?
-God, they're adorable.
-Get in.
Oh, my-- My birthday's not for a month.
Oh, that's okay,
they can't leave for three weeks anyway.
-John, we didn't discuss this.
-I know, but it was a surprise. You can't.
-Hi, guys.
-Just rescued the mom last month.
Family that gave her up
didn't even know she was pregnant.
-You sure we're ready for this?
-Well, like I told you...
...you gotta wait three weeks
before you can bring them home.
-I'm not even gonna be here.
-Why?
-I'll be in Gainesville, covering that trial.
-That's okay.
It'll give me a chance to bond with him
and get a head start on training him.
Get him squared away
before you get home.
-That's true.
-Yeah.
-Well, how are we gonna pick one?
-Girls are 300, boys are 275.
Except for that little guy there.
Him you could have for 200 even.
This one? You're so sweet.
You're like a little clearance puppy.
-Hello, puppy.
-This one likes you.
Clearance Puppy likes you.
-Well, that's your guy.
-I was gonna pick you anyway.
Don't tell anybody.
Don't tell the others.
-Honey, be careful.
-We gotta double-time it a little bit here.
-I really wish I didn't have to go.
-It's gonna be great.
You spent eight months on this trial.
I'm jealous.
Really? Tax evasion?
That's what makes you jealous?
Well, it's sexier than speed bumps.
-Call me the minute you get him home.
-Okay. Okay.
-We also have to come up with a name.
-Yes, well, let's brainstorm it.
I'll just call him Clearance Puppy
till you get back.
Are you gonna be okay?
-Worried about me with a puppy?
-I am.
-Me, John frigging Grogan? Come on.
-I know.
-Goodbye. I love you. You look pretty.
-Thank you. I love you. Bye.
How you doing there, buddy?
Kind of a big day for you.
Let's listen to the radio.
Awkward silences.
You like that? You like Bob Marley?
Bob. Would that be a good name? Bob.
Bob. Come here, Bob.
Or Robert when you got older?
More dignified?
Marley? You like that.
That has a nice ring to it.
Okay, whoa, come on.
It's better if you ride shotgun...
...because we don't wanna have
a car crash on our first real day together.
Okay, come here. Come here.
It's a big day. You can ride over here.
Maybe it's okay today,
just this one time.
If we get pulled over, we explain.
We explain what the circumstances are.
-What happened?
-The Millers got robbed.
Again? Good thing I got a watchdog.
Hey, buddy.
-He's got some teeth.
-Oh, yeah.
I'll just get him some water.
You're not gonna keep him
in the backyard.
Gonna keep him in the garage
till I get him housetrained.
Marley, no, no. Marley, Marley, Marley.
Oh, no.
Hey, you've had enough food, Marley.
You've had two bowls of kibble.
You had half a seat belt in the car.
How are you still eating?
I don't understand where you can put it.
And here's the little box
where Marley is going to bunk down.
Pretty cozy. All right, good night.
You're gonna be okay.
I'm just right inside.
Sleep tight.
All right.
Come on, Marley.
You're killing me, you know that?
Oh, we've got some cleaning up to do
before the missus gets back.
All right.
I'm off to the airport, and you're gonna
ride out the rain right in your little box.
Just a little thunder.
Back in a flash.
-Hi.
-Get in here.
Oh, my God.
-Hi.
-How are you?
-How's my puppy?
-I'm okay.
A little tired, but I'm trying to stay dry.
-Really, how is he?
-He's waiting for you.
Do you hear that? Is that--?
I think that's Marley.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Look at this.
-This is not how I left it.
-How long did you leave him here?
I left him for maybe an hour, tops.
Did he eat the dry wall?
-Oh, that's not right.
-That's-- One little dog did that.
Oh, honey, you're shaking.
Does thunder scare you, mister?
Sweet boy.
Oh, look at us.
So I'm in this cave,
and I can feel the machine guns.
There's like nine of them around me.
-What, like AK-47s?
-Kalashnikovs.
-And then Escobar comes in and says--
-Escobar?
Yeah, he says,
"I read your piece on Qaddafi...
...and I think
you captured his narcissism perfectly."
-Can you believe that?
-Some of it.
I wish you could've been there.
But who's gonna cover the power struggle
down at the Rotary club in Delray?
Oh, it's been just crazy.
-Your time will come, amigo.
-I'll drink to that.
That was crazy. Oh, my God.
-Oh, my God.
-That is the cutest thing I've ever seen.
Say hello, Marley.
-Can I hold him?
-Of course. Here you go.
-You're so cute.
-Oh, I love their puppy breath.
Oh, have you guys
met my buddy Sebastian?
Sebastian, Viviana. Nice to meet you.
-Hi.
-Hi, I'm Shannon.
-Hey, he's a beauty, isn't he?
-He's adorable.
I actually think the
"puppy instead of a baby" idea is working.
Yeah, it's certainly working for me.
Can I take him home?
You're so cute, yes, you are.
I can't let you have the puppy, but
you might have a shot with the big dog.
-Oh, yeah?
-I'm easy.
-Oh, you're easy?
-And I do tricks. I'm paper-trained.
Oh, no, no.
-Oh, my God.
-Marley.
-Marley!
-Come back, puppy.
Marley! Marley!
Marley!
-Marley!
-Got him. Thanks.
-You have to be more careful, man.
It's our first week together,
so we're still working out the kinks.
You shouldn't bring a dog to
the dog beach until he's trained.
Okay, can I get the dog back?
Never let him off leash
unless you have complete confidence.
This is the only beach in two counties
where dogs aren't banned.
Cops see anybody peeing or pooping
down by the water, they'll shut us down.
Why is that funny to you?
I'm just very immature.
Calvin!
See? Aren't you glad you're not Calvin?
See how easy you got it?
Marley, stop.
Marley. Marley.
Honey, the dog's got my....
Marley, no.
Marley,
you can't go through a screen door.
Hey, Steve.
-Happy Thanksgiving.
-You too.
Marley.
It just seems like there's other guys.
Don't understand why you thought of me.
-I'm in a bind.
-Yeah, but I'm a reporter, not a columnist.
John, you'll get better pay.
You can pick your own hours
and choose your own topics.
Why are you hesitating?
-I'm thinking.
-No, you're hesitating.
I'm offering a promotion
and you're hesitating.
I never saw myself as a columnist.
Oh, well, think of it as one of those times
when you surprise yourself.
Okay.
It's only a couple of times a week
until I get a replacement for Jerry.
Then you can go back to doing
whatever it was you were doing.
-What were you doing?
-Obituaries, methane leaks.
-Are you okay with this?
-Yes.
You don't seem thrilled.
-No, it's a promotion.
-We can take away the raise if you like.
No, no, I'm-- Thank you.
All right, now you're talking.
Go on, get to work.
Marley.
I think he dislocated my shoulder.
He doesn't even heel.
Doesn't walk, he just sprints.
Marley. God.
Marley, stop. Down here. Come on.
I had to pull him off three dogs today.
-Poodles?
-Among others.
I say we give him away to a farm.
Isn't that usually what you do
with dogs that are out of control?
Well, usually you train them.
Or you train them.
Come on, down. Come on.
What are you doing?
Arnie gave me a column.
Are you kidding? Baby, that's great.
Oh, yeah, it's a big honor.
I get to write about zoning laws
and give my opinion on yard sales.
Whoa, down, boy.
Easy with the enthusiasm.
No, it's just I don't even read this crap
when other people write it.
Now I'm supposed to, you know,
write two columns a week?
And you've got nothing for Tuesday.
-No, I got nothing for Tuesday.
-I bet you're gonna think of something.
See, this gives me a little inspiration,
but it's not for a column. It's more like--
Look at Marley.
Now he's eating the floor.
Marley, stop.
Marley, you're incorrigible.
"Incorrigible." I don't believe in that word.
Every dog wants to learn.
Hey, come here, baby.
Yes, you're a good girl.
You're a good girl, yes, you are.
Of course, they can't learn
if their parents are weak-willed.
Yeah, well,
I'm pretty strong-willed, but....
-Marley. Sorry.
-Say hello to Marley.
So which of you is gonna be the trainer?
We both thought we would.
We'd like him to listen to both of us.
We're married, so yeah.
No, no, no.
A dog can only have one master.
Which one of you
has the most natural authority...
...in your own relationship?
Well, maybe I'll stand over there
for the beginning.
I thought so. Shall we?
-Jeez.
-All right. Sit.
-Sit.
Sit.
Sit. Marley. Okay, Marley. Marley, sit.
This, class, is a classic example...
...of a dog who has foolishly
been allowed to believe...
...he is the alpha male of the pack.
And therefore,
he can never be a happy animal.
Yeah, he looks pretty miserable.
You, joker.
Rotate in. And lose the sunglasses.
A dog likes to be looked at in the eye.
-I got it. Okay.
-Okay.
-You got him? Okay.
-Yep.
So collar your dogs.
Good boy.
All right, dogs on the left.
On the count of three.
One, two, three. Let's go.
Walk. Walk.
-Very nice.
-Heel.
-Go.
-Very good.
Good.
-Hey.
-Correct him. Rein in that dog.
All right. All right, class.
Come on, let's line up again.
Class, it's a simple question of
having confidence in your own authority.
I shall now demonstrate a simple walk,
all right?
-Come here.
-Mr. Grogan.
-Sorry.
-May I?
All right, even an unruly dog
likes to obey his leader.
Marley, heel.
There.
Marley. Marley. Marley! Marley!
Marley.
Careful. Marley, no! Marley!
-Are you okay?
-That's it. He is out.
-He usually only does this with poodles.
-That dog is a bad influence on the others.
No. Leg humping is like a virus.
Once it takes hold of the group.... No.
-Okay.
-He has got to go.
It was maybe your hair.
It reminded him of a poodle.
-Never bring him back.
-Okay.
Right from the beginning,
she had me in her sights.
-I know, she really did.
-Marley wouldn't take any of her crap.
That's why he got kicked out.
You are now the world's worst dog.
You've been kicked out
of obedience school.
You know,
there is something else that we could do.
No, I know, we just-- We get an--
No, no, no.
I'm smiling, but I'm serious. No.
It's not gonna be so bad, buddy.
You'll see. Sex is overrated.
I can't tell you that,
because you know it's a lie.
Poor son of a bitch.
Okay, you wanna come up?
Yeah, that's the least I can do.
-Get a little fresh air.
-Marley.
Oh, gosh,
it's like he's walking the plank.
That's what breaks my heart.
He's so happy.
-He doesn't know what's coming.
-Honey, he's gonna be fine.
-Oh, no, no, now I'm getting nervous.
-He's okay. He's just getting a little air.
It's like Of Mice and Men.
-Whoa, Marley.
-John, please, grab him.
-Oh, my God.
-He's making a break for it.
-Marley!
-He's onto our evil plan.
-Pull over.
-I can't stop here. I can't.
-Honey, pull over.
-I'm trying to. There's a ton of traffic.
-Come on, pull over.
-All right, all right, all right.
Oh, jeez.
-I need a little help here.
-I know.
-Hey. Get a leash.
-Oh, shut up.
Hey, he's losing his balls today.
Cut him some slack.
-Got him? Careful, careful.
-I got him.
And this is a rough draft because I want--
I'd like to take another pass at it.
The beginning, I think I might wanna--
I think we can maybe lose that
because I think it gets a little bit jokey.
I just reread it.
I didn't think it worked at all.
-I'm sorry. I'm gonna do the zoning piece.
-Wait a minute.
What are you apologizing for?
This stuff is hysterical.
-Really?
-I'm laughing my head off at this.
Getting kicked out of obedience school,
the humping, the great escape.
That's really funny stuff.
I'm laughing my ass off.
It's hysterical stuff. Run it the way it is.
Thanks.
Listen, you know what makes it work?
What makes it work
is that you put yourself into it.
-I like that.
-Good.
Look, I know you're a reporter and all...
...but could you do a few more like this?
-Sure.
-Great.
-Okay, great.
-And tell your dog not to feel too bad.
Sooner or later, we all lose our balls.
Right. Good to know.
Woke up to a kiss from Marley.
Went for a walk that turned into a run.
Took an airboat ride.
Wrote about the death of the Everglades.
Planted an orange tree in the backyard.
Threw sticks in the park.
Watched him swim.
Watched him steal some guy's Frisbee.
Bought new Frisbee. Gave Marley a bath.
Went to work with writer's block.
Hoped for inspiration to strike, nada.
Got a new shirt. Got a new keyboard.
Got the same old paycheck.
Went windsurfing with Sebastian.
Met his new girlfriend.
Met his other new girlfriend.
Watched models posing in the surf.
Wrote about the growth of South Beach.
Interviewed Gloria and Emilio Estefan
at the Cardozo Hotel.
Introduced Jenny,
who gushed like a teenager.
Went shopping.
Bought a Sharper Image pillow.
Slept like a baby. Caught Marley eating
the pillow. Hid the evidence from Jenny.
Cleaned up Marley's vomit.
Helped Jenny make dinner.
Overcooked the spaghetti.
Got into a food fight.
Proofread Jenny's column.
Read Sebastian's latest opus.
Went running with Marley
to burn off frustration.
Didn't see him chew the leash.
Chased him 15 blocks.
Had to call Jenny for a ride.
Wrote a column about gas prices.
Wrote about water prices.
Found one tiny orange on our tree.
Jenny very pleased with herself.
Found my first gray hair. Found
Jenny's first. Bought Jenny flowers.
Rescued our new mailman from Marley.
Rescued the UPS guy from Marley.
Invited my parents.
Took them out to dinner at a cool place.
Got in a fight with Dad over the check.
Got in a fight about money.
Got in a fight with Jenny about fighting.
Drove my parents. Listened to them
complain about not having grandchildren.
Tracked a hurricane heading for Florida.
Hid in the bathroom during the hurricane.
Sat in the dark for three days.
Wrote a column about looters.
Wrote about volunteers.
Wrote about air conditioning.
Watched Marley dig for treasure.
Spent Christmas with Jen's sister
and family in Orlando.
Left Marley at their house
to go to Disney World.
Had to buy them new baby furniture.
Saw Jen light up around the girls.
Got a flat driving home.
Wrote a column about state troopers.
Wrote about tollbooths.
Went to dinner to celebrate Jenny's raise.
Tied Marley to the table.
Marley, come here.
Chased Marley and the table.
Caught the table.
Wrote about Marley pulling the table.
Tried to write a column
about anything but Marley, nada.
Picked oranges from our tree.
Made orange juice.
Drove down to Miami for Bark
in the Park night at the Marlins game.
Brought Marley,
who turned out to be a fan.
Tried to stop him chasing a ball
in the stands.
on the field. Wrote about the ball game.
Took crap from Sebastian about it.
Met his new girlfriend.
Can't remember her name.
Went snorkeling. Cut my leg on coral.
Went to the emergency room.
Wrote a column about hospitals.
Went to an Easter-egg hunt
at Jenny's boss's in Boca.
Drank mimosas. Met a doctor
who does three liposuctions a day.
Wrote a column about nannies in Boca.
Wrote a column about women of Boca.
Wrote a column about writing columns.
Came home to find Jenny dancing
with Marley.
Tried to think of reasons
not to have a baby now...
...nada.
Why don't you just let him off the leash?
Because although I love him,
I don't trust him.
It's been two years.
He's never had an accident.
Because I never let him off leash.
We're not gonna be the guys who get
Dog Beach shut down, are we, Marley?
Nope.
Okay, so, what's next?
-Ice cream?
-No, I mean on your list.
-My list?
-Jen, the list.
Your play list you had when
we got married that had the game plan.
-It was basically my marching orders.
-My plan?
Your plan. I wanna know what's next.
Scare me.
-You really wanna know?
-Hit me.
Well, it's a tossup between a new roof...
Very practical.
--and a baby.
I could live with a few leaks.
-Really?
-Yeah, a couple.
But you know, a couple leaks
turn into maybe one big leak.
And then that big leak
becomes a very big responsibility.
That's true.
We may wanna think about
fixing a lot of things before we start--
Well, we already fixed Marley.
If we fix too many more things,
I think this conversation becomes moot.
John, are you serious?
Yeah. I think so.
You realize we're not talking
about an actual roof?
Yes, I got that.
About halfway through, I picked it up.
Good metaphor, though.
You're not just saying this
because it'll lead to funny columns?
Well, I mean, honey, come on.
I mean, if I get some funny columns...
...that's collateral damage
I think we can live with.
I mean, I'm ready. I mean, if you are.
Instead of trying to have a baby...
...why don't we just stop
trying not to have one?
Okay, if I'm following you correctly,
and I think I am...
...this is the part where we head back,
we take it off, and we get it on.
Yes, but you'll--
It'll have a little more romance than that.
Yeah, we'll get some candles, some Sade.
Of course.
Sade.
-Honey?
-Yeah.
Did you have kibble today?
Marley, come on. Marley, go.
He's a dog.
He won't know what he's looking at.
Trust me, he knows,
and he resents the hell out of me.
-Go on, Marley. You have to go.
-Oh, baby, please focus.
Okay, you're right.
Good. Good.
It's even better than the last one.
-Thank you.
-You're very good, Gorgan.
I like that piece you did in Boca
on the woman. What did you call her?
-Bocahontas.
Is that true?
She had her boobs done four times?
-That's what she said.
-Hysterical.
And is that true about you and your wife
trying to have a kid?
Well, you know, we're not really trying,
because we don't wanna--
-How does that work?
-What do you mean?
-Well, I mean, are you having sex?
-Yeah.
-Did you pull the goalie?
Then you're trying. Congratulations.
Good work.
-You're not "trying" trying.
-Oh, yeah.
Of course, you'd know that
if you ever read my column.
All due respect,
but does anybody ever read your column?
Come on, I bring Marley here to help you
run your game on these poor girls...
...and this is the thanks we get.
-How long you been at it?
-A few months.
-What changed your mind?
-Well, here's the thing.
I'm actually married to someone,
and I care about what she wants.
-Well, is it what you want?
-Yeah.
-I guess that answers my other question.
-Yeah?
I'm about to do a piece on the growth
of the domestic drug trade for The Times.
You're freelancing
for The New York Times?
Yeah, yeah, but it's a big story,
too big for one guy...
...and I was hoping you'd write it
with me.
Are you kidding me?
-It would be a chance to work together.
-Yeah, I would love that.
Of course, it will be a lot of work,
a lot of travel.
I would hope so.
Maybe not the best job
for somebody with a kid on the way.
Well, that's not necessarily happening
right this very second.
Let me talk it ov--
There she is.
-Honey, how are you?
-Hi.
I'm just calling to let you know
that there is a naked woman in your bed.
Why don't the two of you get started
and I'll be there as soon as I can?
That's very funny.
But seriously, can you come home now?
Hey. We're home.
Hi.
You know the baby thing?
I've been thinking
maybe we should take a break.
You know?
I mean, obviously it's not working...
...and maybe it's nature's way
of saying now's not the right timing.
I mean, maybe it's a sign
that we're not quite ready for this, that--
-I mean, have we really thought this--?
-John.
I'm pregnant.
Great.
-Great. Really?
-Yeah.
-Yes.
-You were just saying--?
No, don't worry, that was like--
It sounds so awkward now.
Like I just had this, like, very, you know,
idiotic soliloquy that doesn't apply...
...and I'm really excited.
-Do you wanna start over?
-I would love to.
-That would be great. Can we? Good.
-By all means.
-I'm pregnant.
-What? No! Yes!
-Don't make the same mistake I did.
-What?
There's gonna come a time very soon
where her ankles are gonna swell up.
No, no, I'm ready for that.
She's gonna have blotches
all over her face.
-Yeah.
-She'll be 40 pounds overweight.
-She'll be throwing up all the time.
-I'm not ready for that.
She's gonna look at you and say,
"You bastard. You did this to me."
What happened to the glow,
the, you know, the--?
There's no glow.
Get her a gift.
That will dissipate some of the anger.
Some earrings, a bracelet.
That's thoughtful. That's a good idea.
In fact, maybe I'll get on it right now.
There's a jewelry store on the corner.
Mention my name.
Oh, John.
It's just beautiful.
-Honey, thank you.
-You're welcome.
I was just walking by
just thinking of you...
...and I saw that in the window and I go,
"I'm getting this."
-That's so sweet.
-Yeah, well....
-Do you like it?
-I love it.
Put it on. Or let me put it on.
I think it's better luck.
-Where'd it go? I just had it.
-You just set it down. Did you drop it?
-No, I put it right here.
-Well, it didn't just disappear.
Oh, God.
-Marley. No, Marley, spit it out.
-No, go to the kitchen, go to the kitchen.
Okay. No, no, no.
Marley, I have a treat. Come here.
Stay. Marley, stay.
Good boy. Yeah.
-Marley!
-Good going, honey.
Marley.
Come here, Marley.
Jeez.
-Okay, okay. Marley, drop it.
-Marley.
-Gross. Is it there?
Oh, honey, I don't see it.
Marley, you've gotta lay off
the mangoes.
You know, years ago,
when I imagined my life...
...somehow standing in the backyard
hosing down your crap...
...looking for my wife's swallowed,
recycled, ass-kissing gift...
...never jumped to mind.
Which shows you've gotta dream big
because-- Jackpot.
My, that's a lovely necklace.
It's so shiny.
-Yes, it is.
-And how's that crazy dog of yours?
I read your columns every week.
-So you're the one.
-I am.
You'll get a kick
out of next week's column.
The heartbeat will be very fast,
like a little train.
-That's normal.
-Is it too early to tell the sex?
I-- Not that I care.
It can be male, female,
whatever sex he wants.
Unambiguous genitalia
if I had my druthers, but....
Hang on.
Sometimes you can't hear it.
-You're 10 weeks, right?
-Monday I'll be 10 weeks.
Well, it might be a little too early for that.
Let's go right to the sonogram.
Did you bring your blank tape?
-Oh, yes.
-Yes, yes.
That's warm.
-Let's get a good picture for you first.
-Okay.
It'll be right up on the monitor here.
Excuse me. I'll be just a minute.
-Hey, guys.
-Hi.
Let's take a look at your baby, shall we?
All right.
Is there anything there?
Not what you would expect to see
at 10 weeks.
-I'm not quite 10 weeks.
-Monday.
-It's still, I guess, nine weeks.
-Yeah, nine weeks.
There's no heartbeat, Jen.
I'm very, very sorry.
These things, they happen sometimes.
We don't know why, though.
But you're young, you have your health.
Couple months, you guys can try again.
I'm sorry. All right?
I'm gonna leave you alone for a moment,
and then we'll talk more.
I'm very sorry.
Well, in a couple months,
we can try again, okay?
Want some tea?
Hey, you know what?
I was thinking that we....
We still have those tickets
from your parents...
...for the honeymoon in Ireland.
We could finally do that.
Maybe take some time off.
Jenny?
-Oh, he's big.
-Oh, yeah, he's a hundred pounds.
-Now, he just wants to say hello here.
-Yeah, he loves people.
Now, just be calm and you just stay still.
And you're a dog person, right?
-Actually, I'm--
-Ready? Here we go.
Marley, you can say hello. Oh, no, no, no.
No, don't let him do that.
You just knee him if he does that.
It shouldn't happen all the time,
just when you walk through the door.
This will tell you everything
you need to know.
-I've got the bags here.
-You got everything? Okay. Thank you.
-All right. Come on, honey.
-Will you get the door?
-Okay, here we are.
-Come on, honey, we're really late.
Debby, welcome to our home.
Marley is a spirited dog
who loves interaction.
We've never left him before...
...but we are sure he'll behave
just as he does when we're at home.
There are just a few things about Marley
you're gonna need to know.
He eats three times a day.
If he looks starved, feed him again.
Now, of course, all of this food
is gonna have to go somewhere...
...so use the blue pooper-scooper
and watch your step.
Don't worry about the color.
He likes mangoes.
Marley is not allowed
to drink out of the toilet...
...so be sure to keep the lid closed
and the brick on the lid.
Actually, you might wanna just
keep the bathroom door shut in general.
Like most dogs,
Marley needs a lot of exercise...
...so try to take him for a walk or a run
every morning and every evening.
Marley.
Let go, let go, let go. Marley!
And be sure to lock the doors
and windows before you go to sleep.
But don't worry,
Marley is an excellent watchdog.
You can rest easy at night
knowing he's on the job.
Thunderstorms are his weak point.
You can give him sedatives
if you think a storm is arriving.
Okay. Here you go.
Marley. Marley, come back here.
He doesn't like them...
...so push them down his throat
as far as they go.
Welcome, welcome. I'm Mrs. Butterly.
Now, finally, we do not allow Marley
to get up on any piece of furniture...
...or chew on anything except his toys.
Other than that, enjoy him.
Love, Jenny and John.
We serve tea every day at 4
and dinner at 6 sharp.
Oh, and these blankets are woolen.
Good heat in them.
-So they're electric?
-Oh, not in this house.
My brother died in a fire,
God rest his soul.
In this room, actually.
Oh, not to worry. It's been repapered.
Well, good night to you both
and God bless you.
Thank you. You-- Bless you.
That was just weird.
Oh, gosh.
Honey, I know that we haven't had sex
since, you know...
...but I don't think
we're breaking that streak tonight.
No, I don't wanna break the streak here.
This doesn't feel--
I mean, I think I could, you know,
handle God watching and his mother...
...but not this little porcelain pontiff
right here.
It's July and I think I can see my breath.
-Honey, I can't feel my toes.
-That's not good.
I'm gonna check on that.
-Oh, good God.
-That's not the bed.
It's the shrieks
of oversexed souls in hell.
Do you wanna join them?
Really?
We don't have to.
I know, but the idea that it hasn't
happened here in 50 years is just....
It's kind of turning me on.
Honey, I missed you.
-Marley. Hi, honey.
-Marley.
-Oh, come here. Oh, my God.
-Hi. We missed you so much.
-Hey, Debby.
-Hey.
There were 11 thunderstorms
while you were gone.
Eleven. And you were right,
he doesn't like thunderstorms.
Okay, yeah, 11.
That's a lot of thunderstorms.
Oh, and just so you know,
I am a dog person, but that's not a dog.
That is evil with a dog face
that is humping my leg...
...and peeing on your carpet.
-Marley. Marley.
-Marley, stop that.
Marley, come on, it's just thunder.
No barking.
Marley, come on. It's just thunder.
Marley, come on.
Jenny!
Can you help me out here?
I got 20 minutes to file this column,
and I gotta--
Jenny?
-The luck of the Irish.
-What?
Oh, God. John. Honey.
John. John, wake up, honey. It's time.
Okay, what do I need?
Oh, these will be comfortable. Okay.
You all right? You all right?
Are you okay?
It's okay, I'm not gonna hurt her.
Try not to scream.
I don't want him to kill me.
You remembered
to install the car seat, right?
They won't let us take the baby home--
-I wouldn't forget.
-I know, I'm sorry.
-Got that right there?
-I think I got it. What else?
Yeah, come on, Marley,
help me out here.
You can chew through drywall, Marley.
This is nothing for you.
Good, yeah.
No, no, you're gonna stay here.
I'll leave you this bone
to keep you busy now.
Hopefully no thunderstorms. And I'm off.
Who's your daddy? Come here.
Here's the thing.
In about two minutes,
we're gonna bring home the baby...
...and you'd be doing me a really big favor
if you didn't freak out.
And I'm gonna try to do the same.
-Are you ready?
-I'm ready, yes.
-Okay.
-Hi, come here.
Hi, baby. Oh, hi. Hi, sweetie. Hi, Marley.
Come on. Come here. Okay?
-Marley.
-Would be a bummer if you ate the baby.
-Just....
-Look, Marley, this is Patrick.
Not to be confused with a chew toy,
although it may look like one.
Say hi. See, honey?
He's not eating the baby.
Very good.
Yeah. No, I have a quote for it
right here.
Well, have Legal call them again
and get a release for it.
They told me it was on the record.
I don't-- Patrick, honey,
be careful with those toys.
You know Marley gets--
Carla, I'm not talking to you.
Will you just call them and get a release?
I'll call you back. I'll call you right back.
Ready?
How far do you wanna go?
Those days are over for us, amigo.
We had a good run, though.
Hey, look. There's Daddy.
Come on, Marley.
This is gonna sound crazy,
but what's that thing called...
...when you owe money on a house?
-It starts with an M.
-Mortgage.
Mortgage.
Is it possible to be this tired?
You know what?
I'm gonna get up with him tonight.
No, you won't. You don't hear him.
-Yeah, you're right.
-Yeah, well, why?
I'm just a blessedly sound sleeper.
I do have to go
into the office tomorrow, though.
-Will you watch him then for me?
-It would be my pleasure.
-How long are we talking about?
-I don't know.
-It's not quite what you expected, huh?
-I don't know what I expected.
I never thought Marley
would seem like the easy one.
I know. I know, but you know what?
We adjusted to him...
...and we'll adjust to the baby.
I'm just trying to remember us
from before.
-You mean those younger...
-Yeah.
...sexier, better-looking people?
-I remember them.
-I remember them vaguely.
-I miss them.
They're here.
They're here, they're just really tired.
What, now you're jealous?
Stay here.
-Call the police.
-Okay.
Hey, hey, hey. Are you all right?
What happened?
He told me not to scream
or he'd stab me, but I screamed.
-I screamed and he stabbed me.
-Sit down, just sit down.
It's okay, it's all right.
-Where's your mother?
-At work.
It's okay, it's not that bad.
Keep your hand placed right here.
Okay.
My wife called the police,
so everything's gonna be okay.
In all the time I've lived here,
I've never gotten your name.
-Lisa.
-Okay, I'm gonna sit right here, Lisa.
You're gonna keep your hands
placed there...
...and we're gonna wait for the police
to get here.
They're gonna take care of this, all right?
Okay? Look at me.
It's all right. It's all right.
Safest neighborhood?
In terms of crime,
I'd say you're looking at Boca.
Boca?
I was afraid you were gonna say that.
-That's the way it is, John.
-Okay, thanks.
Boca. Not so bad.
You got kids playing in the street.
I don't know, what do you guys think?
We might live here one day,
if we can afford it.
There we go. I can get you right here.
Stay. Marley, no.
Marley. Marley.
And don't you love this kitchen?
Look at the state-of-the-art appliances.
And my favorite part, the pool, is....
-Why don't we look over here?
-Sorry, can I get a brochure?
-Sure.
-Thank you. Looks nice.
Whose dog is that?
Jenny?
Honey.
Jen?
Hey. You okay?
-Yeah, I'm good. Where have you been?
-I wanna show you something.
It's a house. Now, it's a little pricey,
but I think we can do it.
-Boca?
-I know, I know.
But Frank Bennet on the Metro desk
says it's the safest neighborhood.
-I'm just not sure now is the right time.
-But when is the right time?
After one of us gets stabbed
in the driveway?
-John.
-Honey, it's cramped in here.
This was supposed to be
a three-year house.
I know. I know that.
I just don't think we can afford
to buy a new one.
But, honey, we can.
With both our salaries--
Honey, I'm pregnant.
Really?
Are you sure?
Come here.
Pretty sure.
Four for four.
-Hold on.
-That's great.
Congratulations.
-Come on.
-I mean, to both of us.
Oh, yes. Oh, you're such a good boy.
-Another baby.
-I know.
Honey, I think I have to quit my job.
You don't have to do that.
We can get some help.
No, I don't want any help. I really don't.
I really-- I just don't want--
Will you hand me that pacifier?
I just--
I don't wanna be one of those people...
...that sees their child
for an hour at night.
-I don't.
-I know, but you love your work and--
I do, I love my work, honey,
but this is killing me.
When I'm at the office,
I just wanna be here.
And when I'm here,
I am constantly thinking about work.
And I just know
that I'm doing both jobs halfway.
Well, you're not doing them halfway.
Look, if I have to give up something,
I do not wanna give up this.
Why should I give you a raise?
Give me one good reason.
-Because I'm doing a good job?
-Is that a question?
No, but since I took over the column,
the readership's doubled.
So you are doing a good job.
Yes, if you go by the circulation
and popularity.
Okay. Why not make it permanent?
What do you mean, like forever?
Yeah, that's what "permanent" means.
John, every bozo out there
would like to have their own column.
Everybody in that entire room.
And you've taken the column
and you've turned it into something fresh.
I know you don't wanna hear it,
but you're a really good columnist.
Why are you hesitating?
I just have this idea about myself,
you know, as a reporter.
Well, sometimes life comes up
with a better idea.
I'll tell you what.
You take on a daily column,
I will double your salary.
Gonna start you off
with some corn flakes.
The most important meal-- No, Marley.
Most important meal of the day. There.
I might take a little spoonful.
John, please, just take him for a sec.
I gotta take a shower. I gotta go.
But it happens every time.
Well, you've got to spend more time
with him.
Down.
Marley.
There you go.
-Okay, I'll do it, I'll do it.
-No, no, no, it's fine.
You say to spend more time with him,
and I do, and then you wanna take over.
I don't want you changing him
when you're mad.
-I'm not mad, I'm--
-Thank you. Come on.
Hi, baby. Come on, honey.
Oh, baby. I know, I know.
Oh, watch out. Oh, come on, Conor.
Come on, what?
What's the matter?
What do you need? What is it?
Do you want some food? Food? Milk?
No? Okay.
He's just colicky, Jen.
He'll grow out of it.
Well, here's an idea.
Why don't you stay home, and
I'll go to work while he grows out of it?
Sorry, I'm tired. Just go. Just go.
It's postpartum depression.
They're hormones go on tilt,
and they get depressed.
I remember
after my fourth kid was born...
...I'd wake up in the middle of the night
sometimes and my wife would be there...
...staring at me
with a meat cleaver in her hand.
I thought she was gonna kill me.
I still do.
You get her the gift?
-Yeah, and....
-Well, it usually works.
Okay, Janice, make him look pretty.
He's gonna have this picture
next to his byline for the next 20 years.
What are you doing? Get in here.
Patrick, honey, please, stop doing that.
You're gonna make him sick.
-Just eat it, okay?
-Careful, Patrick.
Remember what we did to Marley
when he didn't listen.
Honey, we really have to pick
out a color of fabric...
...for the curtains in the boys' room.
Okay, well, I don't know,
whatever you want.
I'd really like your help deciding.
No, let me get him.
Thank you.
Marley, just....
Marley. Bad dog. Marley. Marley, stop it.
Marley, let go. Let go.
Marley, let go. Marley.
Marley. Marley. Marley, get back here.
Get back here.
Marley. Marley. Bad dog.
Marley, get back here. Marley.
See, we were supposed to return these,
and now we have to pay for them.
-That's okay. Come on, just--
-No, it's not okay. It's not okay.
I told you not to leave anything edible
where he can get it.
I know, but you
wouldn't exactly say this is edible.
John, you know what I mean.
You said you'd get up early and walk him.
He chews things when he gets restless.
-I am gonna walk him. I just woke up.
-Know what? Forget it.
-I'm gonna do it myself.
-You don't have to--
Yes, I'm doing it myself.
You don't get it. She's gonna kill you.
You've got to take it easy.
We're both hanging by a thread.
-So who gets the dog if you guys split up?
-We're not splitting up.
-Out of the realm of possibility?
-Completely.
There's nothing she can do...
...no tantrum too big,
no depression too deep...
...no failure to perform wifely duties,
that would push you over?
Why do you jump right to splitting up?
Come on, buddy. Mend it, don't end it.
-So life is better with Jenny than without?
-Yes, what--?
Are you wearing a wire? Jen, are you--?
She's listening to this.
Jenny, yes, we had a fight,
but I still love you.
I mean, come on, buddy. I had
a fight with my wife. Let me just sulk.
I just wanna know if you're really happy.
Oh, wait, there she is.
-Where? Who?
-Give me the kid.
No, no, no, I can't be a party to this.
That's shameless.
This is gonna be even better
than the puppy.
No, not my son.
Marley, no. Please, please, Marley, no.
Please.
Marley! Marley, what are you--?
Marley, God, look at this.
Stop it. Why do you do this?
Why do you ruin everything? Go on.
Patrick! Are you okay? I'm sorry.
John, get that dog out of here.
I want that dog out of here right now.
-I'll take him for a walk.
-No, take him to that farm.
All right, buddy,
we're going to the farm again.
Hey, I'm serious. I'm not kidding.
-I can't take this anymore.
-What did he do?
Everything. What hasn't he done?
He's just a horrible, horrible animal.
Well, that's a little unfair.
No, what's unfair is that Conor
hasn't slept in two weeks...
...because of that dog's barking...
...that Patrick gets knocked down
twice a day...
...that I can't even think straight.
-And God forbid there's a hint of thunder.
-Just calm down for a second.
I know it's been a rough couple of months
with the new baby.
I understand that.
But I was talking with Arnie,
and postpartum depression--
Don't you dare.
I am not depressed. I am exhausted.
I am not angry
because of some condition.
I can't even go out for an hour
without the kids...
...because every babysitter
is terrified of Marley.
I know, but you said
you didn't wanna work anymore.
-We can get help, but you said--
-I don't need any help!
-Just get rid of the dog.
-That's not gonna happen, obviously.
-Please keep your voice down.
-Me keep my voice down?
Just get rid of the dog.
Everybody gets rid of their dogs.
-It's just a dog.
-I'm just a husband.
-Gonna get rid of me?
-I've thought about it.
-Oh, well, that makes two of us.
-What do you have to complain about?
What do I--? Oh, because
you're such a joy to be around?
Oh, you're such a jerk.
Nice to walk in
and feel like you're joining a chain gang.
Just a jerk.
Stop it.
It's your fault.
You gotta be kidding me.
Nope. It's just for a couple days
till things cool down at home.
A couple days will be all right.
You guys know each other,
so you should be okay.
You want a beer?
I'm all right.
Are you moving?
-Yeah.
-Where?
New York.
The Gray Lady came a-courting.
The Times offered you a permanent job?
Gave Arnie my notice last week.
-You didn't even say anything.
-I know. I'm sorry, I just....
It all happened so fast,
I'm not even used to the idea yet.
That's great. The New York Times.
It's what we always dreamed of.
Well, congratulations.
I mean, you deserve it.
-Thanks for looking after Marley.
-Yeah.
He's eating your briefcase right now.
-Shit.
-Marley. Marley, no.
-Two days, John, I'm serious.
-Sorry.
-Sorry, I didn't mean to wake you.
-I wasn't sleeping.
Where's Marley?
Sebastian's gonna watch him
for a few days.
I'd love to see that.
Just until I can find
a more permanent home.
This is his permanent home, John.
Marley's not going anywhere.
Honey, I'm sorry.
I just got overwhelmed.
No one tells you
how hard this is all gonna be.
Which part?
What? All of it.
Marriage, being a parent.
It's the hardest job in the world,
and nobody prepares you for that.
Nobody tells you
how much you have to give up.
I feel like they do tell you,
but, I don't know, you don't listen...
...or you think, "They're just miserable."
I've given up so much
of what made me who I am.
But I can't say that, because
I'm a very bad person if I say that.
But I feel that, I really do.
I feel it sometimes.
I just....
-I just want you to know that.
-I do know that.
-And you can say it. I say it.
-But I did make a choice.
I made a choice,
and even if it's harder than I thought...
...I don't regret it.
-Are you sure?
-I'm very sure.
Because it kind of has a
"there's no place like home" feeling to it.
I think these things are gonna happen,
and we're gonna get through them.
-And we'll just do it together.
-Together.
Getting rid of Marley
is not gonna fix anything.
No.
And getting rid of you
isn't gonna fix anything either.
-Can I ask you a favor?
-Yes.
No more kids for a while?
Absolutely. Deal.
Hi, guys.
All right, say hello to Colleen.
-Daddy says her name is Whoops.
-Oh, no, I....
-Patrick said that.
-What?
-I don't know.
-Why did you say that?
I was just kidding around.
It was kind of a secret, guys.
Over here.
-Wait, wait. Over here.
-Oh, yeah!
The old pro brings it back.
He looks for a little separation,
gets an assist from Colleen.
-Yeah!
-Yeah, score!
-Nice shot, Dad.
-Come on, "Nice shot"? Come on, Conor.
-Extraordinary.
-Yeah. Again.
No, wait, let me get that. I'll be back.
-All right.
-My knees are shot.
Hello?
Yes, it is.
Yeah, yeah.
Hi, how are you?
Thanks for getting back to me.
-Darn.
-Hey, who was that on the phone?
The Philadelphia Inquirer.
I sent the editor some clips a while back,
and he wants to meet.
What's a while back?
He was down here on vacation
like a month ago...
...and he read my stuff,
and we kind of had lunch.
How do you kind of have lunch?
Well, I didn't think anything
was gonna come of it.
-Okay, but...?
-They offered me a job.
I mean, I have, you know, an interview.
As, like, a columnist or...?
-As a reporter.
-As a reporter?
Well, what did you say?
I said, "Thank you very much,
but I'm happy here."
"Never have I heard someone piss
and moan as much as John Grogan.
If he doesn't like it here,
he should move."
Part of my job is to get a response.
I'm glad to see a little blood flowing
from people.
No, there's a recurring theme here.
The theme is that we got a lot of cranks
in Broward County.
That's what I'm up against.
What I'm trying to say, with all
due respect, is that you are one of them.
Well, I'm a commentator.
Everyone wants me to act like
everything's great when there are issues.
There's overcrowding, there's crime,
there's racial tensions.
Every time you turn around, there's
a new sky rise even uglier than the--
That goes on all over the world.
It's not Florida, it's you. What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
Everyone wants to think:
"Oh, he's turning 40.
He's become a curmudgeon."
That's not it. Maybe....
I don't know. I don't know,
maybe I'm sick of my column.
I don't find the things that I'm saying
that interesting.
John, John, you're the comic voice
of South Florida.
You're a national treasure,
for God's sakes.
Maybe a regional treasure.
-Well, a municipal treasure for sure.
-Thank you.
Listen, take a vacation.
Go away for a couple weeks.
-Take a month off.
-And go where?
-I don't know. Take--
-I live in a vacation spot.
Then go someplace
where it's painful and sad.
Forty is gonna be tough, buddy.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
But we knew that.
We knew this was when Father Time
was gonna make his move...
...try to take us down a dark alley
and just beat the hell out of us.
You got a little more white
around the temples...
...but it makes you look
more distinguished, I think.
We both lost a step.
Well, how's it feel
to have your best years behind you?
You do everything you wanted to?
No, me neither.
All right. You hot?
You wanna cool off? Let's do it.
You know what?
Not today.
You've been on a leash a little too long.
Go, go.
You got a little bit of a second wind.
Go get it.
-Hey, get your dog!
-What?
No, no. Please, God, no.
No, no, no!
Come here, come here. It's okay.
Dude, that was not cool.
Come on, girl, let's go!
Great.
Let's go. Let's go.
Man, you are the world's worst dog.
You know that, right?
You were top five going into the day...
...and with this little stunt,
you moved into number one.
And I take my hat off to you.
Surprise!
Dad, can I blow out--?
-Happy birthday.
-Yes, you can help me.
But hold on, hold on. On three.
-One, two, three.
But don't beg, Marley.
That's not good.
Because we don't have to.
Tell me the truth. Were you surprised?
Completely, yes. Thank you.
-Really?
-I was. You guys got me.
We got you.
Are you ready for your birthday present?
There's more?
I don't need any other present.
-Happy birthday.
-What was that?
That was my blessing
to take that job in Philadelphia.
That was months ago.
I'm not thinking about that.
Well, then any other job.
We'll follow you wherever you wanna go.
I understand, but I'm not gonna do that.
I'm not gonna uproot us.
We've got our friends,
the kids enjoy school...
...and I've got my poker game.
-I couldn't possibly.
-First of all, it's just an interview.
You don't have the job yet.
And second of all,
honey, you don't have any friends.
That's right. I was wondering,
who were all those strangers tonight?
I hired them.
What I'm trying to say is that our life
is here, and I'm okay with that.
Our life is wherever we are.
-That's it. And you're not happy here.
-That's not true.
You're not happy doing that column.
You're restless. I can feel it.
I'm not.
I feel it every day
that you read Sebastian's articles.
I feel it every time you sit
an extra five minutes in your car...
...before you come in.
-I don't do that.
-You do.
-I'm checking things in the car, I'm not--
-I just think it's time for a change.
I'm 40, Jen.
Maybe at 39, but I'm too-- I don't know.
It feels a little late
to be making big changes.
No, no, no.
What are you doing?
We're not old, John.
We can still surprise ourselves.
See, most girls would do a swan dive...
...but you know
that a cannonball is so much sexier.
So are you ready
for your other birthday present or what?
Yes.
This is like an embarrassment of riches,
this birthday.
They just keep coming.
It's like Hanukkah.
See? We're not old.
Grogan.
-Just wanna wish you good luck up there.
-Thanks. Yeah.
It'll be good. I'm gonna miss everybody.
-I'm gonna miss your laugh.
-Yeah.
There's a good chance that every piece
of advice I gave you was a lot of crap.
Oh, no, no. I appreciate it just the same.
Well, at this point, a mushy guy
would tell you he was proud of you...
...give you a hug,
and send you on your way.
Well, I'm glad you're not that guy, sir.
All right.
Okay. Thanks.
Grogan, just for the record,
you surprised the hell out of me.
That's my specialty.
-Are we here yet?
-No.
-Now?
-We got a couple hours to go.
-Soak it up.
-Now?
-We must be near it.
Are we getting hot or cold?
-Why are we turning in here?
-We're living here.
I want a moment of silence
just to take this in, okay?
Before the pandemonium. Look at this.
-Here we go.
-Come on, we're here.
Marley. Marley, no.
Marley, Marley, Marley, no, no.
Marley, no.
And we're home.
Hey, Andy Rooney. If you're knocking off,
I'll walk with you to the train.
Okay, I'm ready.
Put an exclamation point here.
Mark Twain said
not to use exclamation points...
...because it's like laughing
at your own joke.
Sometimes you gotta laugh
at your own joke because it's funny.
-It's here, it's here, it's here!
-Mom, get up, get up, get up.
-Where? Where? Where?
-Over here.
Come on, come on, come on.
It's here, it's here.
Come on, Dad. Look, Daddy.
Come on, come on, come on.
Whoa, Daddy.
Okay, look at me. Guys, guys, guys.
Remember, angels can fly,
so you gotta get the wings up high.
Yeah. Now, that one's coming.
Now you can really see it.
Guys, lunch is ready.
-Okay. Heading in.
-Take that.
-I'll get you.
-Let's go. Marley!
-Come on, guys.
-Marley, come on. Marley.
No, no, you know what, honey?
Let him be. He's happy.
Thank you.
What are you doing in here?
You're going for the bunk bed tonight?
Pretty good day.
I mean, the snow? Come on.
All right. Sleep tight.
-Too much color?
-Yeah.
Don't get me wrong, it's a good piece.
But you're reporting now, John.
I want you to tell the story,
I don't want you to be in the story.
I'm pretty sure I don't mention myself
in there.
The point is, I still feel you in there.
And all I'm saying
is less you and more facts.
Got it.
-Door's always open.
-Thanks.
Hut.
He's coming, he's coming.
Here comes the old pro.
He shows up for the fourth quarter.
Yeah. Oh, yes. He catches it.
Then he fends off one guy.
He's running through there.
He's shaking tackles left and right.
They can't get him,
because he's got too much--
And Grogan goes down.
Down goes Grogan.
-You're home early.
-That's right.
I had to come home and teach these kids
how to play football the right way.
Okay.
-Guys, seriously, dinner's in an hour.
-Okay.
And I want you
to finish your homework...
...and take off those shoes
before you come in.
Yeah, take off your shoes.
Ground and pound, ground and pound,
ground and pound.
My God.
I come home and it's like I got mugged.
Okay.
Come on.
What's wrong with him, Dad?
Nothing's wrong. He's just tired.
Right, Dad?
Yeah.
I think the football took it out of him.
Let's go.
I don't know, I just don't understand.
A year ago, you couldn't wait to be done
with your column.
I know, but now I got this guy...
...going through every sentence
with a fine-toothed comb...
...and I gotta admit, I miss the freedom,
where I could just--
What?
It's just--
It's exhausting sometimes, John.
You always wanting something
that you don't have.
Are you happy?
-I mean, none of this was part of the plan.
-No.
No, it wasn't part of the plan.
But it's so much better.
You know?
I'm just sort of done making plans.
Marley. Oh, gross.
Seems like somebody needs to go out.
All right. Marley.
Come on. Come on, boy.
Oh, come on.
Now it's really coming down.
Marley?
Marley!
Where did he go? Marley!
What's going on?
I don't know, he's just--
He's not coming back.
-Marley!
-Well, he couldn't have gone far.
-I'll come with you. Hold on.
Marley!
I don't know where he could've gone.
Maybe he went next door again
in the barn.
-Well, we can check in the woodshed.
-Okay.
Marley!
Marley?
Marley.
Where the...?
-Do you see anything?
-No, nothing.
-I gotta go talk to them.
-Okay.
Oh, wow, it's pouring out there.
Did you find him?
You know what? He's out exploring.
You know how he loves the woods.
Bobby says dogs,
when they're gonna die...
...they go away to do it.
That's what his beagle did.
Well, you know what,
that's true for beagles...
...but not Labs like Marley.
He's just out causing trouble.
Don't worry.
Okay, now,
you finished with your homework?
-Yep.
-Nope.
Nope? Well, let's make that a "yep."
Come on, now.
Marley!
Marley.
Marley, are you okay?
Just stay there.
Why did his stomach twist?
We don't exactly know why this happens.
Most likely,
he ate or drank something quickly...
...and his stomach just flipped.
I did manage to get a tube down there
to relieve some of the gas.
-I think I untwisted it.
-He seems okay.
For now he's good.
The problem is that once this happens,
it almost always happens again.
And if it does, I don't know
what I'm gonna be able to do for him.
He's an older dog.
I honestly don't think
he would survive the surgery.
Well, we have to make sure
that it doesn't happen again.
Most likely, it is gonna happen again.
Well, you also talked about
that maybe he ate too fast...
...or drank, you know, too quickly...
...and so maybe
it doesn't have to happen again.
We'll monitor that.
I'm just saying
you may wanna prepare yourself...
...that he may not make it
through the night.
Maybe 10 percent of dogs
survive this kind of a thing.
What is that number based on?
What is it based on?
Yeah, the reason why I ask is, I bet
that number is based on regular dogs.
Regular dogs?
Yeah, and this guy here
is not like other dogs.
I know people say that all the time...
...but to be honest,
I'm not sure he really is a dog.
He once ate an answering machine,
just polished it off.
He didn't chew it,
he ate it and then digested it...
...and then had the phone for dessert.
Another time, my son had colic,
and this guy sat up all night, didn't move.
Just stayed right there for nine hours,
just keeping an eye on Conor.
So I think maybe that the, you know,
the number applies to regular dogs...
...but not to him.
Well, you've got a fighter here.
Let's hope for the best.
Oh, I know he's gonna be okay.
I'll see you in the morning.
-Oh, hi.
-Hey.
They're gonna keep him overnight,
but he seemed better when I left.
And the vet really seemed on top of it.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, I'm good.
-What are you reading?
-I'm reading your old columns.
Marley's in so many of them.
You still look at those?
Yeah, I do sometimes.
Even on the crappiest days...
...when the kids are driving me nuts,
the laundry's not done...
...and a hundred other things
are wrong...
...I always know that I have this.
It's five minutes of you.
Sometimes they're sad...
...and sometimes they're really funny,
silly or whatever...
...but they're all you.
And for those five minutes...
...you make me feel better.
You should read them.
They're pretty great.
Might even make a nice book.
-A book?
-Something.
Hello?
All right.
Thank you.
He's coming home.
Is he there?
Of course he's there. He's always there.
How does he know when we're coming?
I don't know. He just knows.
Dogs know stuff like that.
-All dogs?
-All good dogs.
-Look, there he is. There he is, Marley.
-Yeah.
Hi, Marley.
-Marley.
-How you doing, Marley?
-I missed you at school.
-Hey, I'll race you to the house.
-Okay.
-Go.
-Eagles?
-Yeah, the Eagles are going all the way.
-I don't know.
-I guarantee you.
-What are you, a Dolphins fan?
-No.
-John Grogan.
-Hey.
-I'll see you tomorrow.
-All right.
I said to myself, "That sorry son of a bitch
looks like John Grogan."
-What are you doing here?
-A story.
DEA's showing off the new field office.
I'm cov--
You know what? Doesn't matter.
Man, it is good to see you.
-It's good to see you.
-Yeah.
-You living in the city somewhere?
-I live just outside of town.
More space for the kids.
-Oh, what do you got, like five now?
-Three. Here.
I'll show you a little snapshot
of the Grogan brood.
-Wow, Jen's holding up.
-Yeah, thanks. I think.
I see you finally got a little girl, huh?
-Colleen. She arrived after you left.
-What's with the ladybug getup?
That was for her school play
in preschool...
...and then we couldn't get her out
of her costume for a month afterwards.
And the reason why Marley
looks like he's biting her head...
...is because of the antennas on--
He went ballistic.
-Things don't change.
-That's right.
I wish I didn't have this interview.
That's okay, I gotta get home. I got--
Conor's got a soccer game.
All right, well, one of these days
we've gotta catch up.
Yeah, let's do that.
We'll catch up one of these days.
-Well, it was good to see you.
-Come here. Good to see you.
-Give Jenny my best, okay?
-All right. I will. Okay.
-Here.
-Oh, yeah.
Here. That's a great picture, John.
You did okay.
Thanks. You did okay too.
-I'll see you.
-I think you'll like the next one better.
-Good.
Don't do it to yourself. We're in Philly.
Let's get a cheese steak. Hi.
-Hi.
-Sebastian.
-Hello.
-Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Hello?
Is anybody home?
Marley, hey. Marley, Marley, Marley.
Hey, hey. Marley. Marley.
Marley. You didn't hear me, did you?
I just caught you
in a senior moment there, Marley.
All right, let's go for a walk.
Come on, let's go.
Come on. Come on.
You're almost to the top.
You know what? Come here.
This is a good spot right here.
I know you're a strong boy,
but you're gonna let me know, all right?
You know, when it's time.
I don't wanna make that decision
on my own.
You let me know when you're ready,
okay?
All right.
Marley?
There he is.
Marley.
Hi. Honey,
what are you doing down here?
It's time to head upstairs.
You don't sleep down here.
Come on.
Can you make it upstairs?
I think he's pretty comfortable
down here.
-I'll get him a blanket.
-You all right?
I'm gonna lay down here for a second.
Take a load off.
Yeah. It's actually nice down here.
This might be better.
Well, it would be twice a week,
600 words.
And what's the subject?
You know, everyday stuff.
The stuff we all go through, but funnier.
I don't get it.
I thought you came here to be a reporter.
I know, I did,
but we both know that isn't me.
I'm a columnist, a good one,
and I think--
Excuse me, John?
Your wife's on the phone. It's important.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Think about it? Possible?
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
-Hello?
-I can't get him to come back inside.
He's just laying out there in the cold,
and he won't move.
-Hey.
-Hi.
Patrick came home and we got him here.
Dr. Platt said that if he's comfortable,
leave him for a while and see.
But he's just not getting better.
All right. I'm gonna take him in.
-Is he sick again?
-Yeah, he is, honey.
He doesn't feel too good.
But I'm gonna take him to the doctor.
They're gonna try to make him feel better.
It's all right, Marley.
You're gonna be okay.
You could take Lamby,
but don't chew her other ear off.
That's sweet, honey.
Here, I'll take it.
Bye.
Okay.
I've tried everything I did last time
that worked...
...but I'm not having any luck.
I'm not able to get the tube down there.
The stomach is still twisted.
-There's still surgery, but--
-He's not strong enough.
-I like this one the best.
-Which one?
Oh, the mangoes. Yeah.
-Hello?
-Hey, it's me.
So it's his stomach again.
And they could do surgery, but....
I know.
Do you want me to come down there?
No, I think it's a good idea to stay with
the kids and, you know, be with them.
And I'm just gonna....
I love you, John.
I love you.
Hi.
-I'm gonna give you some time.
-Okay.
-I'll be right outside if you need me.
-All right. Thanks.
Look what I got for you.
Remember this?
Look what Colleen sent you.
You remember that?
You remember chewing up that ear? No.
It's tough to remember all the things
you've chewed up, isn't it?
It all starts to kind of run together.
It's okay. You don't have to do anything.
You don't have your usual energy.
You remember how we were
always saying what a pain you are?
That you're the world's worst dog?
Don't believe it.
Don't believe it even for a minute...
...because you know
we couldn't find a better dog.
You know,
what made you such a great dog...
...is that you loved us every day,
no matter what.
That's an amazing thing.
You know how much we love you?
We love you so much.
We love you more than anything.
I don't know exactly where we go
from here...
...but I want you to remember
you're a great dog, Marley.
You're a great dog.
He won't feel this. He'll just slip away.
You ready?
-Yeah, we're ready.
-Okay.
Okay. Get down.
-He's wrapped in his blanket.
-Yeah, so he can stay warm.
Do you guys
wanna read what you wrote?
Mine's a picture of me and Marley,
grasshoppers and ice cream.
Mommy wrote what I said.
"Dear Marley,
I will never forget you forever. Colleen."
And these are kisses.
-That's beautiful.
-Thank you.
You wanna put it in? He'll like that.
Set it down.
Good. That's a great picture.
Conor, do you wanna...?
"Dear Marley, I loved you all my life.
I hope you like heaven
and that there's lots to chew on.
Your brother, Conor Richard Grogan."
That's a good letter.
Patrick, do you wanna say something?
He knows.
I'd like to give him something.
This necklace.
It's been on quite a journey.
Your dad gave it to me...
...to celebrate the beginning
of our family.
But, you know...
...our family had really already begun.
Bye, Clearance Puppy.
A dog has no use for fancy cars...
...or big homes or designer clothes.
A waterlogged stick will do just fine.
A dog doesn't care
if you're rich or poor...
...clever or dull, smart or dumb.
Give him your heart
and he'll give you his.
How many people
can you say that about?
How many people can make you feel rare
and pure and special?
How many people
can make you feel extraordinary?