Thiobacillus, which.
William, is a
remarkable bacterium...
because...
It's the only known organism
that lives in sulfuric acid.
That's right, and...
- Yes, Miss Rouhani?
- Deinococcus radiodurans.
First discovered in
1956, breeding...
inside drums of
radioactive waste.
That's correct. So, pompejana,
Thiobacillus, Deinococcus.
Which of these three
would most likely survive...
in the extreme
environment of the
Jupiter moon
Callisto, and why?
Tom, can you get
the lights, please?
That's your lab
report question...
for this week,
and it's due in my box
by midnight on Friday.
That's all for
today. Thank you.
So, are you coming...
to the faculty
conference tonight?
To listen to Dean
Stoff lecture...
about how the universe
is like a beautiful woman?
- Think I'll pass.
- Come on. It'll be fun.
- Uh-uh.
- I could pick you up.
Um...
Can't. I have to get back
to my own extreme environment.
But thank you.
- See you tomorrow.
- Yep.
Come on. Go.
Jacob?
- Go, go.
Come on, come on.
- Yes.
- Jacob, dinner.
- You finished your homework?
- Yes. You just killed me.
Good. Now that you're dead,
you can shut that off...
and come down for dinner.
Did you order
pepperoni tonight?
- No. Are these clean?
- Yeah.
We've had pizza
twice this week,
so I made you a
proper meal tonight,
with vegetables.
Vegetables? Ew.
Stop being such a stepmom.
Where'd you get this?
It was Dad's.
Yeah, I know. Where was it?
I found it in the
downstairs bathroom.
It's mine now.
Okay.
Okay. Come on,
I said please shut that off.
- You didn't say 'please.'
- Jacob.
Helen.
- Hello?
- Helen Benson?
- Yes.
- Dr. Helen Benson?
- You're at 106 Longwood Road?
- Who is this?
Someone should be
there shortly.
What do you mean,
someone's coming
here? Who is this?
Everything will be
explained to you en route.
En route where?
- Hello?
- They should be there soon.
Yes, they're at your door now.
Hold on a minute.
Dr. Benson, if you'll
come with us...
- What's happening?
Everything will be explained,
but you must come
with us right away.
- Am I under arrest?
- You're in Federal custody.
Why?
- What is this about?
Everything will be
explained en route.
I have a child here.
Is there anyone
who can look after the boy?
- No.
Can his father
take care of him?
No, his father isn't here.
- I can take care of myself.
Jacob, you can't take
care of yourself.
- There's just no way...
You're coming with
us, Dr. Benson.
Helen?
Jacob, grab your coat.
You're gonna stay at Isabel's.
Attention, Bravo,
prepare to move out.
It's going to be okay.
Dr. Benson, there
isn't much time.
Okay, we've got her. Let's go.
Two stoplights
down, then left,
there's an on-ramp
to the highway.
- Do you see it?
- This must be a mistake.
Helen Benson,
Social Security
number 51-48-7843?
- Yeah.
- There's no mistake.
- What is this about?
Everything will be explained.
Stop the car.
- Can you stop
the car, please?
Ma'am.
I'm not under arrest.
You can't do this.
- This is a matter of
national security.
National security?
Well, that just means
whatever you want it to mean.
I'm just asking you to tell me...
why I'm needed,
or to let me go.
Ma'am, I can't tell you...
why you're needed
because I don't know.
But I know they need you,
and I know it's urgent.
How do you know that?
Where are all the cars?
- They shut down the highway.
- They shut it down?
- For what?
- For us.
- Hi. I'm Yusef.
- Helen.
Helen, do you have any idea
why this is happening to us?
- No.
- Well, think.
What do we have in common?
- What do you do
for a living, Yusef?
I'm a nuclear physicist.
- I'm an astronomer.
- A geologist.
- I'm an astrobiologist.
- Fossil record study?
No, microbiology.
Theories of life beyond Earth.
- All right, so
we're all scientists.
No, not me. I'm
a civil engineer.
Put it all together.
What do you get?
I've participated
in government...
mobilizations
like this before.
War games and preparations
for certain scenarios...
- Is that what
you think this is?
No.
Whatever it is,
it's not a game.
Your attention, please.
Make your way directly across...
the courtyard to
the main barracks.
Leave all your cell phones
and cameras here.
I repeat, cell phones...
and cameras are
not allowed inside.
Leave any cell phones
and cameras here.
Helen.
Can we bring her up?
you need to give up
your cell phones...
Your attention, please...
- Thank you.
...make your way
directly across...
the courtyard to
the main barracks...
- Helen.
- Hi, Michael.
- Been a long time.
- Are you behind all this?
Yes. I'm glad you came.
- It's not like
I had a choice.
Sorry about that.
I had you put on
the 'vital' list.
I thought it was important
to have you part of this team.
Why?
I've been keeping up
with the work you've...
been doing with
Professor Barnhardt.
What does it have
to do with this?
I'll have to crash-brief you
in the conference room.
Object 07/493 was
first spotted...
just beyond Jupiter's orbit...
by the Spaceguard program.
It was notable for the
fact that it was...
not moving in an
asteroidal ellipse,
but rather, it had a
hyperbolic orbit...
and was shooting
through our solar system.
The object was
moving at speeds...
of up to three times
10-to-the-seventh...
meters per second.
At first, it was
projected to pass...
millions of miles
outside of Earth's orbit.
However, we soon discovered
that the object...
was not following...
a gravitationally
freefall trajectory.
As such, its path
was recalculated.
It was at this time...
a crisis response
team was activated...
and everything you
see around you...
was set in motion.
Can we launch a missile
to intercept it?
The military is attempting
to do just that.
In fact, they may
launch several.
But, given the speed...
at which this
object is moving,
our chances of success
are slim, at best.
Why don't they
evacuate the area?
We simply do not
have enough time.
The affected area contains
some 8 million inhabitants.
The best we can do
is to plan for the aftermath.
How long do we have?
Seventy-eight minutes.
Hey.
What did the cops
want, anyway?
Well, there's going to be
a big storm tonight,
and they needed
some scientists...
to help out, you know,
with planning stuff. So...
Pretty soon you're all gonna
go down to the basement, okay?
I already told Isabel.
I haven't seen
anything on TVabout...
Jacob, just...
Just do it. All right?
All right. I should go.
Wait... Can we talk just
a little bit longer?
We're having dinner now.
I really should go.
You know I love you very much.
Okay. Bye, Helen.
Is that a cell phone?
Can I borrow it?
What are the odds
of an asteroid...
making impact in Manhattan?
Astronomical.
Plus, there's no
light signature.
Then it can't be an asteroid.
- A primordial
black hole, perhaps.
Do you know what
that would mean?
Look, whatever it is,
if this object is moving...
at three times 10
- to-the-seventh...
meters per second,
there will be no aftermath.
If they can't stop
it before it hits,
there will be nothing
left but dust.
It will sterilize the Earth.
This is all theater.
They're saying we lost
launch capability.
What? How?
- What does that mean?
- The missile's disabled.
- Disabled by what?
- They don't know.
But they can
restore it, right?
There's a fallback.
They have to launch.
Object impact in seven, six...
'Our father, who
art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
'Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done,
on Earth as it is in heaven...
...three, two, one...
- '...Give us this day...'
- Where is it?
Could they have
made a mistake?
Wait. Roger that.
They're saying...
the object's still
in its approach.
Well, then, where is it?
- It's slowing down.
Awesome.
- Slowing down?
I see it.
Radiation levels are
slightly elevated,
but it's not dangerous.
I'm getting a lot of
electrostatic interference.
Yeah, me too.
Did you feel that?
Feel what?
I feel it.
It's close.
Checkmate 0-6,
who has tactical command here?
This is 2917. I need to know...
who has jurisdiction
on this site.
Checkmate 0-3,
this is Gator 2-3.
We're blind here.
Checkmate 0-6,
do you copy? Over.
What the hell is that thing?
I need the rules
of engagement now.
Target is advancing.
Repeat, target is advancing.
Sniper team is in place.
Sniper team leaders,
come back. I repeat...
Do not fire.
- It's coming right at us.
It's coming out.
Hold your fire.
- Do we engage?
- Fire.
- Cease fire.
- All stations, cease fire.
Don't shoot. Don't
shoot. Do not shoot.
We need a medic.
Klaatu barada nikto.
We need that DNA
swab. DNA swab now.
- It's soaking through.
- Where's the O2? Stat.
Get me the O2, stat.
Go. No one else.
What am I supposed to do now?
Do I start an IV?
No, no. We don't
know its physiology.
For all we know, the
fluids may kill it.
What do I do, then?
What do I do?
Its blood is red.
It must have hemoglobin.
- Okay, she's right.
Start the drip.
Okay. I... I
can't find a vein.
- It doesn't have any veins.
Look for a central
line site, then.
Going into cardiac arrest.
Do I defib?
- Yeah, get in
there now. Go. Go.
Clear.
- The monitor
just shorted out.
Heart rate is stabilizing.
It's stabilizing.
What now? What now?
Do you have a surgeon?
Normally, for a gunshot,
we'd be using a
general anesthetic.
But, as we don't know
how the patient will react.
I have opted for a local.
I'm making the
first incision now.
No explosions.
So far, so good.
Pale flesh,
a texture something akin to...
What?
Whale blubber.
I'm taking a specimen now.
Pack that on ice
and chopper it...
to a genomics lab
for DNA mapping.
I'd like a sample
of that as well.
I am entering
the wound, and...
My God.
What is this?
I'm sorry. I'm a
little taken aback.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing's wrong.
That's the thing.
It's all so familiar.
The outer layer of
the flesh is exotic,
it's strange,
but as I go deeper,
there's muscle,
vein, nerve, bone.
I'm extracting the bullet.
This gray flesh,
it seems to be
just falling away.
It's... It's removing itself.
I think I need to
keep extracting it.
Yes. Continue.
Can you explain any of this?
It's dreaming.
Any signs of neural activity?
It lit up the fMRI
like Times Square.
Get help.
Code white. Subject
is conscious.
Help.
It's looking at you.
Try saying something to it.
My name is Dr. Helen Benson.
We're trying to help you.
You have nothing
to fear from us.
Help you.
Nothing to fear.
Global markets are...
panicked in early
trading this morning...
in response to the
crisis in Central Park.
Trading has been halted...
on the New York
Stock Exchange,
the Nikkei and Hang
Seng, as Manhattan...
prepares for a
massive evacuation.
In other cities
around the world,
people are voluntarily
evacuating...
population centers,
fearing that the sphere
in Central Park...
may be the vanguard...
of an impending
alien invasion.
The President and Vice
President have...
been taken to separate,
secure locations.
Until this situation
has some kind of resolve.
I am the eyes and the ears
of the Presidency.
So, what do we know?
Madam Secretary,
we lost contact...
with one of our DSCS-3...
listening satellites
orbiting Earth.
What is that image?
Are you saying that sphere...
in Central Park
isn't the only one?
In fact, we have intelligence
that smaller spheres...
have landed at other locations
around the world.
Do we have briefings on that?
And, General,
where exactly
are these spheres right now?
I think we're asking
the wrong questions.
What questions
should we be asking?
Well, let's start with this.
Where is our satellite?
We lost contact with it.
In the scheme of things,
the loss of one satellite...
- isn't necessarily
our concern.
DSCS-3...
stands for 'Defense Systems
Communication Satellite.'
Remember what it
communicates with?
They were able to access our...
defense mainframe
via that satellite.
That's how they
temporarily shut down...
our missile defenses...
and entered our airspace.
We've changed all the codes.
- And on top of that,
there is a vast amount...
of vital intelligence
on that mainframe.
They know everything
about us now.
- And we know
nothing about them.
Almost nothing.
The fact that they chose
to disable our defenses...
tells us something
about their intentions.
Madam Secretary,
we brought in several
specialists...
to analyze the tissue samples
we harvested from the being.
This is our chief geneticist,
Dr. Hideo Ikegawa.
This is our chief
astrobiologist.
Dr. Helen Benson.
- Hello.
- Doctor?
The being is in
a nascent state.
The DNA samples
we've taken seem...
to represent three
distinct life forms.
- Three different DNA types?
Yes, including
the being's brain.
The body tissue is human,
as far as we can tell.
The gray flesh encasing it...
is organic material,
some kind of
bioengineered spacesuit.
What it resembles,
oddly enough,
is placental tissue.
Which makes sense,
given the placenta's...
a life-support system.
And that, basically,
in order to survive
in our environment,
the being had to be born here,
in its human form.
They must have come
here in the past...
and obtained a DNA sample
from a human subject.
Now, since that birth,
the being has grown
exponentially.
This is one hour
after surgery.
Three hours.
Six hours.
How much can you
tell us about it...
by decoding its DNA?
You don't understand.
These are the
Dead Sea Scrolls.
Geneticists are gonna be...
studying this code
for generations.
No, they aren't.
This code is the property
of the US government.
Its very existence
is classified.
I want to see it.
Water.
Bring him up.
Does it actually
speak our language?
Or does it just parrot
what it's heard?
No, it seems to already
understand our language.
They've compromised
our satellites.
They know everything about us.
Mr. Driscoll.
My name is Regina Jackson.
I'm the Secretary of Defense...
of the United
States of America.
This body will take
some getting used to.
I've been sent here
to determine...
who or what you represent,
and what your intentions are.
It feels unreal to me.
Alien.
It will take time to adapt.
What were you before
you were human?
Different.
Different how?
It would only frighten you.
Do you have a name?
Klaatu.
Do you represent
a civilization?
I represent a group
of civilizations.
Where is this group
of civilizations?
All around you.
What is your purpose
in coming here?
There is a gathering
of world leaders...
not far from here.
I will explain my
purpose to them.
I'm afraid that's
not possible.
Perhaps you should
explain yourself...
to me instead.
Do you speak for the
entire human race?
I speak for...
the President of
the United States.
Now, please, tell me,
why have you come
to our planet?
Your planet?
Yes. This is our planet.
No. It is not.
We've decided to sedate him...
and move him to a
more secure location.
- Are you going to
interrogate him?
That's a possibility.
Madam Secretary,
as scientists,
we can't consent to this.
He says he wants to
speak to the UN.
History has lessons
to teach us...
about first encounters
between civilizations.
As a rule, the less
advanced civilization...
is either exterminated
or enslaved.
I'm thinking of
Pizarro and the Incas.
Columbus and the
Native Americans...
The list goes on.
Unfortunately, in this case,
the less advanced
civilization is us.
This is a representative...
of an extraterrestrial
civilization.
This is the most
important discovery...
in the history of mankind.
It may well be the
last discovery...
in the history of mankind.
We need to know what
they're planning,
and we need to know now.
So you want to drug him?
Interrogate him?
I'm sorry, we won't do that.
Do you understand?
I understand completely.
Of course, if you won't do it,
we'll have to call
in someone who will.
Well, I'm sure...
you can find
someone who will...
I'll do it.
Helen.
That won't be
necessary, Doctor.
We've already prepared
the solution for you.
I just need a syringe.
I want to apologize to you.
It seems we got
off to a bad start.
It seems we did.
We're going to transport you
to a different facility...
- for better medical care.
- No, you are not.
- Excuse me?
- I am leaving.
I can't allow you to do that.
- It is not up to you.
This is a military
installation.
You're surrounded by
hundreds of soldiers.
There's no leaving here.
I have done nothing wrong.
You invaded our airspace.
That automaton
that emerged from the sphere,
it attacked our troops.
It acted to defend me.
It activates in the
presence of violence.
Dr. Benson? Please.
Run.
It's done.
If you'll come
with us, ma'am...
Keep moving, please.
I'm going to ask you
a series of control questions.
Are you currently in
a seated position?
Yes.
Are you human?
My body is.
Do you feel pain?
My body does.
Are you aware of an
impending attack...
on the planet Earth?
You should let me go.
I'll repeat the question.
What gate did you use
to enter this base?
East loading door.
How do I get there?
One hundred yards left...
from the back of
this building.
Is there a security code?
Four-four-Bravo-three-zero.
What size is that suit?
Forty-two long.
Take it off.
Attention.
All security personnel...
report to your
designated posts.
All civilian personnel...
report to Operations
immediately.
- I'm leaving you now.
- No.
Put every arm of
the government,
military, law enforcement,
Federal, state and
local, on high alert.
- If the media gets
word that we lost...
Use a cover story.
We can't risk a panic.
Call him an escaped convict.
Use every surveillance
satellite,
every drone aircraft,
every freeway camera.
Use every resource we've got.
Attention:
All scheduled trains...
into and out of Penn
Station Manhattan...
are canceled due to
the ongoing evacuation...
and the security
perimeter in Central Park.
We ask that our passengers
remain calm and orderly...
during these difficult
circumstances.
Any disturbance
will be subject...
to immediate arrest
by Transit police.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
We are committed...
to providing you
quality service.
Thank you.
We ask that our...
passengers remain
calm and orderly...
during these difficult
circumstances.
Any disturbance
will be subject...
to immediate arrest
by Transit police.
You're not getting the ticket.
All right, back off.
- Don't push me.
I want the ticket.
Look, I don't...
- Now just give me the ticket.
- I'm not giving you anything.
Give me the...
What's the matter with you?
Rising global unrest...
is causing leaders
around the world...
to criticize the US response
to the arrival of the spheres.
Reactions from both
national and international...
religious communities
have been varied.
While some have responded...
with hope and
measured optimism,
most religious
communities have...
considered recent
events as apocalyptic.
At gatherings and
prayer vigils...
in virtually every major city,
many see the arrival
of the Central Park sphere...
as a sign of a new era,
or perhaps even the
end of the world.
The rapture, the tribulation...
and the impending
battle of Armageddon...
dominate much of
the discussion.
Leaders around the world...
are protesting the
US's decision...
to deny foreign scientists
full access to the being.
Have you done your homework?
School's canceled on
account of the aliens.
- They say it's an invasion.
- Well, they're wrong.
- What makes you so sure?
- I just know.
Don't get that.
- Jacob.
- Hello?
May I speak
to Dr. Helen Benson, please?
It's for you.
- Hello?
- Dr. Helen Benson?
- Yes.
I'm calling from
Newark Penn Station.
We've got your patient here.
Oh, um...
Sorry, I think there's
been a mistake.
I'm not that kind of a doctor.
Hold... Hold on a second.
He says you got his medicine.
I'll be right there.
and stressed...
the need for calm
and understanding...
Sorry. Excuse me?
Excuse me. I'm sorry, someone...
called me. My
name's Dr. Benson.
Okay, he's over there.
He's your problem now.
Go ahead, take him.
He's your problem.
Evacuation registration point...
is located two
blocks this way.
You know, I took a huge risk
back at the hospital.
Did I make a mistake?
Are you a friend to us?
I'm a friend to the Earth.
Let's keep it steady, folks.
Let's keep going forward.
Hello.
Hi.
Okay.
- Now what?
- Drive.
Look in your pocket.
Your inside pocket.
Turn left.
Striker 2829,
descend and maintain 2,000...
to established vectors
to the target area.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
All right, everybody,
we got our mission.
All right, target acquired and...
confirmed, sir.
We are locked on.
Madam Secretary,
they're sending in the drones.
Bring in the
Reapers. We have go.
- Roger that.
Descending to 1,200.
Let's light this thing up.
Arm your Sidewinder missiles.
Roger that, Colonel.
Sidewinder missiles armed.
- He's activating.
- Fire. Fire, fire.
- Missiles intercepted.
- Get out of there.
Withdraw and realign
for another sortie.
Negative. I've lost
link. I've lost control.
Who's in control of
the aircraft, then?
Striker 28 headed
for orb perimeter.
I am out of control.
Anyone got any other ideas?
Why are people running?
We should stay and fight.
They didn't come
here to hurt us.
Well, we should
kill them anyway,
just to make sure.
Don't say that.
That's what Dad
would have done.
I think he would have looked
for a different way.
He would have fought.
- I like to think I
knew him pretty well.
I knew him, too.
Longer than you.
What do you think?
Of what?
Should people run,
or should we stay and fight?
- Neither.
- What should we do, then?
There's nothing you can do.
This is it. Pull in here.
McDonald's?
Where are you going?
Jacob, where are you going?
To the bathroom.
Where is the boy's father?
He's dead.
How did he die?
He was in the Army.
So the boy wishes his
soldier father were...
here to rescue the
world from the aliens.
The boy wishes his
father were here...
for a lot of reasons,
aliens being the
least of them.
He wasn't even that
kind of a soldier.
He was an engineer.
He went over there to
build, not to fight.
And his mother?
She died when he was a baby.
I married his father.
A year ago, he was killed.
Why did you come here?
I came to save the Earth.
From what?
He's here.
Your tea, Grandfather.
Thank you.
Are you one of them?
One of who?
Never mind. Sorry.
You've been out of
contact for a long time.
I had a dangerous assignment.
This is hostile territory.
I've noticed.
I was hoping I could
reason with them.
I'm afraid they are
not a reasonable race.
I've been living amongst them
for seventy years now.
I know them well.
And?
Any attempt to intercede with
them would be futile.
They are destructive,
and they won't change.
Is that your official report?
The tragedy is, they know...
what's going to
become of them.
They sense it.
But they can't seem
to do anything about it.
It's decided then.
I'll begin the process
as soon as possible.
We should make preparations
for our departure.
I'm staying.
You can't stay here.
I can, and I will.
- If you stay, you'll die.
- I know.
This is my home now.
You yourself called them
a destructive race.
That's true.
But, still, there
is another side.
You see, I... I love them.
This is a very strange thing.
I can't find a way to
explain it to you. I...
For many years, I...
I cursed my luck
for being sent here.
Human life is difficult.
But as this life is
coming to an end.
I consider myself
lucky to have lived it.
No sudden movements.
No aggressive...
actions. No matter
what happens,
no gunfire.
Track is in place, sir.
Containment panels
are in position.
- We're ready on your order.
- On my command,
move the panels into place.
- Three, two...
...one.
Synchronize established,
ISI ready to copy.
Containment panels...
are secure, and
we're still here.
9-1-1.
What's your emergency?
The escaped convict
they showed on the news,
- I just saw the guy
at the gas station.
Can you describe him?
He was in a little car,
on the south block...
9- 1-1, what is
your emergency?
I just saw that wanted man
over by the McDonald's.
Can you
describe the car, sir?
Silver four-door,
with a woman and a kid.
I need 3 units to look...
for a silver Honda
near Ochada orchards.
3-1 responding.
We are patrolling the
orchards off I-67.
HP-28, follow up.
This is it. Stop here.
You shouldn't...
Uh, Helen? Who is this guy?
A friend.
- What kind of friend?
Scootch over. He's
a work friend.
What's his name?
- Klaatu.
- Klaatu?
- Yeah.
- What kind of name is that?
It's foreign, I think.
- I never heard you
talk about him before.
I haven't known
him for very long.
We're just giving him a ride.
Where?
- Here.
- The forest?
Stay here.
I want you to lock
the door, okay?
And don't open it
for anyone but me.
I'm serious.
Helen, what's going on?
We're getting images
of these spheres...
from all over the world.
Okavango, Kobe, Baku...
Which of our agencies
gathered this intel?
Ma'am, none of them.
We pulled these
off the Internet.
Is that them?
No. It's us.
Those are ordinary
cephalopods.
Squid. Octopus.
I don't like him.
He's weird, and...
Why are we driving
him around, anyway?
Um...
It's complicated.
Is he coming home with us?
No. No.
Well, what if you
decide you like him...
and he wants to move in?
No, it's not like
that. God, no.
Listen to me.
No one is moving in.
You don't understand.
Whatever. You wait for him.
I'm going home.
Jacob.
What is the matter with you?
These spheres
now appear to be leaving...
in the same mysterious manner
as they came.
Hopefully this mass exodus
will bring an end...
to the panic and unrest...
we've been seeing
around the world.
The only sphere...
that doesn't appear
to be leaving...
is the giant sphere
in Central Park.
You think we scared them off?
They're not afraid of us.
I need to get
back to the city.
Not till you tell
me what's going on.
- Did you do that?
- Yes.
Jacob, get in the car.
- He's one of them.
- Please get in the car.
Get in the car.
I need to know
what's happening.
This planet is dying.
The human race is killing it.
So you've come
here to help us.
No, I didn't.
You said you came to save us.
I said I came to
save the Earth.
You came to save the Earth...
from us.
You came to save
the Earth from us.
We can't risk the survival
of this planet...
for the sake of one species.
- What are you saying?
- If the Earth dies, you die.
If you die, the
Earth survives.
There are only a
handful of planets...
in the cosmos...
that are capable
of supporting complex life.
- You can't do this.
This one can't be
allowed to perish.
We can change.
We could still turn
things around.
We've watched, we've waited,
and hoped that
you would change.
- Please.
It's reached the
tipping point.
- We have to act.
- Please.
We'll undo the damage
you've done...
and give the Earth a chance
to begin again.
Don't do this. Please.
We could change.
We can change.
The decision is made.
The process has begun.
Oh, God.
It won't make any
difference, Helen.
Even if they arrest me,
even if they kill me,
the process will continue.
Both of you, hands on
the car right now.
- Is that a child in the car?
- Yes.
This is HP-28. I'm on I-67.
I have the FBI
suspect in custody...
along with one adult female...
and one child.
Awaiting instructions.
70140, roger.
Tell the child to
get out of the car.
- Get the kid out of the car.
- Honey, come.
Okay, you two, over there.
You, I'm not going
to tell you again.
Hands on the car.
- Please don't hurt him.
- I'm not going to hurt him,
- so long as he...
- I wasn't talking to you.
The pain will only
last a moment.
You killed him.
- Jacob. Jacob.
- Let me finish.
Shh. Shh.
You killed him.
- Come sit down.
- He killed him.
He'll be all right.
I don't understand.
You're going to kill us all,
but you saved him.
He was an obstacle.
I meant him no harm.
You could stop
this, couldn't you?
If you wanted to.
I tried to reason with you.
I tried to speak
with your leaders.
Those aren't our leaders.
If you want to speak to one...
of our leaders, I'll
take you to one.
Let me take you.
Get in the car.
Maybe they were just...
collecting specimens
from our planet.
It's not our planet.
That's what he said to
me in the hospital.
An ark.
- Excuse me?
- It's an ark.
So are all the other spheres.
They're saving as many species
as they can.
If the sphere is an ark,
then what comes next is...
The flood.
Karl, we're here.
All right, let's
get you settled.
That's a Nobel Prize.
He won it for his work
on biological altruism.
Probably still be in
his desk drawer...
if I hadn't gotten
it framed for him.
- You tired?
- Just a little.
Close, but no.
I wouldn't.
He won't mind.
He's one of them.
You shouldn't be helping him.
We should stop him.
For just this once,
I need you to trust me.
Is it possible?
I have so many
questions to ask you.
It's Bach.
It's beautiful.
So we're not so
different after all.
I wish that were true.
So is it a machine
or a living thing?
- It's both, or neither.
- What do you mean, neither?
It seems to be some sort
of silicon-based hybrid.
We're calling it GORT,
Genetically Organized
Robotic Technology.
The military and
their acronyms.
We've used every
diagnostic method available.
MRI, thermal
imaging, PET scan,
but it was impervious.
So we attempted...
a robotically-assisted
exploration...
- using a diamond drill.
- And?
The drill bit fractured.
It'll take...
24 hours to fix
it robotically.
Colonel, we don't
have 24 hours.
Send somebody in there
to fix that drill.
Food and fuel hoarding...
have led to shortages
which erupted...
into looting incidents
throughout Asia...
and South America. Many...
... outbreaks of
rioting and unrest...
in such cities as
Guangdong, China.
London, and Chicago
due to the shortages...
of such basic
commodities as fuel,
food and drinking
water. Many point to...
the Central Park sphere as...
Amidst the chaos...
in the New York-New
Jersey areas,
local police are looking
for an escaped convict...
whose name is not
being released.
Authorities believe that he is...
a significant threat
to the public...
and are asking for
any information...
that could lead
to his capture.
If you have seen this man,
contact the number on
your screen below.
There must be alternatives.
You must have some technology
that could solve our problem.
Your problem is
not technology.
The problem is you.
You lack the will to change.
Then help us change.
I cannot change your nature.
You treat the world
as you treat each other.
But every civilization...
reaches a crisis
point eventually.
- Most of them don't make it.
- Yours did. How?
Our sun was dying.
We had to evolve in
order to survive.
So it was only when your world...
was threatened with
destruction...
- that you became
what you are now.
Yes.
Well, that's where we are.
You say we're on the brink...
of destruction,
and you're right.
But it's only on the brink...
that people find
the will to change.
Only at the precipice
do we evolve.
This is our moment.
Don't take it from us.
We're close to an answer.
What's wrong?
Jacob. Can you
get your boots on?
He can't get caught.
What do I do?
Change his mind.
Not with reason,
but with yourself.
It's too late for that.
Jacob.
Down here. He's here.
- Down here. He's here.
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to help them.
- That's why I called them.
- What?
- I told them where we are.
- Jacob, you didn't.
- We shouldn't be helping him.
Jacob, I'm trying to help us.
We should kill him.
That's what Dad
would have done.
- You fight me on
everything. Everything.
If my dad were here...
But he isn't here. He's gone.
Jacob...
We've extracted the female.
Returning to base.
- Got a visual on the male.
- Yeah, I see him.
Yep, got him.
Target acquired.
Permission to engage.
You are clear to engage.
You are go to take
out the target.
Roger that.
Please don't hurt me.
Thanks.
I don't know where we are.
Can you help me get home?
This way.
- He's come to
exterminate us, hasn't he?
You can't stop him.
The only chance we have
is if he changes his mind.
You have to let
me talk to him.
What makes you think
he'll listen to you?
I don't know that he will.
But I think he trusts me.
And I don't think he
wants to do this.
We have the situation
under control.
Madam Secretary, General Quinn...
needs to see you in
the briefing room.
He says it's urgent.
You're not in control.
You don't know what
he's capable of.
But she didn't do
anything wrong.
So they should
let her go, right?
You are afraid
you're going to be left alone.
I already am alone.
Helen's just someone
that was stuck with...
me when my dad died. You know?
Oh, I forgot. You're an alien.
You don't understand anything.
We're good to go.
Hold it.
Your sleeve.
Oh...
Let... Let me out.
- Open the airlock.
- No.
- Open the door.
- Then we have to flash.
- Our protocol...
- I decide what protocol is.
Open the door. Let me out.
- Reset the drill.
- Let me out. Open it.
I said, reset the drill.
Let me out. Let me
out. Open the door.
Let me out.
Sir, the restraints.
Open the door. Open the door.
This facility has been sealed.
No one leaves.
We've lost contact
with the flash chamber, sir.
Whiskey Task Force, engage.
Were there any survivors?
- No.
As you know, at 0524 hours,
our pilots launched a salvo...
of Sidewinder
air-to-air missiles...
- into the heart of the mass.
- And?
Every strike made it larger.
And this mass,
where is it heading?
Everywhere.
- Dr. Benson.
- Madam Secretary, please.
I don't want to die
here in this room...
without seeing my
son one more time.
Do you really think
you can persuade him?
I think you should let me try.
Go on, then.
But I make you no promises.
I still answer to
the President.
- You're on your own.
No, she's not.
I'll go with you.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
It doesn't work.
Go ahead.
It's me. Are you okay?
I'm fine.
He's right here.
She wants to talk to you.
Yes.
I need to get
back to the city.
- Yes.
Tell her I know where
we can meet her.
I told Helen we
should kill you.
Yes, I heard that.
- I didn't mean it, though.
- You didn't?
Well, not anymore.
So what's gonna happen to us?
I was just wondering
the same thing.
- End of the world.
- Good luck.
This is it. This is where
we're supposed to meet her.
Come on.
Hurry up. It's this way.
You can do this. Just
like with the trooper.
There are some
things I can't do.
But you have powers.
I'm sorry.
Please.
Jacob, nothing
ever truly dies.
The universe wastes nothing.
Everything is simply...
transformed.
Just leave me alone.
- It's not fair.
- No.
No, it isn't fair.
He left me alone.
Oh, baby, you're not alone.
And he didn't leave you.
I see him in you.
All the time.
Sometimes it's hard
for me to bear.
You miss him, too?
So much.
- I'm sorry.
Okay.
It's all right.
He's here to help.
There's another side to you.
I feel it now.
Is that how it ends?
Yes.
You can't stop it?
I don't know.
It would come at a price
to you and your way of life.
But we can change.
You know that now.
Please.
Please, just give us a chance.
I'll try.
I must get back to the city.
Of course, Mr. President.
I understand the situation.
But with all due respect, sir,
any further military action
will only make things worse.
I believe we may still be able
to open a dialog...
Yes, Mr. President.
As you wish, sir.
Thank you.
Checkpoint.
We can't stop.
There isn't time.
- Dive.
- Look out.
Lincoln-Bravo-1 to
Lincoln-Bravo-2,
a black SUV crashed
our checkpoint...
with the suspects.
- En route to your position.
- Roger that, Bravo-1.
Bravo-1, we've got orders...
to let them through.
Do you copy?
Roger that.
They're slowing down.
- They're letting us through.
- Why?
Where is everybody?
They've cleared the area.
Stop the car.
- What?
- Stop the car.
Jacob. Jacob.
I'm okay.
Michael?
We have to get to the sphere.
Helen.
We won't make it.
I can't keep them
out for long.
Mom.
What's happening to him?
Jacob.
They're inside him.
He's dying.
Help him.
Help him. Please.
Your professor was right.
At the precipice,
we change.
It's leaving.
No.
He's leaving.