♪ This land is your land ♪
♪ this land is my land ♪
♪ from California ♪
♪ well, to the New York island ♪
♪ from the Redwood Forest ♪
♪ to the Gulf stream waters ♪
♪ I tell you this land ♪
♪ was made for you and me ♪
♪ as I went walking ♪
♪ down that ribbon of highway ♪
♪ I saw above me ♪
♪ oh, that endless skyway ♪
♪ now I saw below me ♪
♪ that golden valley ♪
♪ and I said this land ♪
♪ was made for you and me ♪
♪ this land is your land ♪
♪ this land is my land ♪
♪ from Riverside, California ♪
♪ oh, to Staten Island ♪
♪ well, on down to Georgia ♪
♪ or Houston, Texas or LA ♪
♪ yeah, you know
this land is your land ♪
♪ this land is my land ♪
♪ this land is your land ♪
♪ ooh, you've got to believe
oh, it's my land ♪
This is what I get
in return.
For 30 years of service
for my company?
And they send
some yo-yo like you
in here.
To try to tell me
that I'm out of a job?
They should be telling you
you're out of a job.
You have a lot of gall
coming in here.
And firing your
number one producer.
And then you're going
to go home tomorrow.
And make more money
than you've ever
made in your life,
And I'm going to go home
without a pay check.
Fuck you.
I just...
I guess you
leave me dumbfounded.
I don't know where
this is coming from.
How am I supposed
to go back as a man.
And explain this to my wife
that I lost my job?
On a stress level,
I've heard that
losing your job.
Is like a death
in the family.
But personally,
I feel more like.
The people I worked
with were my family
and I died.
I can't afford
to be unemployed.
I have a house payment.
I have children.
I don't know
how you can live
with yourself,
But I'm sure that
you'll find a way.
While the rest of us
are suffering.
Who the fuck
are you, man?
Ryan:
Excellent question.
Who the fuck am I?
Poor Steve has worked here
for seven years.
He's never had
a meeting
with me before.
Or passed me
in the hall.
Or told me a story
in the break room.
And that's because
I don't work here.
I work for
another company
that lends me out.
To pussies
like Steve's boss.
Who don't have the balls
to sack their own employees,
And in some cases,
for good reason.
Because people do crazy shit
when they get fired.
( gun cocking )
Did I do
something wrong?
I mean, is there something
I could do differently here?
This is not an assessment
of your productivity.
You gotta try not to
take this personally.
( Murmurs )
"don't take it
personally."
Steven, I want you
to review this packet.
Take it seriously.
I think
you're gonna find.
A lot of good answers
in here.
I'm sure this is
gonna be very helpful,
a packet.
Thank you.
A packet.
( Clears throat )
Well, anybody who
ever built an empire
or changed the world.
Sat where you are
right now.
And it's
because they sat there
they were able to do it.
That's the truth.
I'm gonna need
your keycard.
Great. Okay.
Now,
I want you to
take the day,
Go get together
your personal things,
And then tomorrow,
you get yourself
some exercise.
You go out
for a jog,
You give yourself
some routines,
And pretty soon
you find your legs.
How do I get in
touch with you?
Don't worry,
we'll be in touch
with you soon.
This is just
the beginning.
I'll never see Steve again.
Thank you.
To know me is to fly with me.
This is where I live.
When I run my card,
the system automatically
prompts the desk clerk.
To greet me with
this exact statement.
Pleasure to
see you again,
Mr. Bingham.
It's these
kinds of systemized,
Friendly touches
that keep
my world in orbit.
All the things you probably
hate about traveling,
The recycled air,
the artificial lighting,
the digital juice dispensers,
The cheap sushi,
are warm reminders
that I'm home.
Do you want
the cancer?
The what?
Do you want
the cancer?
The cancer?
The can, sir?
( Chuckles ) Oh. No.
I'm fine, thank you.
How much does
your life weigh?
Imagine for a second
that you're
carrying a backpack.
I want you to
feel the straps
on your shoulders.
Feel them?
Now I want you
to pack it.
With all the stuff that
you have in your life.
You start with
the little things,
The things on shelves
and in drawers,
The knickknacks,
the collectibles.
Feel the weight
as that adds up.
Then you start
adding larger stuff,
Clothes,
tabletop appliances,
lamps, linens,
Your TV.
The backpack should be
getting pretty heavy now.
And you go bigger.
Your couch, bed,
your kitchen table.
Stuff it all in there.
Your car,
get it in there.
Your home, whether it's
a studio apartment
or a two-bedroom house,
I want you to stuff it all
into that backpack.
Now try to walk.
( all chuckling )
It's kind of hard,
isn't it?
This is what we
do to ourselves
on a daily basis.
We weigh ourselves down
until we can't even move.
And make no mistake,
moving is living.
Now, I'm gonna
set that backpack
on fire.
What do you want
to take out of it?
Photos?
Photos are for people
who can't remember.
Drink some ginkgo
and let the photos burn.
In fact,
let everything burn.
And imagine
waking up tomorrow
with nothing.
It's kind of
exhilarating,
isn't it?
Welcome back,
Mr. Bingham.
( Phone rings )
Ryan Bingham's office.
You put me
in a dodge stratus
in Kansas city.
They were completely
out of
all full-size sedans.
Did you try...
Yes.
I reminded them
of your remarkable.
No. 1 gold club status
and years in the program.
They are
literally moving mountains
to see you in a Sebring.
( Sighs )
Fair enough.
Any other messages?
Your sister
Kara called.
Needs to speak urgently
about your sister's wedding.
I told her you were mid-air
and not even I knew
your final destination.
Well done.
And you got
an invitation.
To speak at
Goalquest in Vegas.
Goalquest 20?
Ryan:
Every once in a while,
I do speaking engagements,
Motivational kind of stuff.
But Goalquest?
We're talking major
Tony Robbins shit.
It's got
a hologram on it.
They're calling it Dos Equis.*
*A Mexican beer brand means "stay thirsty."
( Sighs ) all right,
I'll check in.
Hold on. I've got
Craig Gregory for you.
Wait...
( softly ) fuck.
How is my
little road warrior?
Hey, 20 minutes
from boarding into
a world of bliss.
Real good numbers
out of Phoenix,
Ry Guy.
Hey, you know that
big auto is about to cut.
Another 10k
before the end
of the month?
No kidding.
Yeah. Christmas
came early.
I wish I could have you
in about five places at once,
But I do need you
back here in Omaha
by the end of week.
All right?
I thought you
needed me everywhere.
Well, you know,
we got something
real big here,
A real game changer.
What are we
talking about here?
You'll see.
Today I took my first crap
in two weeks, hallelujah.
That's me
hanging up on you.
Great, love that sound.
Are you satisfied
with maestro?
Yeah, I am.
A little stingy
with their Miles.
I like Hertz.
No, Hertz keeps its
vehicles too long.
If a car has
over 20,000 Miles,
I won't drive it.
Maestro doesn't
instant checkout.
I like to park and go.
Hertz doesn't
guarantee navigation.
It's funny.
You don't seem like a girl
who needs directions.
I hate asking for directions.
That's why I get a NAV.
That new outfit,
colonial, isn't bad.
Is that a joke?
Yes.
Because their
kiosk placement
blows.
They never have
available upgrades.
Basically,
it's a fleet
of shit-boxes.
I don't know
how they're still
in business.
I'm Ryan.
I'm Alex.
( Ryan chuckling )
( Exclaims )
Maplewood card.
How dare you bring that
into this palace?
Hilton offers
equal value
and better food,
But the Maplewood gives out
warm cookies at check-in.
They got you
with the cookies,
did they?
Yeah. I'm a sucker for
simulated hospitality.
You know, there's
an industry term
for that.
It's a mixture of
"faux" and "homey."
"faumey."
Oh, my God.
I wasn't sure this
actually existed.
This is the
American airlines...
It's a concierge
key, yeah.
What is that,
carbon fiber?
Graphite.
Oh, God,
I love the weight.
I was pretty excited
the day
that bad boy came in.
Yeah. I'll say.
I put up pretty
pedestrian numbers.
Sixty thou a year,
domestic.
That's not bad.
Don't patronize me.
What's your total?
It's a personal
question.
Oh, please.
And we hardly
know each other.
Come on.
Show some hubris.
Come on, impress me.
( Sighs )
I bet it's huge.
You have no idea.
( Exclaims ) How big?
What is it,
this big?
( Scoffs )
This big?
I don't want to brag.
Come on! Come on.
Let's just say
I have a number in mind.
I haven't hit it yet.
This is pretty
fucking sexy.
Hope it doesn't cheapen
our relationship.
We're two people
who get turned on
by elite status.
I think cheap is
our starting point.
There's nothing
cheap about loyalty.
So, we came up
with this master plan,
which was for me.
To put gauze,
to put bandages
on both my hands.
( laughing )
Then we got
on the plane,
Transatlantic,
flying to Zurich.
Walked up...
Waited till
it was dark,
And walked up
to the bathroom
with her.
Everybody was
watching the movie,
and I was like...
Opened up,
went inside.
She opened
the door for me,
And came in
like she was
gonna help me.
And then, you know,
we gave it our best shot.
It wasn't great.
But it was fun.
It was tricky.
Give me
some details.
Well, it's not
so easy.
Have you ever tried it?
It's not so easy.
Yes, I have.
Really?
Really.
( laughs )
You've done that?
I have done that.
On a transatlantic flight?
On a domestic flight.
Regional, actually.
Like nighttime?
No, like daytime.
You...
What?
I mean,
how do you do that?
I'm really flexible.
Look.
( Exclaiming )
I should throw these out.
( Both laughing )
We can always
use that room
with the ice machine.
Here, look.
( laughing )
Good call
on that towel rack.
I like how
you burritoed me
in the sofa cushions.
I was improvising.
Shame we didn't
make it to the closet.
Mmm.
We got to
do this again.
Oh, yeah.
All right,
I'm in Newark on the 12th,
Modesto on the 13th,
Oklahoma city
on the 15th.
Any southwest?
I'll be swinging
by Albuquerque
week of the 16th.
No, but I'll be in
Florida on the 20th.
Fort Lauderdale?
Miami.
That's nothing.
Forty minutes.
( Both sighing )
I should probably
go back to my room
so I can wake up in my bed.
I think that would be
the ladylike thing to do.
Nice meeting you.
A pleasure.
( Cell phone ringing )
Hello?
Kara: Hey, Ryan,
how you holding up?
Ryan: Every family
has the one person.
Who keeps
the genealogy
in check.
That's my sister Kara,
the glue.
Fine.
You and the kids?
Missy's outstanding,
Matthew made varsity.
How's the road?
Couldn't be better.
Kara: Good. So, Ryan?
Yeah?
I didn't even want to
have to ask you this.
Because I know how
you are about doing
things for others,
But we're coming up
on three weeks
to go to Julie's wedding.
And there's something
we could really
use your help on.
Yeah?
We've been sending
people these kits.
So they can print out photos
of Julie and Jim on cardboard.
And then take photos of them
in interesting places,
Kind of like that gnome
in the French movie.
Why?
Because it's Julie's wedding
and she thinks
it would be fun.
Does it matter why?
How is Julie?
Would you call her?
She thinks you've
turned to butter.
You're awfully isolated
the way you live.
Isolated?
I'm surrounded.
So, your assistant said
you were gonna be in Vegas.
Did he?
Can you get
a photo of the cutout.
In front of
the Luxor pyramid?
The place is a shithole.
Nobody stays there.
Jesus, Ryan,
I'm not asking
you to check in.
Can you just
take a stupid photo?
( Sighs )
I'll try my best.
Thank you for
trying your best.
Ryan: Last year,
I spent 322 days
on the road,
Which means I had to spend
43 miserable days at home.
Hey, neighbor.
Hey. Hi!
Hi. Hey, I signed for this
while you were gone.
Thanks.
I hope it wasn't
too much of a bother.
Nah.
( Exhales )
Wow.
Yeah, it's my sister.
I haven't
met the guy yet.
They're getting married.
Hmm. Lots of luck.
I know, right?
What are you doing tonight?
You wanna come over later?
I've started
seeing somebody.
Oh. Okay. Great.
Hey, it's good
to see you.
You, too.
It seems like
it's been a while
this time.
Okay.
I am just...
I'm thrilled that.
Everyone's back
under one roof.
Welcome home, boys.
I know there's been
a lot of whispering
about why we're here,
So let me jump right in.
Retailers are down 20%.
Auto industry
is in the dump.
Housing market
doesn't have
a heartbeat.
It is one of
the worst times on record
for America.
This is our moment.
Now, last Summer,
we received a dynamite
young woman here.
From Cornell,
And she had some
pretty big ideas that
she challenged me with.
And my first reaction was,
"Who does this kid
think that she is?"
But after I gave it a listen,
she really knocked me out.
So, with a peek
into our future,
Natalie Keener.
If there's one word I want
to leave you with today,
it's this.
( All murmuring )
"Glocal"?
Glocal.
Our global
must become local.
This company keeps
23 people on the road
at least 250 days a year.
It's expensive,
and it's inefficient.
When I came to Craig
three months ago with this,
He told me,
and quite astutely,
It's only a problem
if you have a solution.
Well, today
I stand before you
with just that.
You all know
Ned in reception.
Today I'm gonna fire Ned.
Sorry, Ned. I'm sure
HR will hire you back
this afternoon.
We'll see about that.
( All laughing )
Now Ned could be
any employee.
In any one of our clients'
locations worldwide.
Strategy packets
will be shipped
in advance.
Ned would be
given a seat.
And find one of our
transition specialists
waiting for him.
Mr. Laskin, the reason
we're having
this conversation.
Is your position is
no longer available.
I don't understand.
I'm fired?
Hearing the words
"you've been let go"
is never easy.
Change is always scary,
but consider the following.
Anybody who ever
built an empire
or changed the world.
Sat where you are now.
And it's because
they sat there that
they were able to do it.
That's my fucking line.
But what happens now?
This is the first
step of a process.
That will end
with you in a new job
that fulfills you.
Yeah. But how does it work?
I want you
to take the packet
in front of you.
Review it.
All the answers you're
looking for are inside.
Start filling out
the necessary
information,
And before you know it,
you'll be on your way
to new opportunities.
Now, Ned,
I need you to go
back to your desk.
And start putting
together your things.
As a favor to me,
I'd appreciate it
if you didn't spread
the news just yet.
Panic doesn't help anyone.
I understand.
Give it up for Ned.
( All applauding )
You can start
the morning in Boston,
stop in Dallas over lunch,
And finish the day
in San Francisco,
All for the price
of a T1 line.
Our inflated travel budget
is eviscerated by 85%.
And more importantly
to you guys on the road,
No more Christmases
in a hotel in Tulsa,
No more hours lost
to weather delays.
You get to come home.
Tell me you're not
taking this seriously.
That's why I brought
the entire company
in from the road,
Because we're not
taking it seriously.
There is
a methodology
to what I do.
There is a reason
why it works.
Coke and IBM
have been doing this
for years, all right.
Are you familiar
with them?
Now just like
anything else,
you know,
It's gonna take
a few months of
sort of transition.
And then everybody
is gonna settle in.
Who are you
taking off the road?
How are you
not getting this?
You're grounded.
Everybody's grounded.
It's done.
What we do here is brutal,
and it does leave
people devastated.
But there is a dignity
to the way I do it.
By stabbing them in
the chest instead of
the back, is that right?
You wanted to see me?
Well...
Yeah. You know what?
Yeah, come on in.
Come on in here.
Great job
out there, Natalie.
Thank you.
How's everyone
taking it?
Great.
Listen, I admire your...
Your zeal.
And I think
you have some
very good ideas.
But you know nothing
about the realities
of my industry.
You can set up an iChat,
but you don't know
how people think.
Actually,
I minored
in psychology.
Craig: Nice.
Okay, kiddo, fire me.
Craig: Ryan.
Ryan: Well, since
she's gonna be doing this
on a regular basis,
Don't you wanna know
if she can fire somebody?
She's fired Ned.
My dog can fire Ned.
Fire me.
You don't need to
do this.
No, it's okay.
I got this.
Mr. Bingham,
I regret to inform you.
That your position
at this company is
no longer available.
Hmm.
Who the hell are you?
My name is Miss Keener.
I'm here today to
discuss your future.
My future?
The only one
who can fire me
is Craig Gregory.
Mr. Gregory hired me
to handle this for him.
Handle what?
Handle me?
Mr. Gregory hired me,
he's the only one
who can fire me.
You know what?
I'm gonna
go talk to him.
Mr. Bingham.
No, no, no.
You can't follow me.
You're on
a computer screen,
remember?
Ryan.
All right.
Let's try this again.
Fire me again.
I just did.
Actually, you didn't.
Fire me.
That's enough.
I think we get it.
Mr. Bingham,
I'm here today
to inform you.
That your position is
no longer available.
I'm fired?
Yes, you're fired.
Never say fired.
You've been let go.
Why?
This is a
mythical situation.
How could I
possibly know why?
Why doesn't matter.
You never know why.
It's important not
to focus on the why.
And rather to
spend your energy
thinking about your future.
Well, I'm gonna
spend my energy.
On suing you
unless you give me.
A good reason why
you're firing me.
Mr. Bingham,
The reason's
not important.
So, you're firing me
without grounds?
Now I really have a lawsuit.
I get what you're
trying to say, Ryan.
Don't take
this personally,
Mr. Bingham.
Personally?
This is the most
personal situation.
That you are
ever gonna enter,
So before you try
to revolutionize
my business,
I'd like to know
that you actually
know my business.
That's a hell of a way
to welcome her to the team.
Am I the only one
that sees
that by doing this.
We're making
ourselves irrelevant?
No, frankly,
we're making
you irrelevant.
Nice.
Don't blame me.
Blame the high fuel costs.
Blame insurance premiums.
Blame technology.
You know,
you better watch yourself.
You're a little too young
to become a dinosaur.
I'm not a dinosaur.
I want you to
show her the ropes.
What do I know
what goes on here?
Get Ferguson to do it.
I'm not talking
about here.
No.
Yeah.
Come on.
You're very, very
confident this girl.
Doesn't know what
she's doing, so...
Well, I'm sorry.
I don't think
a MySpace page
qualifies you to.
Rewire an entire company.
Well, then great.
Here's your chance.
Go out there,
show her the magic,
take her through the paces.
I'm not a fucking
tour guide.
Now here we go.
Bingham,
here's the boat.
And here's you.
Do you want to
be in the boat?
Yeah, alone.
We're ringing the bell.
We're rounding everybody up.
You want to stay out there
a little bit longer,
You're welcome to do it,
but you will not
be alone, okay?
You let me know.
Oh, Christ.
( Suitcase tires screeching )
What?
Follow me.
I really like
my luggage.
That's exactly what
it is, it's luggage.
You know how
much time you lose
by checking in?
I don't know.
Five, 10 minutes?
Thirty-five minutes
a flight.
I travel
270 days a year.
That's 157 hours.
That makes seven days.
You're willing
to throw away an
entire week on that?
( Sighs )
You don't need this.
Sorry,
you don't need that.
You're not gonna need
that. They have neck
pillows on the plane.
This, they have
better ones there.
I'll get rid of this.
I can just meet
you at security.
Thank you.
Bingo, Asians.
You can't
be serious.
Never get behind people
traveling with infants.
I've never seen
a stroller collapse
in less than 20 minutes.
Old people are worse.
Their bodies are littered
with hidden metal,
And they never
seem to appreciate.
How little time they
have left on earth.
Here you go.
Five words.
Randomly selected
for additional screening.
Asians.
They pack light,
travel efficiently,
And they've got a thing
for slip-on shoes.
You've got to love them.
That's racist.
I'm like my mother.
I stereotype.
It's faster.
( Typing noisily )
Are you mad
at your computer?
I type with purpose.
What is it that
you're working on
so furiously?
I'm building a workflow
of firing techniques.
It's questions and responses,
actions and reactions.
It's a script
taking you through
the steps of firing someone.
Who's it for?
Well, theoretically,
you could put it in
the hands of anyone.
And they'd be
downsizing immediately.
All you have to do
is follow the steps.
Natalie, what is it
you think we do here?
We prepare
the newly unemployed.
For the emotional
and physical hurdles
of job hunting,
While minimizing
legal blowback.
That's what we're selling.
It's not what we're doing.
Okay.
What are we doing?
We are here to
make limbo tolerable,
To ferry wounded souls
across the River of dread.
Until the point
where hope
is dimly visible.
And then stop the boat,
shove them in the water
and make them swim.
That was really impressive.
Are you gonna put
that in your book?
( Continues typing )
( Cell phone ringing )
I got to grab this.
I'll meet you at
the car rental.
Okay.
Hey, I was hoping
I'd hear from you.
I'm in Hotlanta,
and I need a rib-joint
recommend bad.
Fat matt's.
Bring a bib.
You never called.
Well, I wasn't sure
what was appropriate.
Appropriate?
Ryan, I'm not some waitress
you banged in a snowstorm.
That word has no place
in our vocabulary.
I am the woman
that you don't have
to worry about.
Sounds like a trap.
Listen, the next time
that you're worried
about manners, don't.
If you wanna call, call.
Just think of me
as yourself,
only with a vagina.
When am I gonna see you?
Well, I'm out of
Hartsfield into IAD,
With a connection
at ORD into SDF.
Sorry.
Yeah, tell me about it.
How long's your layover?
They got multiples into SDF.
Think you could push?
Yeah, I can push.
All you have to do today
is watch and listen.
And when I talk
about a strategy packet,
hand them one of those.
Sounds great.
So, although
I wish I were here
with better news,
The fact is that
you and I are
sitting here today.
Because this will
be your last week.
Of employment
at this company.
Why me?
What am I
supposed to do now?
Am I supposed to feel better
that I'm not
the only one losing my job?
This is ridiculous!
I have been
a fine employee
for over 10 years,
And this is
the way you treat me.
How do you sleep
at night, man? How?
How's your family?
They sleeping well
at night?
Electricity still on?
Heat still on?
Refrigerator
full of food?
Gas tank full of gas?
Going to chuck e. Cheese
this weekend or something?
Not me.
No, my kids,
we're not gonna
do anything.
What do you
suggest I tell them?
Perhaps you're
underestimating
the positive effect.
That your career transition
can have on your children.
The positive effect?
I make about
90 grand
a year now.
Unemployment is what,
250 bucks a week?
Is that one of
your positive effects?
Well, we'll get
to be cozier,
Because I'm not gonna
be able to pay
my mortgage on my house.
So, maybe we can move
into a nice fucking.
One-bedroom
apartment somewhere.
And I guess
without benefits,
I'll be able to hold
my daughter as she,
You know,
suffers from her asthma.
That I won't
be able to afford
the medication for.
( Clears throat )
Well, tests have
shown that.
Children under
moderate trauma.
Have a tendency to apply
themselves academically.
As a method of coping.
Go fuck yourself.
That's what
my kids'll think.
Your children's admiration
is important to you?
Yeah. Yeah, it was.
Well, I doubt they ever
admired you, Bob.
Hey, asshole,
aren't you supposed
to be consoling me?
I'm not a shrink, Bob.
I'm a wake-up call.
You know why
kids love athletes?
I don't know.
Because they
screw lingerie models?
No, that's why
we love athletes.
Kids love athletes
because they
follow their dreams.
Well, I can't dunk.
No, but you can cook.
What are you
talking about?
Your resume says
that you minored
in French culinary arts.
Most students,
they work on
the fryer at KFC,
But you bussed
tables at Il Picador
to support yourself.
And then you
get out of college.
And you come
and you work here.
How much did
they first pay you
to give up on your dreams?
27 grand a year.
And when were
you going to stop.
And come back
and do what
makes you happy?
Good question.
I see guys who work
at the same company
for their entire lives,
Guys exactly like you.
They clock in,
they clock out,
And they never have
a moment of happiness.
You have
an opportunity
here, Bob.
This is a rebirth.
Now, if not for you,
do it for your children.
He just waltzes in
and cuts in line?
We reserve
priority assistance.
For our Hilton
honors members.
The promotions are great.
You should check it out.
( laughs )
Hungry much?
Our business expense
allots $40 each
for dinner.
I plan on grabbing
as many Miles
as I can.
Okay, you got to
fill me in
on the Miles thing.
What is that about?
Are you talking about,
like, frequent flyer Miles?
You really
want to know?
I'm dying to know.
I don't spend a nickel
if I can help it.
Unless it somehow profits
my mileage account.
So,
what are you saving up for,
Hawaii, south of France?
It's not like that.
The Miles are the goal.
That's it?
You're saving
just to save?
Let's just say
that I have
a number in mind.
And I haven't
hit it yet.
That's a little abstract.
What's the target?
I'd rather not.
Is it a secret target?
It's 10 million Miles.
Okay.
Isn't 10 million
just a number?
Pi's just a number.
Well, we all need a hobby.
No, I...
I don't mean to
belittle your collection.
I get it.
It sounds cool.
I'd be the seventh
person to do it.
More people have
walked on the Moon.
Do they throw you a parade?
You get lifetime
executive status.
You get to meet
the chief pilot,
Maynard finch.
Wow.
And they put your name
on the side of a plane.
Men get such hard-ons
from putting
their name on stuff.
You guys don't grow up.
It's like you need
to pee on everything.
Now who's stereotyping?
Fear of mortality.
It's like, "Yeah,
you're gonna die one day."
And why do you suppose
that's singular to men?
Probably because
you can't have babies.
The baby argument.
If I had that many Miles,
I would show up
at an airport,
Look at
the destination board,
pick a place and go.
( Cell phone buzzing )
Thanks for the advice.
Oh, Jesus.
Okay. Closer.
Way closer.
Still closer.
Closer. Okay.
A little left.
Okay, down a little.
Too far. Up.
Up one more inch.
I don't get it.
Why does your sister
want a fake photo?
My sister is kooky.
She thinks
this is charming.
It's like
the gnome thing.
No, I mean,
why would your sister
want a fake photo.
In front of
the St. Louis
airport?
Are you kidding,
Lambert field?
The Wright Brothers
flew through there.
That domed main terminal,
it's the first of its kind.
It's a precursor
from everything,
from JFK to De Gaulle.
Pretty sweet.
Just take
the picture.
( Clicks )
Well, that's a keeper.
Let me see it.
Why she wants
dozens of reminders.
Of all the places
she hasn't been
is beyond me.
Well, I'm sure
she'll be crushed.
For having
missed this airport.
Look,
before Lindbergh could
cross the Atlantic,
He took off from
one of those runways.
Do you ever wonder
why they called it
the spirit of St. Louis?
No.
Well...
( sighs )
Do you know how fucked
this place is now?
I am the one thing,
the one thing,
Preventing this place
from being totally
fucked in the ass.
Sometimes they
just need to vent.
Please, for the love of God,
can I fire the next one?
Miss Barnes,
thank you
for joining us.
I'm here to
be fired, right?
Well, we're here
to talk
about your future.
You don't have
to sugarcoat it.
I get the drill.
What are they offering?
Inside the packet,
you'll find a clearly
worked out severance package.
Give me
the bullet points.
It's actually pretty good.
Three months' pay,
six months' medical.
And a full year
of placement services
through our company, CTC.
Placement services.
That's generous.
Commonly,
it takes one month of
searching for every $10,000.
You expect to earn in salary.
So, I could be
looking for a while.
Not necessarily.
Don't even sweat it.
I'm pretty confident
about my plans.
Really?
Yeah.
There's this
beautiful bridge
by my house.
I'm gonna go
jump off it.
Ryan: Natalie.
Hey!
Natalie!
( Sighing )
People say these
things all the time.
It's part of the trade.
They do?
Yeah.
I mean,
they say crazy things.
They get worked up.
She was really calm.
I think
that's a good sign.
So, they don't
ever actually do it?
No. No, it's just talk.
How do you know?
Do you follow up?
I mean, no.
Nothing good's
gonna come of that.
I wouldn't
worry about it.
This is what we do,
Natalie.
We take people at
their most fragile,
and we set them adrift.
You ready to go back in?
All right, let's go.
Come on.
( Goin' Home playing )
♪ I've spent too long ♪
♪ away from home ♪
♪ did all the things ♪
♪ I could have done ♪
No, I'm fine.
Tell me something sweet.
I'll be back soon.
I'm not really sure
how long this whole exercise
is supposed to last.
No, I don't even
think of him that way.
He's old.
♪ I'm not the only one ♪
♪ so long ♪
♪ I'm going ♪
♪ going home ♪
♪ I saw the streets ♪
♪ all ripe with jewels ♪
♪ balconies and ♪
♪ the laundry lines ♪
( stammering ) I'm done?
I wasn't expecting this.
Not at all.
Just like that?
I'm disappointed
that I've given
so much of my life...
This is not fair.
There are people that
are gonna be way more
qualified than me now.
I don't know
what to do when I wake up
in the morning tomorrow.
( Sighs )
Are you okay?
Are we going?
Yeah.
♪ So long ♪
♪ I'm going ♪
Ryan: This is how I start
every day of my life.
Now, this is gonna
be a little difficult,
so stay with me.
You have a new backpack.
Only this time,
I want you to
fill it with people.
Start with
casual acquaintances,
friends of friends,
Folks around the office.
And then you
move into the people.
That you trust with
your most intimate secrets.
Your cousins, your aunts,
your uncles,
Your brothers, your sisters,
your parents.
And finally
your husband,
your wife,
Your boyfriend
or your girlfriend.
( clicks tongue )
You get them
into that backpack.
Don't worry.
I'm not gonna ask you
to light it on fire.
( all laughing )
Feel the weight of that bag.
Make no mistake,
your relationships
are the heaviest.
Components in your life.
Do you feel the straps
cutting into your shoulders?
All those negotiations
and arguments and
secrets and compromises.
You don't need to
carry all that weight.
Why don't you
set that bag down?
Some animals were meant
to carry each other,
To live symbiotically
for a lifetime.
Star-crossed lovers,
monogamous swans.
We are not those animals.
The slower we move,
the faster we die.
We are not swans.
We're sharks.
Natalie: Never?
Ryan: No.
Ever?
No.
You never want
to get married?
Nope.
Never want kids?
Not a chance.
Ever?
Never.
Is that so bizarre?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
I just don't see
the value in it.
All right,
sell it to me.
What?
Sell me marriage.
Okay, how about love?
( Scoffs ) Okay.
Stability, just somebody
you can count on.
How many
stable marriages
do you know?
Somebody to talk to,
someone to
spend your life with.
I'm surrounded by
people to talk to.
I doubt that's
going to change.
( Sighing )
How about just
not dying alone?
Starting when
I was 12,
We moved each one of
my grandparents into
a nursing facility.
My parents went
the same way.
Make no mistake,
we all die alone.
Now, those
cult members
in San Diego.
With the kool-aid
and the sneakers,
They didn't die alone.
I'm just saying
there are options.
Oh, fuck.
Brian left me.
( Sobbing hysterically )
All right.
Okay, okay.
( Shushing )
Yeah.
( Continues sobbing )
Hey.
Natalie,
this is Alex, my friend.
This is Natalie.
I should give
you both a moment.
No. No,
that's fine.
I'm fine.
It's a pleasure
to meet you.
Maybe we should
just all go up to
our rooms and freshen up.
Or maybe a drink?
Now you're talking.
He broke up with you
over text message?
It's kind of
like firing someone
over the internet.
What a weaselly prick.
Yeah.
But what does
that make me?
Someone who
falls for a prick.
We all fall for them.
Pricks are spontaneous,
they're unpredictable,
and they're fun.
And then we're surprised
when they turn out
to be pricks.
I followed him to Omaha.
You did?
I had a job waiting for me
in San Francisco.
When he got an offer
from Conagra.
He said we could
start a life together.
So, I followed him.
To Nebraska?
I thought I'd be
engaged by now.
No offense.
None taken.
That's all right.
When I was 16,
I thought by 23
I'd be married,
Maybe have a kid,
Corner office by day,
entertaining at night.
I was supposed to be driving
a grand Cherokee by now.
Yeah, life can
underwhelm you
that way.
I mean,
where did you think
you'd be by...
It doesn't
work that way.
At a certain point,
you stop
with the deadlines.
It can be a little
counterproductive.
I don't want to
say anything
that's anti-feminist.
I really appreciate
everything that your
generation did for me.
It was our pleasure.
Well done.
But sometimes
it feels like no matter
how much success I have,
It's not gonna matter
until I find the right guy.
You really thought
this guy was the one?
I could have
made it work.
He...
He really fit the Bill.
You know?
The Bill?
White-collar, college grad,
Loves dogs,
likes funny movies, 6'1",
brown hair, kind eyes,
Works in finance
but is outdoorsy,
you know, on the weekends.
I always imagined
he'd have
a single syllable name.
Like Matt
or John or Dave.
In a perfect world,
he drives a 4runner.
And the only thing
he loves more than me
is his golden lab.
And a nice smile.
What about you?
Let me think.
( Sighing )You know, honestly,
by the time you're 34,
All the physical requirements
just go out the window.
I mean, like,
you secretly pray that
he'll be taller than you,
And not an asshole
would be nice.
Just someone
who enjoys my company,
comes from a good family.
Because you don't
think about that
when you're younger.
I don't know.
Someone who wants kids.
Likes kids. Wants kids.
Healthy enough to
play with his kids.
( Chuckling )
Please let him
earn more money
than I do.
You might not
understand that now,
But believe me,
you will one day.
Otherwise,
that's a recipe
for disaster.
( Chuckles )
And hopefully
some hair on his head,
But, I mean, even that's not
a deal breaker these days.
A nice smile.
Yeah, a nice smile.
Nice smile
just might do it.
Wow, that was depressing.
I should just date women.
Tried it.
We're no picnic ourselves.
I don't mind being
married to my career,
And I don't expect it
to hold me in bed
as I fall asleep.
I just don't want to settle.
You're young.
Right now you see settling
as some sort of a failure.
It is, by definition.
Yeah. But by the time
someone is right for you,
it won't feel like settling.
And the only person
left to judge you.
Will be the 23-year-old girl
with a target on your back.
So, what's the plan
for the evening?
Well, we were
gonna hit that party.
For the tech conference
at the hotel.
I didn't know you
could just attend those.
I thought you had
to be registered.
Well, technically,
I don't think.
It's open to the public.
Just gonna
stop by.
You're gonna crash it?
They throw
a really nice party.
Well, they have more money.
Than they know
what to do with.
And they have
a good time,
usually.
No, no, I get it.
I'm in.
Jennifer Chu?
Shit!
It'll be fine.
( O.P.P. Playing )
Doing all right?
Yeah. This was
a great idea.
You're so pretty.
You're exactly
what I wanna look
like in 15 years.
Thank you, Natalie.
You should dance.
Come on.
No, no, no.
( Good Times playing )
Hi. I'm Dave.
I'm Natalie.
Who's Jennifer?
I don't know.
DJ: All right.
How's everybody
doing out there?
( all cheering )
All right.
Right about now,
give it up.
For a very special
Alphatech guest.
Young MC!
What's up, Alphatech?
I got a busted
computer at home.
Can somebody fix it for me?
( all laughing )
♪ This here's
a jam for all the fellas ♪
♪ trying to do what
those ladies tell us ♪
♪ get shot down
'cause you're overzealous ♪
♪ play hard to get
females will get jealous ♪
♪ okay, smarty, go to a party ♪
♪ girls are scantily clad
and showing body ♪
♪ a chick walks by
you wish you could sex her ♪
♪ but you're
standing on the wall
like you was Poindexter ♪
♪ next day's function
high-class luncheon ♪
♪ food they're serving
and you're
Stone-cold munching ♪
♪ music comes on
people start to dance ♪
♪ but then you ate so much
you nearly split your pants ♪
♪ a girl starts walking
guys start gawking ♪
♪ sits down next to you
and starts talking ♪
♪ says she wants to dance
'cause she likes to groove ♪
♪ come on, fatso, just ♪
♪ bust a move! ♪
Say, "Yeah!"
all: Yeah!
Say, "Oh, yeah!"
All: Oh, yeah!
Say, "Bust a move!"
All: Bust a move!
all: Bust a move!
Let me hear you say, "Yeah!"
All: Yeah!
I want you to have
a key to my place.
Wow. I had no idea
we were at that point
in our relationship.
Yes.
Wow.
Where is she?
♪ Lying in my bed I hear the ♪
♪ Clock tick and think of you ♪
♪ Caught up in circles ♪
♪ Confusion is nothing new ♪
♪ Flash back ♪
♪ To warm nights ♪
♪ Almost left behind ♪
♪ Suitcase of memories ♪
♪ Time after ♪
♪ Sometimes
you picture me... ♪
Back home I don't
get to act the way
I do with you.
That's why I don't
have a back home.
I know.
You're so cool.
Mr. Empty backpack.
You know about
my backpack?
I googled you.
You did?
It's what us modern girls do
when we have a crush.
Did it bother you?
It depends.
Is the bag empty
because you hate people.
Or because
you hate the baggage
that they come along with?
I don't hate people.
I'm not exactly a hermit.
You just don't want to be
tied down with the whole
responsibility thing?
I don't know what
originally sparked
the backpack.
Probably needed
to be alone.
Recently, I've been
thinking that I needed
to empty the backpack.
Before I knew what
to put back in it.
Man 1: Oh, no!
Man 2:
I think we're out of gas.
Hey. You're up?
Yeah, I have to fly
standby and make
a meeting in Cincinnati.
Oh.
Okay.
( Exclaims )
I made you feel cheap.
It's all right.
Just leave the money
on the dresser.
I'll text you later
so we can swap schedules.
Hey.
I really like you.
I like you, too.
Good.
Go catch your plane.
Last night...
It was kind of out of hand,
and I said things...
I'm not actually
sure of everything
that I said,
But I didn't
want you to think...
Just relax.
It was nice to
see you cut loose.
So, did you
wake him up
or slip out?
What?
This morning.
Your new friend.
Did you wake him up
for an awkward goodbye.
Or did you just slip out
and make him
feel like a whore?
I just left.
Protocol's always tricky.
What happened to Alex?
She had to leave town early
to get to a meeting.
That's too bad.
Where does she live?
Chicago.
Thinking of going
to see her?
We don't really have
that kind of relationship.
Try right over there.
That direction.
What kind of
relationship
do you have?
Well, you know, casual.
Sounds pretty special.
It works for us.
( Camera clicks )
Don't you think
there's a future there?
I never really
thought about it.
What's going on here?
Really never
thought about it?
No.
How can you not
think about that?
How does it not
even cross your mind.
That you might want
a future with someone?
It's simple.
You know that moment
when you look
into somebody's eyes.
And you can feel them
staring into your soul.
And the whole
world goes quiet
just for a second?
Yes.
Right. Well, I don't.
You're an asshole.
No.
Look, I'm just dicking
around. Come on.
Give me a hand.
Don't you think it's worth
giving her a chance?
A chance to what?
A chance at
something real.
Natalie,
your definition of real.
Is going to evolve
as you get older.
Can you stop
condescending
for one second.
Or is that one
of the principles of
your bullshit philosophy?
Bullshit philosophy?
The isolation,
the traveling.
Is that supposed
to be charming?
No, it's simply
a life choice.
It's a cocoon of
self-banishment.
Wow. Big words.
Screw you.
Screw you, too.
You have set up
a way of life that
basically makes it impossible.
For you to have
any kind of
human connection.
And now this
woman comes along.
And somehow runs
the gauntlet of your
ridiculous life choice.
And comes out on
the other end smiling.
Just so you can
call her "casual"?
I need to grow up?
You're a 12-year-old.
I don't have
a gauntlet...
Fuck.
( Grunting )
( Blow dryer whirring )
Now, listen,
these Detroit guys
can be tough.
They've been
getting hammered.
So, you don't get
distracted. Stick with
the simple stuff.
You get these packets
in their hand.
And you get them
out the door, okay?
Hey, welcome to Detroit.
What's going on here?
I've been looking at
those great numbers
over the last few days.
I thought maybe we
should just nut up
and give this a try.
We could use
a little more time.
Well,
you got to leave the nest
at some point, huh?
This is a real company,
Craig. We're here
to do some damage.
I know. It's a good thing
we brought our best, okay.
Let's stop screwing around.
All right.
Just give me a minute.
To prepare and get
my things together.
I was thinking that Natalie
was going to take this one.
She's hardly
ready for that.
I've been watching her
results the last few days.
She's great.
This is a whole other animal.
You know, she created it
and everything, right?
Natalie,
are you not up for it?
Yeah, I'm game.
That's my girl.
Just remember,
don't apologize,
Don't tell them how
hard this is for you.
Today's one of the worst
days they're ever gonna
have in their life.
How we feel
doesn't even compare.
Got it.
All right. Just keep
it professional.
You'll be fine.
What's all this?
What's going on?
Hello, Mr. Samuels.
I wish I were here
with better news.
However, your position
here at Wertheimer's
is no longer available.
What are you talking about?
You've been let go.
Just like that?
Who are you?
My name
is Miss Keener,
And I'm here
today to talk
about your options.
I worked for this
company for 17 years.
And they send
a fourth-grader
to can me?
What the fuck is this?
It's perfectly
normal to be upset.
However, the sooner
you can tell yourself
that greater.
Opportunities are
waiting for you...
Greater opportunities?
I'm 57 fucking years old.
Anybody who ever
built an empire
or changed the world.
Sat where you are now.
And it's because
they sat there that
they were able to do it.
There's a packet
in front of you.
I want you to take
some time and review it.
All the answers
you're looking for
are inside those pages.
The sooner you
trust the process,
The sooner
the next step of your life
will unveil itself.
( Sniffling )
I need you to
go back to
your office now.
And start putting together
your personal things.
( Sobbing )
Mr. Samuels, that's all
we can discuss now.
Mr. Samuels.
( Continues sobbing )
Mr. Samuels!
( Door opening )
You did good.
You okay?
You want me
to take over?
No, I'm all right.
No. Look, we just got here.
That's one place.
I think we need
to try a few more.
Maybe it doesn't
make a difference,
But it's comforting to know
that we're in the next room.
I know you don't give a shit
about my comfort.
I think we could
try a few more,
that's all I'm saying.
Fine.
All right.
Okay. All right.
He thought you
did a great job.
You did.
I'm real proud of you.
Thanks.
They're pulling us
off the road.
We're going home.
Really? For good?
Yeah.
Good job.
I'm sorry about
what I said about Alex.
That was out of line.
It's all right.
I understand.
I mean,
who am I to be doling out
relationship advice, right?
No kidding.
Are you gonna be okay?
What do you mean?
In Omaha?
I don't know.
It's better than
you'd think.
Ryan.
Ryan. Where
are you going?
I'm grabbing another flight.
Something I've
got to take care of.
I'll see you
back at home.
Okay,
just walk it
in a little.
A little more.
There you go. Yeah.
( Camera clicks )
Got it.
( Chuckles )
They're a cute couple.
You think so?
Yeah, they'll
make cute kids.
How do you like
Wisconsin in February?
I like it
if you're there.
And I know a killer
burger in Milwaukee.
Northern Wisconsin.
What are you
doing this weekend?
No.
What, I haven't...
Well, you want me
to be your date?
Yeah. Yeah.
At your sister's wedding?
It's not like I
know her that well.
Look, I'm not
the wedding type,
right?
But for the first time
in my life,
I don't want to be
that guy alone at a bar.
I want a dance partner.
I want a "plus one."
And if you can stomach it,
I'd like it to be you.
Excuse me.
Are you available?
This line's for
members of our
Matterhorn program.
Kara: Hey. Ryan.
Hey.
Kara. Hi.
Hi.
Hey. Hi.
Alex, this is
my sister Kara.
Hi.
Well, hello.
Ryan's told me
nothing about you.
( Chuckles )
So, you two are dating?
( Both laughing )
Not exactly.
Well, hey,
don't worry
about it.
We're all
getting a little old.
To be calling
someone girlfriend.
I remember when
mom used to call Jack
her boyfriend.
God. Drove me up the wall.
Boyfriends are for kids,
right?
So, what are you
doing at the hotel?
Yeah. Okay,
Frank and I are trying out
a trial separation.
I'm sorry.
So, you're not
staying at the house?
No, there was
a room on hold here,
So I thought
I'd just take it
for the weekend.
So, the rehearsal
dinner.
Yeah, tonight.
I'll see you two there.
Nice digs.
There's a packet.
( Chuckles )
Hey, look who's here.
Oh, my God!
He finally made it.
Oh, my God! Ryan!
Hey.
Hi.
You must be Alex.
Yes, I am.
Hi. How are you?
You are so beautiful.
Kara was right.
Thank you.
Gosh. You look
so grown-up.
I do?
You're the one
that's getting married.
I know, right?
You haven't
even seen my ring.
Look at that.
It's lovely.
Julie: Jim designed it.
That's...
Hey, Jim.
Hey.
How's it going?
Hey. I'm Ryan.
Jim. Good to meet you.
Alex. Pleasure.
Pleasure.
Thank you, guys,
for coming.
Brother!
( All laughing )
It's true, though.
Yeah, it's crazy.
I got the pictures
you asked me to get.
You can just put
them right there.
Yeah, okay.
( Indistinct chattering )
You got so many
of them up there,
I almost didn't have room.
I know. It's so great.
Everyone just chipped in.
What gave you the idea
to do something so...
Substantial.
Well, Jim has
a lot of our
nest egg invested.
In this
real estate venture.
Mmm-hmm. It's a real
estate investment.
It's exciting,
but we went over
our finances and...
A honeymoon just
kind of at this state
in the game.
Just doesn't
really seem affordable.
So, you know,
we just thought,
"just because we can't
travel doesn't mean
we can't have pictures."
No, I think
that's a fabulous idea.
Yeah, it's
a good one.
I mean,
the concept is
turnkey everything.
Okay? You buy
a maintenance contract
when you get the home.
You know,
we'll whack your weeds,
We'll change
your light bulbs.
Furniture,
you can bring your own.
Or else you can pick one
of our beautiful packages.
Seamless traditionalism,
yet all the perks.
Nice.
And we all need
a place to call our own.
This is America.
This is what
we were promised.
It's a nice touch.
What?
The bit at the end
about the promise.
I like that part.
Thanks.
You...
You still renting
that one-bedroom?
No. I gave it up.
So, you own now?
No.
But you're looking?
No, not really.
So, you're just good?
I'm good.
Well, that's good.
Can you believe
it's tomorrow?
How are you gonna sleep?
I don't know.
Well, do you want
some Xanax?
I don't think
that's for sleeping.
Yeah. No, I think
I'll just have a glass
of warm milk.
That'll do
the trick.
Okay.
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Hey.
There's another
box inside.
I'll grab it.
You sure?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
( Chuckling )
Jim seems like
a good guy.
Yeah, isn't he great?
He's going to
make a great husband.
You know, Julie,
I was thinking,
You know,
with dad not being here,
I was wondering
if you had anybody to
walk you down the aisle.
Yeah.
No, Jim's uncle
is gonna do it.
He's been
really supportive.
Julie: He's been great.
Well, good. That's great.
I just wanted to
make sure that you...
I wanted you
to be covered,
that's all.
So, I should
be there, what?
Yeah, the guests
are arriving
around 5:00,
And things
get going at 5:30,
so around then.
Okay.
( Footsteps approaching )
Let me... I'm gonna
help you with those.
Got it.
It's okay.
Ryan: None of that
was here.
Uh-huh?
This is all new.
Really?
Is that all you got?
What?
( laughing )
Give me a boost.
Watch...
Hang on.
( Grunting )
I took geography
in here.
You ever fool around
with one of
your teachers?
No. Did you?
No.
Not until college.
That's me on the right.
It's kind of hard
to tell.
You can tell
by the eyebrows.
You played basketball?
I was a point guard.
Don't act so surprised.
I didn't know
you were
such a jock.
That's me, too.
And that.
My first fight.
How'd it go?
Got my ass kicked.
This is where
we used to go
to make out.
Yes. Yeah.
This is very
romantic.
Go, cougars!
( Whistling )
I'm really happy
I came here.
So am I.
( Cell phone ringing )
It's Kara.
Hey.
Ryan, where are you?
We're having
a meltdown here.
What's going on?
What happened?
It's Jim.
Can you get back here?
We need your help.
Okay.
We got to go.
I'll grab your suit.
Thanks.
( Sniffling )
What happened?
Jim's got cold feet.
Today?
Yeah, that's how
cold feet work.
What do you
want me to do?
Talk to him.
You want me
to talk to him?
Hey, it's either
you or me.
You know my track record.
I've already struck out once.
I haven't been to bat.
I haven't been in the dugout.
Don't you talk for a living?
Motivational-type stuff?
I tell people how
to avoid commitment.
What kind of
fucked-up message
is that?
It's a philosophy.
It's stupid.
Hey, it could have
helped you.
Ryan, you haven't
been around much.
Fuck, basically,
you don't exist to us.
I know you wanna
be there for her.
Well, here it is.
This is your chance.
Hey. What's up, Ryan?
Jim.
You ever read this before?
Yeah, it's pretty
powerful stuff.
Yeah, I'll say.
Kara mentioned that
you were having
some thoughts.
I don't think
I'm gonna be
able to do this.
And why would you
say that today?
Well, last night
I was kind of
laying in bed.
And I couldn't
get to sleep,
So I started
thinking about the wedding
and the ceremony,
And about our buying a house
and moving in together,
And having a kid
and then having
another kid.
And then Christmas
and Thanksgiving
and spring break.
And going
to football games.
And then,
all of a sudden,
they're graduating,
They're getting jobs,
and they're getting married,
And, you know,
I'm a grandparent.
And then I'm retired.
I'm losing my hair.
I'm getting fat.
And then
the next thing you know,
I'm dead.
I'm just, like...
I can't stop from thinking,
"What's the point?"
I mean, what is the point?
The point?
Yeah, I mean,
what am I starting here?
Jim, it's marriage.
It's one of
the most beautiful
things on earth.
It's what people
aspire to.
You never
got married.
That's true.
I mean,
you never even tried.
Well, it's hard
to define try.
I don't know, just...
You seem happier
than all
my married friends.
Look, Jim,
I'm not gonna
lie to you.
Marriage can be
a pain in the ass.
And you're kind of right.
This all is just stuff that.
Leads to your
eventual demise.
Yes.
And we're all on
running clocks,
And they can't
be slowed down
or paused,
And, you know,
we all end up in
the same place.
Yeah.
There is no point.
That's what I'm saying.
( Inaudible )
You know,
I'm not normally
the guy you would talk to
about stuff like this.
If you think about it,
Your favorite memories,
the most important
moments in your life,
Were you alone?
No, I guess not.
Hey, come to
think of it,
Last night, the night
before your wedding,
When all this shit
is swirling
around in your head,
Weren't you guys
sleeping in
separate bedrooms?
Yeah, Julie went
back to the apartment,
And I was just by myself
in the honeymoon suite.
Kind of lonely, huh?
Yes, it was
pretty lonely.
Life's better
with company.
Yeah.
Everybody needs
a co-pilot.
That was a nice touch.
Thanks.
( Exhales )
So, what's
the mood like
out there?
It's not good.
She's pretty pissed?
She's upset.
What should I do?
Go get her.
I'm such a fuck-up.
I love you so much.
Will you be
my co-pilot?
Yes. Yes.
Welcome home.
( Help Yourself playing )
♪ I know you'll help us
when you're feeling better ♪
♪ and we realize
that it might not be
for a long, long time ♪
♪ but we're willing
to wait on you ♪
♪ we believe in everything
that you can do ♪
♪ if you could only
lay down your mind ♪
♪ I... ♪
♪ want you to
try to help yourself ♪
♪ oceans of water
underneath our feet ♪
♪ terrible design ♪
♪ Dusty rooms you cannot sweep ♪
♪ clouding up your mind ♪
♪ I know you'll help us
when you're feeling better ♪
♪ and we realize that
it might not be
for a long, long time ♪
♪ but we're willing
to wait on you ♪
♪ we believe in
everything that you can do ♪
♪ if you could only
lay down your mind ♪
♪ I... ♪
♪ want you to
try to help yourself ♪
♪ I know you'll help us
when you're feeling better ♪
♪ and we realize that
it might not be
for a long, long time ♪
♪ but we're willing
to wait on you ♪
♪ we believe in
everything that you can do ♪
♪ if you could only
lay down your mind ♪
♪ I... ♪
♪ want you to
try to help yourself ♪
Okay, this is
your stop.
When am I
gonna see you?
You're just gonna
have to come visit.
So settled.
You're not
gonna change on me,
are you?
No. Same guy.
Just one address.
Woman on PA: This is
your final boarding call.
For American airlines
flight number 3972
to Chicago.
All right.
Call me when
you get lonely.
I'm lonely.
( laughing )
Natalie: Some guy sits
down in a conference
room somewhere.
And our server
routes his session.
To one of our
termination engineers.
"Termination
engineers"?
Really?
I preferred "terminators,"
but it bumped with legal.
Can't imagine why.
They follow a workflow
that takes them
through anything.
From a standard dismissal
to a violent aggressor.
What are they doing now?
Are they practicing?
Well,
beta testing,
role-playing.
We go live
at the end of
the month.
Kyle, you're
running through the
events too quickly.
You need to give them
time to acknowledge
each statement, okay?
It's a legal thing.
Ryan?
Hmm? Yeah.
There's more?
( Taken at All playing )
♪ Were you looking ♪
♪ for signs along the way ♪
This is ridiculous.
Craig: But, you know,
legal's really starting
to come hard at me.
On this term
"terminate," so...
♪ is this road ♪
♪ really the only way ♪
♪ can this road be taken ♪
♪ taken at all ♪
♪ can you see
by your lonely
light of day ♪
♪ is this road
really the only way ♪
♪ can this road be taken ♪
♪ taken at all ♪
Man: Ladies and gentlemen,
put your hands together.
For today's challenge speaker,
Mr. Ryan Bingham.
( audience applauding )
Go get them.
Last year,
I flew 350,000 Miles.
The Moon is 250.
I want you to
imagine for a second.
That you're
carrying a backpack.
I want you to
feel the straps
on your shoulders.
You feel them?
Now I want you
to pack it.
With all the stuff that
you have in your life.
Start with the little things,
the things on
shelves and in drawers.
Excuse me.
What the fuck
are you doing?
Okay, everyone,
just relax.
Hey, you gotta sign.
Thought I did
that already.
Okay, thank you.
All right.
Hey, you forgot to give me
your Hertz No. 1 gold card!
( Ringing doorbell )
So, I was in
the neighborhood.
( Children shouting )
Boy: Hey! Hey, wait!
Wait, wait.
Man: Hey, honey,
who's at the door?
It's just
somebody who's lost.
( Cell phone ringing )
Alex?
What were you thinking,
showing up
at my door like that?
What do you mean? I...
I wanted to see you.
I didn't know
you had a family.
Why wouldn't you
tell me that?
Look, I'm sorry
I ruined your evening,
But, I mean, you could have seriously
screwed things up for me.
That's my family.
That's my real life.
I thought I was a part
of your real life.
I thought we signed up
for the same thing.
Try and help me understand exactly what it is
that you signed up for.
I thought our relationship
was perfectly clear.
I mean, you are an escape.
You're a break from our normal lives.
You're a parenthesis.
I'm a parenthesis?
I mean...
What do you want?
Tell me what you want.
You don't even know
what you want.
I'm a grown-up, okay?
So, if you would like to see me again,
then give me a call.
Okay?
Stewardess on PA:
Ladies and gentlemen,
We have a special
announcement to make.
Our pilot has just
informed me that.
We are passing over
the city of Dubuque,
Which might not mean much
to most of you,
But means a lot to one of our
flyers today.
Oh, no.
Because he just
hit 10 million Miles!
( all applauding )
Congratulations.
Such an amazing
accomplishment.
You must be
very, very excited.
Hi, captain.
Captain.
That seat taken?
No. No.
You're the youngest
yet to hit 10 mil.
Don't know where
you found the time.
Yeah. I don't know.
Oh, yeah.
Here you go.
Seventh card we've made.
Small club.
We really appreciate
your loyalty.
You know how many times
I thought about this moment?
Played out the conversation
that you and I
would have right here.
Really?
What did you
want to say?
You know,
I don't remember.
That's all right.
It happens to all of us.
So, where
are you from?
I'm from here.
Woman: Hello, Mr. Bingham.
How did you know
it was me?
This is
your dedicated line.
We reserve them
for our most loyal
and appreciated flyers.
I'd like to transfer
some of my Miles.
Can I open up an account
to Jim and Julie Miller?
Certainly. How many Miles
would you like to transfer?
How many Miles
does it take
to circle the globe?
We have our
round-the-world tickets.
They're 500,000 Miles each.
That'd be fine.
Got a second?
I'll call you back.
What the hell happened
to you yesterday?
I was trying to get
hold of you all day.
I was...
Some personal stuff.
What's going on?
Do you remember
Karen Barnes,
Part of a 30-person reduction
a few weeks back in Wichita?
Natalie fired her.
I fire
dozens of people
a day. I...
She killed herself,
jumped off a bridge.
( Sighs ) Fuck.
I need to know.
If you remember any woman
that gave you any signals,
depression...
They're all depressed.
We're firing them.
Hey, I need to ask you
this stuff, okay?
No, I don't
remember anything.
You never think
that they're...
You don't remember any woman
that gave you any signals?
Anything at all, Ryan?
No, nothing stands out.
Natalie all right?
Natalie quit.
She quit?
Text message.
Yeah, fucking nice, right?
No one's got
any manners anymore.
She say where
she was going?
No. She was
a little upset.
I should
give her a call.
I need you
back in the air.
Hey, did you hear
what I said?
I thought you'd be
thrilled about that.
It's fine. What about
the videoconferencing?
CTC is going to pause
the new-media front.
They're gonna give it
some more thought.
We are gonna get
our workhorses
back in the air,
Doing what they
do best, okay?
How long are you
sending me out?
We're gonna let
you sail and sail.
You send us a postcard
if you ever get there.
Man: So, what happened?
How exactly do you mean?
You graduated
top of your class.
You seemed to have
your pick of employment,
including right here.
Instead you went to Omaha
to fire people for a living?
It's challenging work.
I'll say.
I can't imagine
doing that day in,
day out.
Not in this climate.
I followed a boy.
Well, I guess
everybody does that
at one point or another.
This guy says I'd
be lucky to have you.
Ryan: To whom it may concern,
I can't even count
the number of people
I've fired in my lifetime.
So many that I've
actually forgotten.
What it's like
to hire somebody.
We've never met,
but I know you'd be lucky
to have Natalie Keener.
My advice?
Take her and
don't look back.
She'll be the best decision
you've made in a long time.
I sure hope he's right.
Woman: Well,
I don't have
a lot of hope,
And I really don't know
when it's gonna get better.
There's a lot of
people unemployed,
And I really don't know.
When there's
gonna be light at
the end of the tunnel.
I can't find
much to talk about.
Talk about being proud.
I'm proud of my kids.
I think the anger
comes from the fact.
That I just
wasn't needed anymore.
I would say, you know,
Without my
friends and my family,
I wouldn't have made it.
It would have been
a lot tougher.
If I would have had to
make it on my own.
When I wake up in
the morning and I look
over and I see my wife,
That gives me
the sense of purpose.
It's not all about the money.
Money can keep you warm.
It pays your
heating bills, you know.
It can buy you a blanket.
But it's not as...
Doesn't keep you
as warm as when
my husband holds me.
Let me get up.
Let me get out.
Let me find something.
So, my kids
are my purpose,
my family.
Ryan: Tonight most people
will be welcomed home.
By jumping dogs
and squealing kids.
Their spouses will
ask about their day,
and tonight they'll sleep.
The stars will
wheel forth from
their daytime hiding places.
And one of those lights,
slightly brighter
than the rest,
Will be my
wingtip passing over.
( Be Yourself playing )
♪ How does it feel
when life doesn't seem real ♪
♪ and you're floating about
on your own ♪
♪ life seems uncertain
so you draw the curtain ♪
♪ pretending
there's nobody home ♪
♪ don't theorize
look in your eyes ♪
♪ they can't tell lies ♪
♪ though you disguise
what you see ♪
♪ your reality ♪
♪ we needed a savior ♪
♪ and by our behavior ♪
♪ the ones that were worth it
are gone ♪
♪ but songbirds are talking ♪
♪ and runners are walking ♪
♪ a prodigal son's coming home ♪
♪ don't theorize
look in his eyes ♪
♪ and they won't tell lies ♪
♪ but if he defies
what you see ♪
♪ here is a key ♪
♪ be yourself ♪
♪ why don't you be yourself? ♪
♪ come on and be yourself ♪
♪ oh, be yourself ♪
♪ why don't you be yourself? ♪
♪ you can be... ♪
On answering machine:
Hi, Jason. My name is Kevin,
And I recently
lost my job.
I wrote this song
as sort of a statement
about uncertainty.
And having
a certain amount of
anxiety about the future.
So, maybe you can
use it in your movie.
♪ I'm up in the air ♪
♪ choices drifting by me
everywhere ♪
♪ and I can't find the one ♪
♪ that would
help me do the work
I've left undone ♪
♪ 'cause I'm up in the air ♪
♪ I'm making some plans ♪
♪ finding out
there's always new demands ♪
♪ and I can't be precise ♪
♪ when people ask me
what I'm doing with my life ♪
♪ I say, it's up in the air ♪
♪ I'm hearing from friends ♪
♪ it's that tired,
old advice again ♪
♪ you just cannot
keep floating all around ♪
♪ you got to get your feet
back on the ground ♪
♪ but it's hard to come down ♪
♪ when you're up in the air ♪
♪ I'm talking with my peers ♪
♪ listening to them
tell their inner fears ♪
♪ and some have
lives that haven't gone
the way they planned ♪
♪ and some are
trapped in situations
they can't stand ♪
♪ well, I don't want
the same for me ♪
♪ so I stay up in the air ♪