Let's welcome
our favorite alumnus,
and the next senator
from the state of New York,
David Norris!
Thank you. Thank you.
Well, hi, there.
My name is David Norris,
and I'd like to be the next senator
from the great state of New York.
Look at you. What's your name?
I'm going to go through Yonkers,
door to door...
- And take the city that way.
- We love you.
The recent endorsement
by the fire fighter's union
is another boost to Norris
who already had a six-point lead
over his opponent, Roger Linfield.
Whenever I see you on C-Span,
and you stand,
I always think you're about to go, Chug!
Congressman, you certainly started
your career off,
eight years ago, with a bang
or should I say, a bust.
For the last eight years,
David Norris has represented
Brooklyn, New York City and America.
This is my campaign chairman,
Charlie Traynor.
These are voters.
Latest polls have you up 10 points.
We're 10 points up?
This is not going to be easy getting there.
I have some real opposition,
and what they're saying about me is
that I'm too young to hold this office.
- Win big, but run like you're 20 down.
- Okay, you got it.
Thank you, Gary.
But that's okay because
these are the same people
who say that young people don't vote,
young people don't care about politics,
but I'm here to tell you, your future
is about your choices, not theirs.
So, today I'd like to put them on notice
because come November,
I want them to know
that it was young people like you,
who kicked their asses.
David! David!
Thank you.
- Charlie.
- What's wrong?
- Yeah?
- Any ideas?
I'm working on it.
Keep me posted.
Yeah.
David Norris, until recently,
he was way ahead in the polls.
Mary Matalin and James Carville are here.
Mary, this is a surprise.
It is a surprise. Such political promise.
This compelling story, he grew up
in a rough neighborhood in Brooklyn.
He overcame the loss of his entire family,
his mom and his brother when he was 10,
his father before he got to high school,
he got over that. He had such promise.
And he was the youngest person ever
elected to the House of Representatives.
Yeah, he was elected
when he was actually 24,
but he gets in a bar room fight
the night that he's elected.
I like this, all right.
Then you have this photo
coming out of the New York Post.
I think the accretion of this stuff
was just too much for the voters.
It reeked of some level of immaturity here,
of impulsiveness.
People want maturity,
they want adults in Congress.
Big night for us, gentlemen.
Everybody ready?
You look exhausted.
You should take a vacation
when all this is finished.
You've earned it.
I'm not sure the kind of tired I am
can be fixed by a vacation.
Everybody needs a vacation,
even us.
All right, let's get him back on track.
Mary,
over the past couple of weeks
since the photo came out,
they thought people...
Why are you still watching CNN?
That it wasn't such a big deal,
but clearly it was.
They called this way too early.
Come on.
Put on your pretty little tie and let's go.
Suffolk County numbers,
Linfield, 415,120. Norris...
370,233.
I really thought we'd win Suffolk.
Kings County just came in too.
Well...
I didn't win Brooklyn.
It's going to be a blow out.
NBC has us up next.
- I'm going to go work on my speech.
- David...
David. Hey!
I'm sorry I wasted your time, Charlie.
NBC news is now calling the election
for Roger Linfield.
After a shockingly poor showing
at both Suffolk County,
and his home county, Kings,
it now appears David Norris
will lose this election badly.
Hello?
I grew up in Red Hook,
and I don't want to surprise anybody,
but I got into a few fistfights along the way.
It's not whether or not
you get knocked down,
it's what you do when you get back up.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm here tonight
to tell you I will get back up.
But tonight is not about me.
It is about coming together
and welcoming the newest senator
for the great state of New York,
Roger Linfield.
Shit!
Shit, shit, shit.
Hello?
- It's the men's.
- Yep.
Sorry about that.
I didn't mean to eavesdrop.
I just didn't know what to do.
I heard you come in and say, hello,
and I probably should have said, hi,
but then I thought that would be weird
because it's the men's.
Then you started talking to yourself
and it was obviously very personal.
So I was stuck in no man's land,
and then it all got to be too much,
so I came out.
What are you doing in here?
Just...
I'm hiding from security.
Why?
I crashed a wedding upstairs.
People still do that?
It was a dare.
Who dared you to crash a wedding?
Me.
- I crashed a wedding once.
- Did you?
Yeah, in high school.
But I got caught.
I spent the night in jail.
I think that happened more than once
from what I heard.
You're that guy running for Senate,
aren't you?
Yeah, I am that guy.
And judging from your speech,
you're not winning?
No.
That's too bad,
the other guy is such a tool.
He is a tool.
I wish I could have made that clearer
in the campaign ads.
Personally, I think mooning your friends
at a college reunion is no big deal.
The Post did not have to run the photo.
- At least not a full page.
- God, no.
It was my favorite moment
of your whole campaign.
Really? I could have used you on my team
a couple of months ago.
I could help poll test every word that
comes out of your mouth before you say it.
Oh, you like politicians?
I like it when they do stuff I can relate to.
- Like pull their pants down?
- I love that.
See, that kind of candidate wouldn't even
get elected to the student council.
My guy would know how to tie his own tie.
It's a clip-on.
Oh, I wish.
That would have been my other
favorite moment of your campaign.
Do you still have a chance?
Is it over?
He crushed me.
Sorry.
Well, losing has its advantages.
Like what?
For one thing, as a politician,
you're never really alone
unless you're asleep,
or in the bathroom usually.
That gets old.
Really?
Yeah, I guess I'm mostly just looking
forward to having some time by myself.
I don't buy it. I think you love it.
Do I know you?
I guess I could have been more convincing.
Okay.
You don't have to worry about being
convincing till the next election.
Are you a registered New York voter?
Do I sound like I am?
Holy shit.
David.
Wow, sorry, guys.
- Sorry.
- I got to go.
Sorry.
Hang on.
- You going to give your speech?
- Hang on.
Hey!
Hey.
Ma'am.
I got to go.
- Ma'am?
- That is so much better.
She's on the move.
Southwest staircase.
Excuse me? Ma'am.
What was that?
I don't know.
Are you ready?
Yeah, yeah.
All right, go do the speech.
Come on.
Congressman David Norris.
I grew up not far away from here,
in Red Hook.
- Brooklyn!
- I love you, David!
I love you more!
I love you both.
But we had a rule in my neighborhood.
When you got in a fight,
it wasn't whether or not
you got knocked down,
it's what you do when you get back up.
And I came here to tell you tonight,
that I will get back up.
It's bullshit.
We didn't have that saying
in my neighborhood.
It's just one of those phrases
that had some traction
with the focus group
and so we kept using it,
but it's not true.
In 1998, I did a cover story for GQ.
The title was Youngest Congressman Ever.
And since then, every story has tried
to explain how I got here so fast.
And the word that people kept using
was authentic.
But here's the problem.
This isn't even my tie.
- Go get Jim for me.
- This tie was selected for me
by a group of specialists
in Tenafly, New Jersey
who chose it over 56 other ties we tested.
In fact, our data suggests
that I have to stick to
either a tie that is red or a tie that is blue.
A yellow tie made it look
as if I was taking my situation lightly,
and I may in fact, pull my pants down again
at any moment.
A silver tie meant
that I'd forgotten my roots.
My shoes...
You know, shiny shoes,
we associate with high-priced lawyers
and bankers.
If you want to get a working man's vote,
you need to scuff up your shoes a little bit.
But you can't scuff them up so much that
you alienate the lawyers and the bankers
because you need them to pay
for the specialists back in Tenafly.
So, what is the proper scuffing amount?
Do you know we actually paid
a consultant $7,300...
Was it $7,300, Charlie?
Nice. What an asshole.
$7,300, for a consultant to tell us
that this is the perfect amount of scuffing.
He has to spill his coffee on his shirt
by 7:05.
7:05 at the latest.
I'll get him as soon as he enters the park.
Can't imagine being on this guy
as long as you have.
For energy efficient technologies.
RSR Venture Capital announced yesterday
that former Congressman David Norris,
would become a senior partner.
Norris led an unsuccessful bid
for Senate last month.
But his concession speech was considered,
by many, to be electrifying
and has made him the obvious
front runner in the 2010 Senate race.
Investment banker Charles Traynor
founded RSR,
one of the country's most successful
venture capital firms.
Traynor is a childhood friend of Norris' and
was the Chairman of his Senate campaign.
- Hey!
- Hey.
Tom Frankel from The Journal
is calling you in five minutes.
I just gave him this number.
Give him 3-2-2-7.
I'm not used to this phone yet.
No, I can't.
He's going to ask you about joining the firm.
All business calls have to be done
on a company Blackberry.
- Really?
- Sarbanes-Oxley.
You voted for it, pal.
In fact, you co-sponsored that one.
Yeah, I remember.
Hey, I just saw you on TV.
- Really?
- Yeah.
What did they say?
You're bald.
Nice.
Yeah, it was weird too,
because it was a financial show.
But they were really captivated
by your receding hairline.
I got to go, you jack-off.
Bye.
Congressman.
I have to tell you,
I really admire what you did last month.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
I wish there were more politicians like you.
Thank you. I'm retired now.
I had to go get a real job.
- You'll do well.
- Thank you.
Hey!
You got a guy running for the bus.
There is another M6 right behind me.
Hey!
No way.
Sorry.
Oh, my God.
Have we met?
You look vaguely familiar.
- Waldorf men's room.
- You got it.
Were you just staring
at my legs while I slept?
I was defenseless against the small dress.
It's a skirt.
It's a belt.
What is it with you and the argyle?
What is the deal with you
and the boring shades of blue?
My clothes match.
Did your team pick that out for you?
No team. Team is gone.
I did it all by myself.
I saw your speech.
Yeah, the speech.
Something must have got into me.
Wow, that is something.
Really augments the moment.
Nice ring, asshole.
Hello? Hello?
It doesn't even work.
Could that ringer get louder
- or do you have that maxed out?
- It's a new phone.
Are you going to run again?
Don't know.
I'm starting a new job today.
You have to run again.
You can't do that.
The country will end up being
run by tools like Linfield.
It kind of is.
Oh, shit.
Sorry.
I don't know what just happened.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Can you hand me that?
- You sure you okay?
- Yeah.
- I'll pay for the dry cleaning.
- No, it's really fine.
Please don't.
Seven bucks will probably cover it.
You keep that, you might need it.
You know what? Here.
You write your number down, then I can
call you and come pick up your skirt.
Oh, my goodness, me.
That is very smooth.
Oh, shit.
Why don't you let me spill some on you
and then we'll be even?
- That's a terrible idea.
- I think it's a great idea.
Just one bit because that's not fair.
You actually are crazy.
No, now it all makes sense.
Okay, hang on. Oh, jeez.
He's not here. I know, I'm sorry.
- Who was that?
- I don't know. Who cares?
- It'll be on the... Can you just...
- No.
Okay, now we're in the third grade.
This is great.
It's a sturdy little fucker, isn't it?
I'm sorry. I don't know what happened,
it just happened.
Okay.
- Okay, that was a new phone.
- Let's wipe it off.
I'm Elise, by the way.
I'll remember that.
- That's my number.
- Terrific, thank you.
I'll call you.
The morning after the election,
I woke up thinking about you.
Hey, man, what's up?
You're not going to believe
who I just ran into.
- Who?
- The girl from election night.
- The one you kissed?
- She kissed me.
You still sticking with that story?
- It's the truth.
- Whatever, dude.
They're ready for you
in the main conference room.
What are the odds? It's amazing.
That's great, man, just don't take
her advice on speeches anymore.
First time worked,
it's not going to work again.
You're just jealous
because it's the best speech I ever gave
and you didn't write it.
Just so you know, I think I'm coming down
against your solar panel thing.
Why?
I just don't think the research is there
and the price point is too high
on these things.
Of course, it's too high.
But if our company doesn't get involved
with stuff like this, who will?
Convince me in the meeting.
I will. See you, buddy.
Hey, Janet.
Hey, Susan.
We just got approval
for a recalibration on the Lasalle case.
Two minutes.
Hey!
What the hell are you doing?
Grab him.
9-1-1, Janet! 9-1-1!
You can't get away, David.
David, I really wish you'd just listen to me.
All right, I'll handle it.
David,
you really are making this
harder than it has to be.
All right, take it easy, guys.
Take it easy.
It's okay, David.
No. No, sir.
It's being taken care of.
Yes, sir. It's being taken care of.
Yes, sir. No, sir.
No, sir. Yes, sir.
I understand. I'll take care of it.
What a goddamn mess.
- Donaldson?
- Yes.
What do you want to do?
We have to reset him. Call for a briefcase.
You kidding? It's going to take
a signed order from the Chairman.
- Get legal on it.
- Legal just arrived.
There's no way
the Chairman approves a reset.
This is your fault.
There is no way you get a briefcase.
Hey.
- What are my options?
- Hey.
Just bullshit him.
Bullshit this guy?
Hey! What's going on here?
Look at this.
Questions will burn in him
till the day he dies.
He won't stop searching for answers.
He won't quit.
We have to watch him
forever, make sure he doesn't talk.
Endless ripple effects.
You remember the Torres case
40 years ago?
It's not that bad, is it?
In the end, they just leveled with him.
Completely?
Looking at that,
I don't see you have a choice.
Who the hell are you guys?
We...
are the people who make sure
things happen according to plan.
My name is Richardson.
You really think
I couldn't see that coming?
I can read your mind.
Yeah, really.
Pick a color.
Blue.
Pick a number. Seventeen.
Now, why are you still thinking
about running?
I don't really know what's going on here.
You've just seen behind a curtain that
you weren't supposed to know existed.
Must be jarring.
It's not your fault.
Your path through the world this morning
was supposed to have been adjusted.
You were supposed to spill your coffee
as you entered the park this morning.
You would have gone upstairs to change,
you would have missed the bus,
and you would have arrived at work
10 minutes later than you did,
and we would have been gone.
I was supposed to spill my coffee?
We call that an adjustment.
See, sometimes, when people spill
their coffee or their Internet goes out
or they misplaced their keys,
they think it's chance.
And sometimes it is.
Sometimes it's us...
nudging people back on plan.
Sometimes when nudging isn't enough,
management authorizes a recalibration.
We deploy our Intervention Team and
they change your mind for you,
like we did with your friend Charlie.
He's fine, by the way.
You don't need to worry about him.
Now...
There is something I need you to
understand if I'm going to let you go.
Okay.
Very few humans have seen
what you've seen today,
and we're determined to keep it that way.
So, if you ever reveal our existence,
we'll erase your brain.
The Intervention Team will reset you.
Your emotions, your memories,
your entire personality will be expunged.
Your friends and family will think
you've gone crazy.
You won't think anything.
You understand?
Not one word about us.
Okay.
Oh, one more thing, you bumped
into a woman this morning on the bus.
Elise?
What does that have to do with anything?
You were never supposed to see her again.
What does that matter?
Because it matters.
- It's in his wallet.
- Hey, hey. God! Hey!
What's with you guys? Jesus!
Oh, come on. No! No!
What the hell?
Really?
Okay.
- Okay.
- Take him back.
- Enjoy the rest of your day.
- I can walk. I'm capable of walking.
Dude, what are you doing on my floor?
You know, I called you like 10 times,
you could have picked up.
Christine, I found him. He's in my office.
What the hell are you doing?
Round up the guys,
we're going to do the meeting now.
You have a headache?
What is wrong with you?
Hey, we're in the big conference room on 17.
Let's go.
Morning, Congressman.
You sure you're okay?
Yeah, you?
I'm great, why?
You don't have a headache or anything?
No, I feel fantastic, man.
Is it me or is this an odd conversation?
On David's solar panel deal,
our tech guy has serious doubts
about the efficiency ratings they're claiming.
They'd need a 20-fold improvement
over anything anyone else
has been able to manufacture at that
price point to really be a game-changer.
You're opposed to this anyway, Charlie.
And with these financials...
I know it's a risk, but,
if our company doesn't take a chance
on something like this, then who will?
I mean, I'm willing to take a fire
on something that could change the world.
Not to mention, be incredibly lucrative.
David?
Yeah, I mean, it's why I took the job here.
All right.
Let's do it.
Come into my office for a second.
Something is wrong.
A couple of hours ago you miraculously
reunite with the girl of your dreams.
Explain to me why you don't have
an ear-to-ear grin right now.
I lost her number.
What?
The woman on the bus.
I lost her phone number
and all I had was her first name, so,
I'm never going to see her again.
I'm sorry.
Wow, I'm really sorry.
Your entire world is turned upside down
and you're thinking about a woman.
Even if you could remember the number,
you'll never get through.
Lost cell phone, changed numbers,
whatever creates the fewest ripples.
My name is Harry, by the way.
The fewest ripples?
You freeze people. You froze my friend.
We need special authorization to...
Poke around in people's brains.
- You make them think whatever you want...
- Be quiet, David.
- Can I get you something?
- Just some water, please.
Your friend will be fine.
Recalibrations make tiny changes
in the way people reason.
It doesn't work on emotion or personality.
That's too intrusive.
You said authorization.
Authorization from who?
The Chairman.
The Chairman?
That's just a name we use.
You use many other names.
We can't talk here.
Meet me on the 4:00 p.m. boat
and I'll answer what I can.
If you reveal us,
even if it's unintentional...
I know. You'll bump me on the head.
Richardson has automatic authority
to reset you.
You mean lobotomize me?
Try not to forget it.
Be on the 4:00 p.m. boat.
Ask your questions, I'll tell you what I can.
What were they doing to Charlie?
Just changing the way he weighs
investment risks
which will subtly shift the direction
of his company in the way upstairs wants.
So, Richardson could read my mind?
Richardson was trying to scare you.
No, he knew the number
I was thinking of, the color.
Because he set it up as a choice.
Choose a color, choose a number.
We can't read your mind
or hear your thoughts.
When you make a decision,
your mind weighs options.
We can perceive them.
We know when you're going to go
off the plan or not because
if we're close enough,
we can sense when it's going to happen.
We're just here to keep you on plan.
That's all we're authorized to do.
Are you allowed to be telling me this stuff?
Are they following me now?
We have to monitor the entire world.
We don't have the manpower
to follow everyone all the time.
And there is something about water.
It blocks our ability
to read your decision tree.
Are you an angel?
We've been called that.
We're more like case officers
who live a lot longer than humans.
Why are you helping me?
I have my reasons.
And why won't they let me be with Elise?
All I know is
the amount of resources they've used
keeping you from her
is pretty damn important to them.
You're going to look for her, aren't you?
You won't find her.
They'll make sure of it.
Even if they weren't trying to stop you,
there are nine million people in this city.
You'll never find her.
Forget about her.
Move on with your life.
Stop! Stop the bus!
Elise? Elise, hi.
David.
You know, I rode the M6 to work
every day for three years
hoping that I'd bump into you.
Listen, is there a place we could go
and talk?
Don't you have to get to work or something?
I just got sick.
I haven't seen you in three years,
you make me sick.
That's not an ideal come-on,
just so you know.
What are you looking for?
I felt like someone was watching us.
Hey, Charlie,
I'm going to have to skip breakfast,
and I probably have to postpone the speech too.
I just bumped into Elise.
You just hung up on your friend.
We've known each other since we were kids.
- What speech?
- It doesn't matter.
- You want to take a walk?
- No.
We have a lot to catch up on.
I don't think you should cancel your speech.
What if I don't like you
at the end of our walk?
I'll take my chances.
Seriously, my number hasn't changed,
just call me like you didn't last time.
Look, if you take a walk with me,
I'll explain why.
It's been years. How do you know
I don't have a nice boyfriend?
Do you have a nice boyfriend?
- Would it matter if I did?
- Yeah.
So you don't have any real conviction then?
Okay, it wouldn't matter at all.
So, you don't mind being a home-wrecker?
Congressman!
How are you doing, man? I'm from Red Hook.
You're the best.
Thank you. Good to see you.
If you were married, then it would bother me.
But now you're just saying
what you think I want to hear.
I'm single.
Now let's hear your bullshit excuse
for not calling me.
I didn't have your number.
I gave it you on the bus.
Handed it to you.
I was mugged. It was taken from me.
No, come on.
- My wallet was taken.
- Come on.
Why else would
I fawn all over you on a bus
three years ago and then never call you?
Because, I don't know!
You have a girlfriend and you felt terrible.
Listen, I swear to you
that I did not have your number.
All right.
No, on my parents' graves.
- That's heavy.
- That's too heavy, I know, but it's true.
I didn't have your number.
And I didn't even have a last name to go by.
If you google just Elise,
- you get 757,000 hits.
- You did not.
And none of them are you.
- We have a problem.
- What?
David Norris is off plan.
Son of a bitch. How did he find her?
Chance.
Just spotted her on the street.
We never should have let him meet her
in the first place.
We followed protocol to the letter.
Guy rides the same bus every day
for three years.
Who does that?
Three years later,
I'm still cleaning up your mess.
Let's cut the power
at her dance studio.
I'm a dancer.
Not like that, you pervert.
I'm in a contemporary ballet company.
I think you have the wrong idea about me.
No, I think that was the first thing
that crossed your mind, actually.
I think you should invite me
to one of your performances.
The company is called Cedar Lake,
and there is actually a show
tomorrow night, if you want.
- Is that an invitation?
- No, it's information.
We're covering the girl's artistic director
and we're still working on Charlie Traynor.
This whole thing will be over in an hour.
Hi, how are you? Paul, right?
- How did you remember that?
- I'm a politician, I'm good with names.
Her decision tree
is diverging from our models.
- It's just the two of you?
- Yes.
Thirty-six hours without contact,
she'll never speak to him again.
Look at her file.
It's the last thing in the world
she'll put up with.
No, something's wrong.
I'm already seeing inflection points.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
We're in motion on changing
the location of her rehearsal.
You have to be born with the right body
like very flexible hips
and shoulders and long neck.
- And you weren't?
- No, I was. I was lucky.
But after 15 years of that precision
and the training...
How is everything over here?
It's great. Thank you.
It's good, thank you.
So, I wanted to try something else
just on my own,
open-ended and human, I guess.
What do you mean?
Look.
What's this?
If they kiss.
A kiss? That's all it takes?
A real kiss.
If that happens, every possible adjustment
strong enough to break them up
will cause ripples over your limit.
I think that everything you go through in life
should come out in the way that you dance.
I haven't found that to be the case
with my dancing.
It's a shame.
David, hate to interrupt.
- Hi.
- Hi, nice to see you again, Elise.
- How did you find me?
- Does it matter?
Nice work.
There's a crowd of people
waiting for your announcement speech
at the Brooklyn Bridge right now.
You're announcing today?
You can't skip this for me.
I know. I told you I'm not going to
let you out of my sight.
- David, what the hell?
- Do you want to come?
- Do you want to watch?
- No. I can't, I have to go and rehearse.
Actually, I just heard that
they're moving my rehearsal
to Pier 17, right next to the bridge.
Why don't we just postpone it?
We'll do the speech another time.
- No, David, come on, you can't do that.
- Thank you.
- You have to go.
- Check.
David, she's rehearsing so close.
It'll take you three minutes
to get there after the speech.
- All right.
- Just come over when you're done.
Keep the change. Thank you.
Have Charlie's aide call him now.
Are you sure you don't want a ride?
No, I have to go home and change.
You're so late.
Your friend is about to cry.
I'm wrangling him right now.
Yeah, I know.
Shifting her rehearsal to Pier 17
was a genius move.
We're not out of the woods yet.
Come over when you're done.
- David.
- Okay.
Sorry, the TV crew is there.
We got to go, man.
We're okay.
Look, whatever happens, I'm not going to let
anything come between us again.
Okay.
I'll see you soon.
Hey, how you doing?
Thank you. Appreciate it.
How are you?
Thanks a lot. Good to see you too.
Thank you.
I have to say,
it's good to be back in Brooklyn.
There's been a lot of speculation
- as to whether or not...
- It's done.
I would run for a Senate seat here
in the state of New York.
I came here today
to put an end to that speculation
and to tell you, unequivocally,
I will seek the Senate seat
for the great state of New York.
David! David!
Shit.
Don't forget, I added the bankers' group
after The Daily Show tomorrow.
Are you listening to me?
David?
I cannot get a break on this case.
Okay. I got to get to Pier 17.
Do the interview
and you can do whatever you want.
Just handle the interviews for me.
I'll talk to those guys...
- This has got to go on the nightly news.
- I got to see Elise right now.
Every time we get close,
you do something to mess this up.
This is different.
- City, please?
- Manhattan.
- What listing?
- Cedar Lake. It's a dance company.
Connecting.
He's going to ask the parking attendant
to use the hard line.
I already killed it.
Excuse me, can I use your phone?
I have an emergency.
Restaurant across the street.
I took out everything for three blocks.
This guy is a pain in the ass.
Come on, let's go talk to him.
There is a whole world of women out there.
I thought we established
this one was off limits.
It's been a while, I must have forgotten.
Doesn't change the fact.
You put us together three times.
That wasn't us, that was just chance.
Why do you want to keep us apart?
Because the plan says so.
Then you misread the plan.
There is no misreading the plan
when it comes to you and Elise.
Then the plan is wrong.
- Do you know who wrote it?
- I don't care.
You should.
You should really show a little respect.
If I'm not supposed to be with her,
how come I feel like this?
It doesn't matter how you feel.
What matters is what is in black and white.
You don't know why I'm not
supposed to be with her, do you?
That's why you can't tell me.
You don't know.
Who is this guy?
Excuse me, everyone.
Sorry to disturb your lunch.
It's an emergency.
Has anyone here ever seen a performance
at the Cedar Lake Ballet Company?
The Cedar Lake Ballet Company?
Yeah, I have.
Where is it?
Son of a bitch.
Hey, taxi. Hey!
Taxi! Hey!
Taxi!
Maybe you should try the subway.
Don't all these taxies you're diverting
have plans too?
How long you going to keep that up?
Twenty minutes? An hour?
Wow, the ripples must just be endless.
I don't care what you put in my way,
I'm not giving up.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Taxi!
Hey!
You all right?
- You okay?
- What happened?
You got hit. Are you okay?
- I think so.
- Don't move.
You all right?
Hello, I just witnessed an accident
on the corner of Water and Dover Street.
Unfortunately,
you're the only witness, Congressman.
- But we did this three times already.
- I just need a few more details.
Oh, I see.
You're not even a cop, are you?
You're one of them.
- Calm down.
- Okay.
Someone could have been killed.
Sir, if you would just calm down.
Hey, Sergeant.
Hi. Sorry, excuse me,
I know you need a statement from me,
but do I need to stay here
or can I do it over the phone?
No, sir, we know
how to get in touch with you.
Okay. Now, is this man
under your command?
Never mind. Thank you.
Hey, hey, hey!
You want to make a quick 100 bucks?
You're going to have to break
a couple of traffic laws.
All right, 26th and 10th.
It's a ballet company called Cedar Lake.
Go through that.
Look out!
Watch it.
This is going to keep happening,
just go through.
Son of a bitch!
- Set a traffic jam on Broadway.
- Too many ripples.
He's getting out of range.
I don't know what to do with this.
You're reaching your limit.
Hey!
Excuse me.
Two down. Two down.
Oh, shit!
Next one.
I hate downtown.
Sorry.
I've got inflection points.
All he needs to do is see her dance
and you're at your ripple limit.
What?
All right, block the door.
He's already through it.
Not that one, the next one.
Excuse me.
David Norris, I'm here to see Elise.
I'm blocking them all.
Hat! Hat!
- Is she here?
- Yeah, she's in the studio.
It's too late. He's already seen her.
You hit your ripple limit.
Celebrate now.
They're just going to kick it upstairs.
It's Donaldson.
He has no idea what he's up against.
Let's take a walk.
The intense chemistry between them,
the constant inflection points,
and the kicker, you pulling them apart twice
only to have chance put them back together.
Yeah, all that seemed a little much.
So, I asked Burdensky
to do some research this morning.
Have you been in here before?
No, of course not.
It seems like David Norris and Elise Sellas
were meant to be together
because they were meant to be together.
Wait, what?
In the '70s when he was born,
they were meant to be together,
same thing in the '80s, '90s.
Wasn't till 2005 that the plan changed
and she was supposed to stay with Adrian.
The problem here is there are remnants
from all those old plans
that keep pushing them together.
They still feel like they belong
with each other even though they don't,
and we're about to tear them apart again.
You spend your whole career
hoping, someday,
you'll get a red-letter case.
Something you can really
make a name for yourself with.
Finally you get one,
and it's booby-trapped.
What?
I'm saying, it wasn't your fault.
They were meant to be together.
What?
Were. In an earlier version of the plan.
Actually, a dozen earlier versions.
I always wondered
how we had such bad luck
that she was on that particular bus
on that particular day.
How could a plan just change like that?
I don't know.
It's above my pay grade.
So, we're going operational.
This is exciting. It's been a while.
We're not going operational.
No one ever made it to my job
by taking stupid risks.
So, what are we going to do?
We're going to kick this case upstairs
to someone with the latitude
to clean up this mess
without breaking into a sweat.
We're going to bring this to Thompson.
Thompson?
When he was in the field,
his nickname was...
The Hammer, yes.
He'll crush this little romance
with a flick of his hand
and force them back on plan again.
I want to go to a club.
Why ruin a really nice day?
- Come on.
- No, I don't dance.
Everyone can dance.
You just feel the music.
Well, I've been told
that I have trouble feeling.
Who told you that?
A long list of women.
That's gross.
You know what?
Let's race to that lamppost.
You win, I dance for you.
I win, you dance for me.
On the pole?
If you like, yeah.
This is serious. What are the rules?
There are no rules.
You bastard! Oh, my gosh!
You challenged me in those shoes?
Okay, fine. I can't.
You're right. These are the wrong shoes.
I'm going to twist an ankle.
You said, no rules. I avoided them.
You said you had trouble feeling.
Great.
Hey, David.
- You're even cuter in person.
- Hey, it's David Norris.
How you doing? How are you?
How are we feeling about this tie?
- Hey, David Norris!
- Hey, how you doing?
Maybe I should go home and get my tux.
Definitely don't do that. It's good.
I should never have come back
here again without my backup dancers.
- I voted for you.
- How are you?
Norris, you're a rock star!
Did you grow up over here?
Yeah, three blocks over that way.
Pioneer Street.
My whole childhood.
What were you like as a kid?
I've spent about half my time in the
principal's office up until the sixth grade.
Yeah, that was when
my mother and my brother died
within a month of each other.
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's fine.
You know how I always tell that story
about how I got inspired to go into politics
because my dad took me to the Senate Gallery
and we sat together and that's true.
But what I leave out is
he did that right after they died.
And I was bottoming out.
So, he wanted to get me out of here
for a little while
and he planned this road trip to DC,
and I think it's because JFK was his idol.
And we went and sat in the gallery.
I remember watching him watch them,
and I knew that that's what I wanted to do.
I wish they were here to see all this.
I was...
Didn't expect to tell you any of that.
David?
- Hello?
- It's Adrian.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Why are you calling?
Hi.
No, I was...
Because I was sleeping.
No.
No, it's not.
Why are you calling?
Okay, well, I got to go.
No, I got to go. Okay.
I'm so sorry.
- It's all right. Everything okay?
- Yeah.
Oh, my God. That was so weird.
I woke up and you weren't here.
And then the phone rang
and it was my ex
which is just so strange.
Sorry, I guess we hadn't gotten
to any of that stuff yet.
Right.
You know, we broke up a while ago,
and it's over and then he calls
four times in one morning.
He called you four times this morning?
How long have you guys been broken up?
Three months.
It's like he knew I was with someone else.
- Was it serious?
- We were engaged.
So, not really that serious?
Right.
Well, what happened?
- Do you want to know this?
- Yeah.
He was a great guy.
Brilliant choreographer and dancer,
and we had the same group of friends.
We had known each other a long time.
Well, he sounds great.
Why didn't you marry him?
Because of you.
I'm not some hopeless romantic.
I've never allowed myself to be that way.
But once I felt,
even for a moment,
what I felt with you.
You ruined me.
I didn't want to settle for less.
I know the feeling.
It scares the shit out of me.
I'm not going to hurt you.
You don't need to say that.
This is the first time
in 25 years that I don't feel
like I'm by myself.
That's a lot
of responsibility for me.
I don't know if I'm quite comfortable
with that.
Well, too late.
You know, I'm supposed to go
to an interview right now.
What if I told you I wasn't
ready to let you out of my sight quite yet?
- Sounds good.
- You want to go?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Are you handsome
or is it that
Washington is so populated by
I don't want to say,
hideous abnormalities...
This is getting a little weird.
David Norris, everybody.
- Excuse me, ma'am.
- Yes?
Congressman Norris asked me
to give you a message.
He was just called into a meeting.
- He says it's urgent.
- Okay.
He said he'll call you as soon as he's out
and he'll see you at the show tonight.
Okay, thank you. Thanks.
This way, Congressman.
Hello?
Frustrating, isn't it?
My name is Thompson.
Whatever happened to free will?
We actually tried free will before.
After taking you from hunting and gathering
to the height of the Roman Empire,
we stepped back to see
how you would do on your own.
You gave us the Dark Ages
for five centuries
until finally we decided
we should come back in.
The Chairman thought that maybe
we just needed to do a better job
with teaching you how to ride a bike
before taking the training wheels off again.
So, we gave you the Renaissance,
the Enlightenment, scientific revolution.
For 600 years we taught you
to control your impulses with reason.
Then in 1910, we stepped back again.
Within 50 years,
you had brought us World War I,
the Depression, Fascism, the Holocaust,
and capped it off by bringing
the entire planet to the brink of destruction
in the Cuban missile crisis.
At that point a decision was taken
to step back in again
before you did something
that even we couldn't fix.
You don't have free will, David.
You have the appearance of free will.
You expect me to believe that?
I make decisions every day.
You have free will over which toothpaste
you use or which beverage to order at lunch.
But humanity just isn't mature enough
to control the important things.
So, you handle the important things?
The last time I checked,
the world is a pretty screwed-up place.
It's still here.
If we had left things in your hands,
it wouldn't be.
Tell me why I can't be with Elise?
Because the last guy didn't know.
Meeting Elise at the Waldorf
three years ago wasn't chance.
That was us.
We knew she would inspire you
to give that speech.
That speech that brought you back
from the edge of oblivion
and overnight made you the frontrunner
in this coming election.
What are you saying?
You want me to win the election?
This one and four more after it.
And I'm not just talking about elections
for Senate.
You can matter, David. Really matter.
What your father wanted when he took you
to the Senate Gallery when you were 10.
What your brother wanted when he made
you promise the day before he overdosed
that you wouldn't be like him.
Why do you think you have that yearning
to be in front of people?
That terrible emptiness when you're not.
Don't do that.
David, you can change the world,
but that doesn't happen
if you stay with her.
Why do you people care who I love?
It's not about her, it's about you.
What being with her does to you.
What it does to me?
I'm better when I'm with her!
Even you said it. The speech.
In small doses, Elise was the cure.
But in large doses,
- she rubs off on you.
- Stop.
David, the president can't be a loose cannon.
Stop talking. It's not working.
Why do you refuse to accept
what should be completely obvious by now?
You've seen what we can do.
You can't doubt we are who we say we are.
Look, it's not about who you are,
it's about who I am.
Can't outrun your fate, David.
I just disagree with you
about what my fate is.
I know what I feel for her
and it's not going to change.
All I have are the choices that I make.
And I choose her
come what may.
It's 6:20.
If you leave now,
you can make Elise's show.
She's a beautiful dancer.
I thought I made myself clear.
There is one more piece to this
I haven't mentioned.
I guess I just didn't have the heart.
If you stay with her,
it not only kills your dreams, it kills hers.
What?
Elise is about to become one of
the most famous dancers in the country
and eventually one of the world's
greatest choreographers.
If she stays with you, she ends up
teaching dance to six-year-olds.
When you look back at all this, David,
just remember
we tried to reason with you.
I always hear people saying,
you can't blame yourself
for what happens to other people,
but in this case, really, you can.
This is what you do, David.
This is what you did getting into a bar fight
the night you first got elected.
What you did to get that embarrassing photo
in The New York Post.
We give you opportunities
other people would kill for
and you squander them with impulse.
It doesn't take a genius to see Elise
isn't exactly helping you with this.
It's a sprain, David,
but if you stay with her, you'll take
away the only thing she ever cared about.
It's up to you.
- It's just a sprain.
- Yeah.
The doctor said it's going to
be better in a month or less.
That's totally unexpected.
I'm so relieved.
Great. Great.
You're such a great dancer,
and you'll heal up
and just get better and better.
- I'm going to go make a couple phone calls.
- Okay.
Okay.
I'm so happy for you.
It's done.
Thompson finished it.
I know.
You can't let it get to you
like it did with his family.
This is the job.
You ever wonder
if it's right?
I mean,
if it's always right?
Not like I used to.
Look, Chairman has the plan.
We only see part of it.
I was talking to some friends of ours
over in Monroe County this morning,
and I said something to them that I think
a lot of you may have heard me say before
but it bears repeating.
David Norris, who has spent the last
two days campaigning in the Tri-Lakes area
received some welcome news yesterday
when the latest New York Times poll
gave him a 16-point lead over his opponent
less than a month before election day.
Since his announcement 11 months ago,
Norris has had a significant lead...
Hi. Thanks. Thanks a lot.
Yeah, thank you. I need it. Thank you.
- Who should I make it out to?
- My nephew, Miles.
- There you go.
- Thank you so much.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure. Pleasure.
- Can we get a picture with you?
- Sure, come on.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Hey.
I want to show you this,
because you would find out eventually.
I want to be here when you do.
She's getting married
to that guy she was engaged to.
You okay?
I think I'm going to...
Take a day off.
Hell, take a couple. We're 16 points up.
Yeah, even I can't blow a lead that big.
Congressman,
good to see you again.
Your friend just left you this.
He said you would be stopping by.
Why would you want to see me?
Thompson was lying when he said
you couldn't be with Elise because
she brings out your reckless side.
Then why?
Why do they care so much?
Because she's enough, David.
If you have her, you won't need
to fill that void inside of you
with applause and votes
and dreams of one day making it
to the White House.
That's important,
but it's not the only thing that matters.
Why are you so different from them?
Your dad...
was a very smart man.
He could have been a lot more.
Wanted to be.
Your brother too.
But the plan didn't call for it.
What about my mother?
That wasn't me.
That wasn't us at all.
It was just chance?
I'm sorry.
You know, Thompson is not lying.
They're already talking about me
being a presidential candidate.
I'm phoning in my speeches
and I'm 16 points up.
The public loves you.
Before I met Elise, that's all I cared about.
I don't even notice it now.
I can't stop thinking about her.
Do you know where she's getting married?
In front of a judge tomorrow morning.
Is she happy?
Thompson won't let you anywhere near her.
Not tonight, not tomorrow, not ever.
Harry.
Is she happy?
I got to try and get her back.
Will you help me?
Will you just help me get to her?
They'll sense you coming a mile away.
What if I could move as fast as you?
Teach me about the doors.
The rain will stop in the next hour,
and that's the only thing keeping them
from seeing us right now.
If we're going do this,
we'll need all night to do it
and a place surrounded by water
to do it in.
Always turn the doorknob clockwise.
What happens if I turn it the other way?
You don't want to do that.
That's only for us.
Put your hand on my shoulder
and don't let go
until we cross the threshold.
Are these ever locked?
Not when you're wearing one of our hats.
Keep moving, David.
Is this...
It's the Museum of Modern Art.
Yeah.
Close the door.
This is the city's main pumping station
for downtown Manhattan.
We're 10 blocks from the courthouse.
Wait here.
Hi, is the floor open?
You okay, sweetie?
Yeah, I just...
I just feel like being on the floor.
Lower Manhattan is layer upon layer
of substrate.
That's what we call the doors
that have been added over time.
Makes it a lot more complex to
navigate downtown than it is uptown
and a lot slower.
Your destination, 60 Centre Street,
Courtroom 300.
There are thousands of different ways
to get to the courthouse using the doors.
I want you to learn
how to stay in the substrate
so Thompson won't be able
to get a fix on you.
Okay.
Just south of the diner, it's a red door.
I come out on Broadway,
right by Leonard Street.
That's good. Keep going.
From Leonard, half a block down.
Okay, suppose Thompson's there?
Okay, I go east to Lafayette.
No, it's Crosby Street there.
Eight doors?
I'm zigzagging all over the place.
That will take me too long.
But every time you go through a door,
their plan books will lose track of you,
so it's safer.
Look, I need you to understand
this has never been done before.
So, the minute you go through that
first door, all hell will break loose.
Assume everyone with a hat on is a threat.
I don't care if it's a Yankee cap,
a bowler, or even a yarmulke.
Assume everyone in a hat
is working with Thompson.
Even you guys can't get through the doors
without your hats on, right?
Right.
It's one of the ways the Chairman
limits our power.
Water is another way.
And you said before, what if Thompson's
in front of me on Crosby Street?
Right.
Why don't I just knock the hat off his head
and then run by him
before he has time to pick it up?
That's good, improvisation.
We have trouble with that.
The fastest way is actually
if I go right for the blue door.
Yeah, but then you're exposed
the entire way there.
That's a lot more dangerous
than leapfrogging through doors.
But if I make it,
I'll take them completely by surprise.
If you make it.
Come on, we have a lot more to get through.
Whatever it takes.
Your father used to say that.
I guess you're not supposed to
identify with your subjects.
You're not supposed to feel guilt.
We're not built to lead
with our emotions like you are,
but that doesn't mean we don't have them.
Some more than others.
You're lucky, it started raining again.
We need to get going.
The wedding is in 10 minutes.
We have time.
Being early is just as bad as being late.
Is your fiance here?
She's on her way in.
Courtroom 300.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- This is it.
- Okay.
- I'm going to go for the blue door.
- Of course.
Here is your way through it.
Don't lose it.
- Thanks, Harry.
- Good luck.
Okay.
It looks like Mr. Norris is using the rain
to make a run for it.
Call the proctor at the wedding.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing. I'm just nervous, I guess.
I just need a minute in the bathroom, okay?
Sir, he's got a hat.
He's in the substrate.
He just went into the substrate.
No, no, no.
It's an emergency. Sorry.
Docket number 22, please come forward.
- We're next. Will you go check on her?
- Yeah.
- You're David Norris!
- Yeah, I got to go.
- Nothing in the hat.
- Go ahead.
She's not even in there.
Where is she? Where is she?
Elise.
You're not marrying that guy.
I'm so sorry,
and I don't know what you must
think of me, but you can't marry him.
You don't love him.
I've been terrible, I know.
- I'm getting married.
- No, you can't.
Don't touch me! What are you doing?
Do you know that no one has ever hurt me
as much as you did?
I'm so sorry that I left you the way that I did.
David, you know what?
You left me in a fucking hospital.
What are you doing?
I know it seems terrible
but there was a reason.
You don't know anything about me
and what makes me happy.
I'm sorry that I hurt you.
Oh, my God.
Don't worry about him, he's with them.
- Just listen to me.
- Oh, my God, what did you do?
- Forget about him.
- What are you doing?
Look at me, I know that you love me.
Okay, this says that you love me
and that I love you and that
we're not supposed to be together.
Because of this book.
But I know that I'm supposed to be
with you because of the way I feel.
I love you and I don't care what happens.
I want to spend the rest of my life with you
even if it's only a little while.
He just revealed us.
Call the Intervention Team.
Tell them it's a square-one reset.
Mr. Thompson has deployed
the Intervention Team.
He's requesting an emergency
Reset Authorization.
I'll carry it in.
Why are they chasing you?
They're going to reset me.
What are you talking about?
I never lied to you.
Down here.
He's down here.
I love you, Elise.
I'm going to show you something.
You deserve to know.
What's going on?
We got to keep moving.
There is another door here.
Got them. Sixth Avenue.
Contain this.
Oh, my God. What's happening to me?
All you need to know, we're being chased.
I need you to trust me.
- Okay.
- Okay, come on.
Door, door, door!
Find another door!
What the hell is going on?
What the hell is going on, David?
Okay, I'm sorry.
- How did we just do that?
- I'm so sorry.
These doors belong to the people
who are chasing us.
- Who are they?
- I don't know what to call them,
but they want to take you away from me.
Why do they care about us?
They hurt your ankle, Elise.
Everything you've worked for your entire life,
it doesn't happen if you stay with me.
- That's why I left you in the hospital.
- I don't understand.
I don't understand.
This can't be wrong.
Why do they think it's wrong?
The book... Their book.
But what if I can find who wrote it?
Okay, I can go through this door alone.
You'll never see me
or the people chasing us again.
Or you could come with me,
and I don't know what's on the other side,
but I know you would be next to me,
and that's all I've wanted
since the minute I met you.
I'm coming with you.
Okay.
Take the other one.
Turn it to the left.
To the left.
Oh, my God.
Hey! You can't be in here.
Stop, sir!
Hold them up!
Come on.
Stop them!
Harry Mitchell,
they want you in the Chairman's office.
Immediately.
Come on.
Hey! Hey!
How did you get in here?
Search the room!
Shit!
Go back.
No.
Oh, my God.
- I love you.
Did you really think
you could reach the Chairman?
And change your fate if you did?
Or write your own?
It doesn't work like that and I told you why.
I've got a message for you.
I understand.
Even Thompson has a boss.
Harry?
- You're the Chairman?
- No.
You've met him though, or her.
Everybody has.
The Chairman comes in a different form
to everyone
so people rarely realize when it happens.
Is this some sort of test?
In a way, it's all a test,
for everybody, even the members
of the Adjustment Bureau.
David, you risked everything for Elise.
And Elise, when you came through that door
at the Statue of Liberty,
you risked everything too.
But you inspired me.
It seems like you inspired the Chairman too.
- Is that about us?
- Yes.
What does it say?
It says that this situation
between the two of you
is a serious deviation from the plan.
So, the Chairman rewrote it.
Okay.
Now what?
Now...
You can take the stairs.
Most people live life
on the path we set for them.
Too afraid to explore any other.
But once in a while,
people like you come along
who knock down all the obstacles
we put in your way.
People who realize free will is a gift
you'll never know how to use
until you fight for it.
I think that's the Chairman's real plan,
that maybe one day
we won't write the plan.
You will.