[SNORING]
-Good morning, Miss Ratched.
-Good morning.
-Mr. Washington.
-Morning.
-Good morning, Miss Ratched.
-Good morning.
-WASHINGTON: Morning, Bancini.
How you feel?
Rested.
Medication time. Medication time.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
[MUTTERING]
[WASHINGTON SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Okay, move it up.
Mr. Fredrickson, just be careful now.
Juice.
WASHINGTON: Chief.
Okay, my friend, let's go.
OFFICER: Here's his papers,
and I'm gonna need a signature.
[INMATE LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
Whoo!
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
Hi.
-Mr. McMurphy's here.
-RATCHED: All right.
Thank you.
-All right, I'm ready.
-Okay. One pair of socks.
T-shirt.
Hi.
Goddamn, boy, you're
about as big as a mountain.
Look like you might
have played some football.
What's your name?
He… He can't hear you.
He's de… Deaf and dumb Indian.
Is that so?
Come on, Bibbit.
McMURPHY: Can't even make a sound, huh?
How.
[INMATES SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[WHOOPING]
HARDING: Come on, Billy.
Club lead. Jack of clubs.
Ha, ha. Uh-oh.
-McMURPHY: What's your name, son?
-Bill… Billy Bibbit.
Glad to know you, Bill. McMurphy's mine.
Ha-ha-ha.
That's old Charlie Cheswick's cards.
-Ha-ha.
-That's his ace of spades.
Your turn, Bill.
Big 10.
-Put one of them on it, will you?
-Wait a minute.
Oh, I can win that one.
-I win.
-Oh, you overtrumped?
-Sure.
-Pinochle, huh, Bill?
-You're avoiding spades?
-Mm-hm.
Oh, okay.
You sure you're avoiding spades?
What's the bid?
-I know how to play the game.
-Five… Five-fifty.
Oh, uh, you like to look at
other people's cards, do you?
-Yes.
-Ever seen this one?
-Come on, Martini.
-Martini.
Martini, will you…
Will you play a club?
Whose turn is it now?
Well, let's see, he trumped.
Where you going?
-Aren't you gonna play?
-What's the matter with him?
-Aren't you gonna play, Martini?
-HARDING: What's…
Martini? I wanna play.
You took a trump.
You got… It's your lead.
Billy? Billy, I wanna win some… I…
Get a grip on yourself, will you?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Yes?
-Mr. McMurphy's here, Doc.
-Good, have him come in.
Thank you.
McMurphy, I'm Dr. Spivey.
Dr. Spivey, what a
pleasure it is to meet you.
Sure.
Pull up a chair, sit down, let's talk.
[CLEARS THROAT]
R.P. McMurphy.
That's a hell of a fish there, Doc.
-Isn't that a dandy?
-Yeah. It's about 40 pounds, ain't it?
-No, 32.
-Thirty-two.
I'll tell you, it took every
bit of strength I had
to hold it while the
guy took the picture.
Every damn bit.
Probably that chain
didn't help it any either.
You didn't weigh the chain, did you, Doc?
No, I didn't weigh the chain, but
damn, I'm awful proud of that picture.
That's the first Chinooker I ever caught.
-It's a nice one.
-Hmm.
Randall Patrick McMurphy.
Thirty-eight years old.
Mm.
What can you tell me about, uh
why you've been sent over here?
Well, ahem, I don't know.
What's it say there?
-Mind if I smoke?
-No, go right ahead.
Well, it, um
says several things here.
Said you've been belligerent
talked when unauthorized
you've been resentful in attitude
toward work in general, that you're lazy.
Chewing gum in class.
[McMURPHY LAUGHS]
The real reason you've
been sent over here
is because they wanted
you to be evaluated.
-Yeah.
-To determine whether or not
you're mentally ill.
-Uh-huh.
-This is the real reason.
Why do you think they might think that?
[SIGHS]
Well, as near as I can
figure out, it's because I, uh…
Uh, fight and fuck too much.
In the penitentiary?
No, no, no, you mean why… Wait…
Why did you get sent over
here from the work farm?
Oh. Oh, yeah. Oh. Uh…
Well, I really don't know, Doc.
It says here that you went around…
-Let me just take a look.
-It ain't up to me, you know.
One, two, three, four…
You've got at least
five arrests for assault.
Yeah.
-What can you tell me about that?
-Five fights, huh?
Rocky Marciano's got
40, and he's a millionaire.
-That's true.
-That is true.
Of course, it's true that you
went in for statutory rape.
That's true, is it not, this time?
Absolutely true. But, Doc
she was 15 years old going on 35, Doc,
and, uh, she told me
she was 18, and she was
uh, very willing. You know what I mean?
-Mm. Mm.
-I practically had to take
to sewing my pants shut.
But, uh, between you and me, uh
she might have been 15.
When you get that little red beaver
right up there in front of
you, I don't think it's crazy at all.
-And I don't think you do either.
-I hear what you're saying.
No man alive could resist that.
That's why I got into jail to begin with.
Now they're telling
me I'm crazy over here
because I don't sit there
like a goddamn vegetable.
It don't make a bit of sense to me.
If that's what being crazy is
then I'm senseless, out of
it, gone down the road, wacko.
But no more, no less. That's it.
Well, to be honest with you,
McMurphy, what it says here…
Is that
they think…
They think
you've been faking it in order
to get out of your work detail.
What do you think about that?
Do I look like that
kind of guy to you, Doc?
Well…
Let's just be frank for a
minute, Randall, if you would.
Tell me
do you think there's anything
wrong with your mind, really?
Not a thing, Doc.
I'm a goddamn marvel of modern science.
Well, you're gonna be here for
a period for us to evaluate you.
-We're gonna study you.
-Mm-hm.
We'll make our determinations
as to what, uh, we're going to do,
and give you the necessary treatment, uh
-as indicated…
-Doc, let me just tell you this.
I'm here to cooperate
with you 100 percent.
A hundred percent.
I'll be just right down the line with you.
You watch.
Because I think we ought to get to
the bottom of, uh, R.P. McMurphy.
[EXHALING SHARPLY]
INMATE: Whoo!
The scythe.
-INMATE: Oh.
-I'm awfully tired.
-WASHINGTON: Sit down.
-I'm tired.
Well, sit down.
INMATE: Oh.
That better?
[INMATE COUGHS]
WASHINGTON: Mr. Ellsworth
you'll wear yourself out. Come here.
Okay.
RATCHED: All right,
gentlemen, let's begin.
At the close of Friday's meeting
we were discussing Mr. Harding's
problem concerning his wife.
Mr. Harding stated that
his wife made him uneasy
because she drew stares
from men on the street.
-Is that correct, Mr. Harding?
-Yes. Uh, yes. That's correct.
He also thinks he may
have given her reason
to seek sexual attention elsewhere,
but he wasn't able to say how.
Mr. Harding has been
heard to say to his wife:
"I hate you.
I don't ever want to see you again.
You've betrayed me."
So does anyone care
to touch on this further?
[PAPER RUSTLING]
Mr. Scanlon, would you begin today?
Are you sure?
Billy, how about you?
No… No… No, ma'am.
RATCHED: I'd like to write in my
book that you began the meeting.
[INMATE COUGHS]
RATCHED: Just once.
Mr. Martini?
Are you with us?
Yes.
RATCHED: Would you like to begin?
Mr. Cheswick?
-Me?
-RATCHED: Yes.
You mean there's not a man here
who has an opinion on this matter?
[INMATE CLEARS THROAT]
RATCHED: All right.
Mr. Harding
you've stated on more than one occasion
that you suspected your
wife of seeing other men.
Oh, yes. Yes, very much… I suspect her.
Well, maybe you can tell
us why you suspect her.
Well, I can only
speculate as to the reasons why.
Have you ever speculated, Mr. Harding
that perhaps you are
impatient with your wife
because she doesn't meet
your mental requirements?
HARDING: Perhaps, but you
see, the only thing I can really
speculate on, Nurse Ratched
is the very existence of my
life, with or without my wife
in terms of the human
relationships, the juxtaposition
of one person to another,
the form, the content.
Harding, why don't you knock
off the bullshit and get to the point?
This is the point.
This is the point, Taber.
It's not bullshit.
I'm not just talking about my
wife, I'm talking about my life.
I can't seem to get that through to you.
I'm not just talking about one
person, I'm talking about everybody.
I'm talking about form.
I'm talking about content.
I'm talking about interrelationships.
I'm talking about God,
the devil, hell, heaven.
-Do you understand? Finally?
-Ha!
Yeah, Harding, you're so
fucking dumb I can't believe it.
Oh. Oh.
It makes me feel very
peculiar, very peculiar
-when you throw in that.
-Peculiar?
-Why?
-What does that mean, peculiar, Harding?
-Peculiar? Peculiar?
-Peculiar?
-SEFELT: Ha-ha-ha.
-I'm going to tell you guys something.
You just don't wanna learn anything.
You just don't want to listen to anybody.
He's got intelligence.
You've never heard the word peculiar?
Say, what are you trying to say?
You trying to say I'm queer? Is that it?
Little Mary Ann?
Little Marjorie Jane? Huh?
That it?
Is that what you're trying to tell me?
Is that your idea of
communicating something?
-Well, is it?
-CHESWICK: Oh.
They're all crowding
in on you, Mr. Harding.
-They're all ganging up on you.
-Is that news?
No, they… They sometimes
wanna gang up on me too, but I…
-Cheswick, do me a favor.
-CHESWICK: What? Huh?
-Take it easy.
-CHESWICK: Take it…
-And stay off my side.
-CHESWICK: But I only wanna…
I only wanna help you.
-HARDING: I understand.
-CHESWICK: Don't you want me to…
-HARDING: Please.
-CHESWICK: But I only wanna…
-Please.
-But I only wanna help you.
Please!
HARDING: You see
the other day you made
some allusions, both of you.
-Illusions?
-HARDING: A sexual… Yes, allusions.
Allusions. Not illusions. Allusions
to sexual problems I
might be having with my wife.
All right, say it's true.
Say I know it to be true, but you don't.
If that's your idea of
trying to tell me something…
Harding, I think you're some kind
of morbid asshole or something.
-SEFELT: Peculiar.
-Asshole again.
FREDRICKSON: It makes you feel peculiar.
You been talking about your wife ever
since I can remember. She's on your mind.
-Blah, blah, blah.
-I'm not talking about my wife.
When are you gonna get
that through your head?
When are you gonna
wise up and turn her loose?
-FREDRICKSON: Please.
-SEFELT: No, just peculiar.
-I'm tired.
-I don't wanna hear it.
-BANCINI: I'm tired.
-CHESWICK: I don't wanna hear it.
-I'm tired.
-It's a lot of baloney.
-CHESWICK: I don't wanna hear it.
BANCINI: It's a lot of
baloney and I'm tired.
CHESWICK: I don't wanna hear it.
WARREN: We know you're tired.
We're tired.
BANCINI: I'm tired
and it's a lot of baloney.
WARREN: You're not tired, Bancini.
[SOBBING]
BANCINI: Take your hands off me.
[INMATES YELLING]
[INMATES PLAYING MUSIC]
RATCHED [OVER PA]:
Recreation time, gentlemen.
The bus is waiting.
All non-restricted patients
please report to the bus.
Ever play this game, Chief?
Come on, I'll show you.
Old Indian game.
It's called, uh, Put
the Ball in the Hole.
Now, that ought to be…
Just hold it right there.
All right.
Now, that's your spot. Don't move.
Never move.
That's your spot, you understand?
Right there. You don't move. Now
take the ball.
Here, take the ball.
That's it. Hold on to it.
Not too hard, Chief.
You'll crush all the air out of it.
We're gonna put her in the basket.
You understand?
All right. Now, uh, raise up your arms.
Raise the ball up in the air, Chief.
Raise it up.
McMurphy, what you talking to him for?
He can't hear a fucking thing.
I ain't talking to him.
I'm talking to myself.
It helps me think.
Yeah, well, it don't help him none.
Well, it don't hurt him either, does it?
Don't hurt you, does it, Chief?
See? Don't hurt him.
All right, now, Chief, uh…
Let's raise our hands up in the air.
Just raise them up.
Up, you understand?
Raise the hands up, here.
Up. Raise your hands up.
Up. That's it. That's it.
Up, all the way up.
All the way up.
That's a baby, all right. Huh?
Okay, now, uh…
Now, jump up in the air,
and put it in the basket, Chief.
Jump up and dunk it in.
Jump up in the air and stuff
that son of a bitch in there, Chief.
Take a rest, Chief.
Just stay right there.
Take a rest. I'll be right back.
[McMURPHY LAUGHS]
Bancini, come here a minute.
You're looking all right.
Get right over here for a second.
Now, just stand right there.
Just get down a little bit.
All right. Stand up.
Stand up. Go ahead.
Whoo. That's a baby.
All right, you got her.
All right. Now, over there.
[LAUGHS]
Hit me, Chief. I got the moves.
I got them, Chief.
Hold it right there. Give me the ball.
Give me the ball. That's it.
Thank you, Chief.
Now, hold it right there.
Now, you take the ball, you
jump up and put it in the basket.
See what I mean?
Put it… Bancini, hold still.
All right, Chief, here. Take the ball.
Now, jump up and put her
in the basket, Chief. Huh?
Jump up and put her in the basket!
Not you, Bancini.
Raise up… Bancini, where you going?
-I'm tired. I'm tired.
-Where… No.
Fast break. Defense. Get back. Back.
Come on, Bancini, where
the fuck you going at?
-General, get this man around here.
-BANCINI: Aah! Aah!
-That's it, back. Over to Chief.
-Oh, I'm tired.
Fast break. Fast break.
Hit me, Chief. Hit me, baby.
Put it in the basket, Chief!
Put it in the basket!
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON TV]
[MUMBLING]
[McMURPHY SHUFFLING CARDS]
McMURPHY: Thirty-eight…
All right.
Make the bets.
-MARTINI: What's this?
-Make the bets.
It's a dime, Martini.
MARTINI: I bet a nickel.
A dime's the limit, Martini.
[INMATE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
I bet a dime.
This is not a dime, Martini.
This is a dime.
If you break it in half
you don't get two nickels, you get shit.
Try and smoke it. You understand?
-Yes.
-McMURPHY: You don't understand.
All right, here they come.
Queen to the Chesser,
big bull to Tabelations
10 to Billy to match his whang,
and the dealer gets a three.
MARTINI: Hit me. Hit me.
-Hit me. I bet a dime.
-McMURPHY: I can't hit you
because it ain't your turn yet.
You understand?
You see these other people?
These are the real ones.
These are real people here.
What'll you do, Ches? Hit or sit?
CHESWICK: Um…
Hit me.
McMURPHY: That's 23 up, Cheswick.
All right, Taber, you're busted.
Give me this.
-Twenty-three…
-McMURPHY: Uh? Hit?
-Hit me.
-Shut up!
McMURPHY: Taber.
-Give me a dime.
-MARTINI: I'm next, Taber.
McMURPHY: You're not next. Huh?
-MARTINI: Hit me.
-Ace.
-That's four or 14.
Don't want any more. Billy?
-MARTINI: Hit me. Hit me.
-McMURPHY: All right, five.
-Hit me. Hit me.
-McMURPHY: Huh?
You didn't make a bet, Martini.
I can't hit you. Jesus Christ.
-Huh?
-MARTINI: I bet a dime.
All right, here. Go ahead.
-That's 20 showing.
-MARTINI: No.
-Take your money.
It's not.
It's 10, 11, 12, 13.
This is a fucking queen
here, you understand?
-You don't count the this… and the this:
-Hit me.
You got 20 showing.
MARTINI: Hit me again.
I want another card.
-Scanlon, who's pitching the opener?
-MARTINI: Mac? Mac? Mac, here.
Medication time.
-MARTINI: This isn't a queen.
-Medication time, gentlemen. Medication.
-MARTINI: Mac, hit me.
-McMURPHY: Who's the…
-Who's pitching the opener?
-Hit me.
Jesus Christ Almighty.
Do you nuts wanna play
cards or you wanna jerk off?
TABER: Play the game.
I can't even hear myself think already.
Aah! Stay back.
McMURPHY: Excuse me, ma'am.
I just wanted to…
-Stay back.
-Mr. McMurphy.
Patients aren't allowed
in the nurses' station.
Well, I just, ahem, wanted to, uh, turn…
When you're outside, we'll discuss
whatever problem you have, okay?
Patients are not allowed in
the nurses' station. All right?
McMURPHY: Yes, ma'am.
PILBOW: Billy.
Let me get in here, will you, Hard-on?
Thank you. Excuse me, miss.
Do you think it might be
possible to turn that music down,
so maybe a couple of the boys could talk?
That music is for everyone, Mr. McMurphy.
I know, but do you think we
might ease it down a little bit,
so maybe the boys didn't have to shout?
Huh?
What you probably don't realize
is that we have a lot
of old men on this ward
who couldn't hear the
music if we turned it lower.
That music is all they have.
Your hand is staining my window.
-Oh. I'm sorry, ma'am. Really sorry.
-RATCHED: All right.
-Mr. McMurphy, your medication.
-Huh?
-What's in the horse pill?
-It's just medicine. It's good for you.
Yeah, but I don't like the idea of taking
something if I don't know what it is.
-Don't get upset, Mr. McMurphy.
-I'm not getting upset, Miss Pilbow.
It's just that I don't want anyone
to try and slip me saltpeter.
You know what I mean?
[TAPPING ON COUNTER]
RATCHED: It's all right, Nurse Pilbow.
If Mr. McMurphy doesn't want
to take his medication orally
I'm sure we can arrange that
he can have it some other way.
But I don't think you'd
like it, Mr. McMurphy.
You'd like it, wouldn't you, Hard-on?
Give it to me.
-RATCHED: Good.
-Mm.
Mm.
Very good.
Mm, yummy.
-PILBOW: Mr. Harding?
-Mm-hm. Oh.
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
Tell me, lover boy
why didn't you tell
her to go fuck herself?
[LAUGHING]
Jesus Christ.
Okay. Funny, huh? That's funny, huh?
You know, that wasn't very smart.
She could have seen that.
-Oh.
-Yeah.
-Ooh.
-Oh.
Ooh.
God Almighty, she's got
you guys coming or going.
What do you think she is?
Some kind of a champ or something?
HARDING: No, I thought
you were the champ.
Wanna bet?
Bet on what?
One week.
I bet in one week I can
put a bug so far up her ass
she don't know whether
to shit or wind her watch.
What do you say to that?
Wanna bet? No, you wanna bet?
One week. That's all I need.
Who wants to bet?
You wanna bet? Bet a buck. One buck. Huh?
I'll bet.
McMURPHY: Tabes in, 1 buck. Solid.
Last time we were discussing
Mr.
Harding and the problem with his wife,
and I think we were
making a lot of progress.
So who would like to begin today?
Mr. McMurphy?
Yeah, I've been thinking
about what you said about, uh…
[McMURPHY CLEARS THROAT]
…you know, getting things off your chest.
And, uh… Uh, ahem.
Well, there's a couple of things
that I'd like to get off my chest.
Well, that's very good, Mr. McMurphy.
Go ahead.
McMURPHY: Okay.
Today, as you may or may
not know… It doesn't matter.
…is the opening of the World Series.
What I'd like to suggest is that
we change the work detail tonight,
so that we can watch the ball game.
RATCHED: Well, Mr. McMurphy,
what you're asking
is that we change a very
carefully worked-out schedule.
A little change never hurt, huh?
A little variety?
Well, it's not necessarily
true, Mr. McMurphy.
Some men on the ward take a long,
long time to get used to the schedule.
Change it now, and they
might find it very disturbing.
Ah, fuck the schedule. They can go
back to the schedule after the Series.
I'm talking about the World
Series, Nurse Ratched. Huh?
Well, anyway, this is no
way to proceed about this.
How would it be if we had a vote,
and let majority rule?
Great. Let's vote on her.
So all those in favor, raise your hands.
Okay, guys, come on.
Put your hands up.
What's the matter with you?
Don't you wanna watch the World Series?
Come on, get your hands up.
It'll do you good
to get some exercise
putting your arms up in the air.
That's it. Come on, let's…
What is this crap?
I mean, I watch the Series.
I haven't missed the Series in years.
Even in the cooler.
When I'm in the cooler,
they run it there or they have a riot.
What's the matter with you guys?
Come on, be good Americans.
Well, Mr. McMurphy, I
only count three votes,
and that's not enough
to change ward policy.
I'm sorry.
HARDING: My turn. Okay, hot dice.
I wanna get to go.
Because I need cash.
I wanna get to Mediterranean Avenue.
Big 10. Perfect.
Two fives. Two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine…
-What are you doing?
-Hotel.
-You do not have a hotel there.
For the third time
-you do not have a hotel on Boardwalk.
-MARTINI: Hotel.
-It costs $1000 and four green houses…
-Hotel.
-…to put a hotel on Boardwalk.
TABER: Play the game.
-Knock off the bullshit.
-Huh?
-Play the game, Harding.
-What are you talking about?
-Play the game.
-I ain't doing anything to you.
-What bullshit?
-Your bullshit.
-Your bullshit?
-Play the game.
-HARDING: Hands off me.
-TABER: Play the game.
-Enough bullshit. You hear me?
-Play the game.
-What the fuck are you picking on me for?
-Play the game, Harding.
-Look, I'm trying to ignore you.
-Just play the game.
Keep your hands off me.
-Keep your hands off me! You hear me?
-TABER: Play the game.
-Come on, come on, come on.
-I can be pushed just so far, see.
TABER: Play the game.
You touch me once more.
Just touch me once more.
Just once more, huh? Just once more.
-Just touch me once more.
-TABER: Play the game, Harding.
HARDING: Just touch me once more.
Holy Jesus.
[YELLING]
[LAUGHING]
Is that what your schedule
does for you, Hard-on? Huh?
Damn lunatic.
I don't know what you're talking about.
No?
Well, then stay all wet, Harding, huh?
Because I'm going downtown
and watch the World Series anyway.
Anybody wanna come with me?
-I do, Mac. I wanna go with you.
-McMURPHY: Ches, all right. Anybody else?
-Where?
-Any bar downtown.
Mac… Mac, you can't…
Can't get… Can't get out of here.
Anybody wanna bet?
Hmm, chickenshits?
Maybe he'll just show
Nurse Ratched his big thing,
and she'll open the door for him.
[LAUGHING]
Yeah, maybe I will,
and then maybe I'll just use your
thick skull and knock a hole in the wall.
Sefelt, see?
[LAUGHING]
Why, my head would
squash like an eggplant.
[LAUGHING]
Fuck Sefelt's head, I
don't need Sefelt's head.
I'm gonna take this, put
it through the window,
and me and my buddy
Cheswick are gonna go out
downtown, sit down in
a bar, wet our whistles,
and watch the ball game.
And that's the bet.
Now, does anybody want any of it? Huh?
You're gonna lift that thing?
Yeah. That's right.
I'll bet a buck.
Taber, $1.
I bet a dime.
Mac, you can't…
Can't li… Lift that thing.
Anybody else want any of it? Hard-on?
Hmm?
I'll bet $25.
Twenty-five dollars, Hard-on.
Mac! Mac, no… Nobody
could ever lift that thing.
Get out of my way, son.
You're using my oxygen.
You know what I mean?
All right.
[GRUNTS]
Giving up?
No. Just warming up.
Warming up. Warming up.
This will be the one.
All right, baby. Come on.
[McMURPHY MUTTERING]
Fucking thing.
[GRUNTING]
But I tried, didn't I? Goddamn it.
At least I did that.
[BANGING]
MAN [ON RADIO]: And on the
mound, the left-hander Al Downing.
The two pitchers still warming
up right down below us.
The second game of the 1963 World Series
is being brought to you
from Yankee Stadium.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO]
RATCHED: Did you tell the
girl how you felt about her?
Well… Well, I went…
I went over to her house
one Sunday afternoon,
and I brought…
Brought her some flowers.
And I said… I said:
"Celia, will you ma…"
[STUTTERING]
"Ma… Marry me?"
[LAUGHING]
Billy?
Why did you want to marry her?
Well, I was in lo… In love with her.
Your mother told me that
you never told her about it.
Billy, why didn't you tell her about it?
Billy, wasn't that the first time
you tried to commit suicide?
Oh, my God.
Yes, Mr. Cheswick?
Miss Ratched
I'd like to ask you a question, please.
Go ahead.
Okay, uh… You know, if, uh
Billy doesn't feel like, uh, talking
I mean, uh, why are you pressing him?
Why can't we go on to some new business?
Huh?
The business of this
meeting, Mr. Cheswick
is therapy.
Oh.
Well, you know, I don't
understand this, Miss Ratched
because, uh, I don't, uh…
Mr. McMurphy
he said something
yesterday about a World Series.
A baseball game?
You know, and I've never
been to a baseball game,
and, well, I think I'd like to see one,
and that would be good therapy,
too, wouldn't it, Miss Ratched?
I thought we'd decided that issue.
Well, I don't think so, because, I mean
we discussed that yesterday,
and we have a new game
today, I think, don't we, Mac?
That's right, Ches, and we
want a new vote on it, don't we?
Would one more vote
satisfy you, Mr. McMurphy?
Yeah.
It'll satisfy me.
There's a vote before the group.
Everyone in favor of changing the
schedule, please raise your hand.
Okay, I wanna see the hands. Come on.
Which one of you nuts has got any guts?
-All right. That's it.
-I only count nine votes, Mr. McMurphy.
Ha-ha-ha. She only counts nine.
Only nine. It's a landslide.
[LAUGHING]
There are 18 patients on
this ward, Mr. McMurphy,
and you have to have a
majority to change ward policy.
So you gentlemen can
put your hands down now.
Are you trying to tell me that
you're gonna count these?
These poor son of a bitches?
They don't know what we're talking about.
Well, I have to disagree
with you, Mr. McMurphy.
These men are members
of the ward, just as you are.
All right. All I need is one vote, right?
Right?
All right.
Okay.
Wanna watch the World Series?
Come on in, pal.
This could be a big moment for you.
Wanna watch a baseball game?
You wanna watch baseball?
Just raise that hand up.
Just raise the hand up.
-What do you say?
-INMATE: I gave it all to her.
Sorry.
Bancini, old horse.
What do you say?
You wanna watch the ball game on TV? Huh?
Wanna watch the ball game?
Baseball? World Series?
-What do you say, pal?
-I'm tired.
You're tired?
Just raise your hand up, Bancini.
Watch the ball game, huh?
-I'm tired. Awfully tired.
-Okay. All right.
What about you, pal?
All we need's one vote. Just one vote.
Just your one vote. That's all we need.
Just raise your hand up, and your
buddies can watch the baseball game on…
General, you remember, don't you?
October, the banner, the stars.
[SINGING "THE STAR-SPANGLED BANNER"]
The World Series.
Raise your hand up, Gen…
[SINGING "THE STAR-SPANGLED BANNER"]
McMURPHY: Just raise your hand up.
What about you pal, huh?
Wanna watch the ball game?
Wanna watch the ball game, huh?
Just one vote. Just raise your…
Gentlemen, the meeting is adjourned.
For chrissake, isn't there
one of you fucking maniacs
-that knows what I'm talking about?
-Mr. McMurphy?
Huh?
The meeting is adjourned.
Just wait a minute. Just one minute?
You can bring the
subject up again tomorrow.
All right, Chief
you're our last chance. What do you say?
Huh? Just raise your hand up.
That's all we need from you today, Chief.
Just raise your hand up one time.
Show her that you can do it.
Just show her that you can still do it.
Just raise your hand up.
All the guys have got them up.
Just raise your hand up, Chief.
Will you? Huh?
[SIGHS]
Come on, there's gotta be one guy
in here that's not a total fucking nut.
Mac?
Chief. The Chief.
[SCREAMS]
Chief! Nurse Ratched!
Nurse Ratched, look.
Look. The Chief put his hand up.
The Chief put his hand up.
Look, he voted.
Would you please turn… Would
you please turn the television set on?
The Chief has got his
hand up, right there.
The Chief voted. Now, will you
please turn the television set on?
RATCHED: Mr. McMurphy
the meeting was adjourned,
and the vote was closed.
But the vote was 10-to-8.
The Chief, he's got his hand up. Look.
No, Mr. McMurphy.
When the meeting was
adjourned, the vote was 9-to-9.
Ah, come on, you're not gonna say
that now. You're not gonna say that now.
You're gonna pull that shit now, when…
The Chief just voted. It was 10-to-9.
I want that television set turned on!
Right now!
[ORDERLY SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MILLER: Mr. Cheswick.
Come on. Come on.
-CHESWICK: I wanna watch television.
-MILLER: No, you have a work assignment.
[CHATTERING]
-Koufax.
-INMATE: Where's my sponge?
McMURPHY: Koufax kicks. He delivers.
It's up the middle, it's a base hit.
Richardson's rounding first, going for
second.
The ball's in to deep right center.
Davidson over in the corner.
Here comes the throw.
Richardson around the dirt.
Slides, he's in there! A double!
He's in there, Martini!
Richardson, he's on second base.
Koufax is in big fucking trouble.
Big trouble, baby.
All right, here's Tresh.
He's the next batter.
Tresh looks in. Koufax…
Koufax gets the sign from Roseboro.
He kicks once, he pumps.
It's a strike. Koufax's curve ball is
snapping off like a fucking firecracker.
Here he comes with the next pitch.
Tresh swings.
It's a long fly ball to deep left center!
[YELLING]
-It's going! It's gone!
-RATCHED: Mr. Washington,
and Mr. Warren, please see
that the men are doing their work.
[CHATTERING]
Somebody get me a
fucking wiener before I die.
Koufax looks down. Looking at the great
Mickey Mantle now. Here comes the pitch.
Mantle swings. It's a fucking home run!
Gentlemen, stop this.
Stop this immediately.
[YELLING]
Do you like it here?
Well, that fucking nurse, man.
What do you mean, sir?
She, uh…
She ain't honest.
Oh, now, look.
Miss Ratched's one of the finest
nurses we've got in this institution.
[McMURPHY LAUGHS]
Well, I don't wanna break
up the meeting or nothing,
but she's something
of a cunt, ain't she, Doc?
How do you mean that?
She likes a rigged game.
You know what I mean?
Well, you know, I've, uh,
been observing you here now,
for the last four weeks,
and I don't see any
evidence of mental illness at all.
I think that you've been
trying to put us on all this time.
You know, what do you want me to do?
You know.
[TAPPING]
You know what I mean? Is that it?
Is that crazy enough for you?
Want me to take a shit on the floor?
Hmm. Christ.
Have you ever heard the old saying,
"A rolling stone gathers no moss"?
Yeah.
Does that mean something to you?
Uh…
It's the same as "Don't wash
your dirty underwear in public."
I'm not sure I understand what you mean.
I'm smarter than him, ain't I?
[McMURPHY LAUGHS]
Well, that sort of has
always meant is, uh
it's hard for something to
grow on something that's moving.
How did you feel about
what happened yesterday?
Well, you wanna kill.
You know what I mean?
[LAUGHING]
[McMURPHY CLEARS THROAT]
Do you gentlemen have any more questions?
MAN: No, not at the moment.
I don't have any more,
but, uh, perhaps you do.
Do you have a question, McMurphy?
Where do you suppose she lives?
[INMATES PLAYING MUSIC]
Chief, come on with me.
Come on.
We'll show these guys who's nuts.
Huh?
All right, wait. Stand right here.
[HORN HONKS]
All right. Grab the fence.
Grab the fence here.
Right here, Chief. Strong.
Strong, like this, here.
That's it. All right. Okay. Up.
That's it. All right, you got it?
You do. This one. Here. All right, push.
[GRUNTING]
WARREN: Come on, Bob.
INMATE: Where you going?
McMURPHY: Don't breathe on me, Club.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
WARREN: Come on, you guys.
Get the lead out, huh?
Hey, what the hell's going on here?
Hey, wait a minute. Aah!
Hold it.
-See how easy it is?
-INMATES: Oh! Whoa!
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
McMURPHY: Boys
this here is Candy.
Candy, this is the boys.
Hi.
-Hi.
-ALL: Oh!
You all crazies?
[CANDY LAUGHING]
McMURPHY: Let's go. Down here.
-Isn't this wonderful?
-Right down here.
No problem.
Huh?
Right here. Come on.
Come on, we don't wanna
be late for our first day out.
[McMURPHY LAUGHING]
Hello.
Come on, will youse?
What are you standing around for here?
Get onboard. Give them these, Candy.
MAN: Hey, wait a minute.
What the heck is going on here?
-What are you doing on this boat?
-We're going fishing.
No, you're not going fishing.
Not on this boat.
You're not going fishing on this boat.
Oh, yeah, on this boat.
Uh, ask Captain Block.
-Captain Block?
-Captain Block. Yes, that's right.
Who are you?
Uh, we're from the, uh,
state mental institution.
Uh…
This is Dr. Cheswick,
Dr. Taber, Dr. Fredrickson
Dr. Scanlon. The famous Dr. Scanlon.
Mr. Harding, Dr. Bibbit
Dr. Martini, and, uh, Dr. Sefelt.
-How about you? Who are you?
-Oh. I'm Dr. McMurphy. R.P. McMurphy.
Wait, wait, wait one second.
You don't understand.
We chartered the boat,
we're going to go fishing,
and, uh, that's all there is to it.
You better quit on this. They'll
throw you in the can again, you know.
No, they won't. We're nuts.
[LAUGHS]
They'll just take us back
to the feeb farm, see?
Von Sefelt, get the stern line.
-Tabes, you're at the bow.
-SEFELT: This one?
That one. The one at your feet.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Get back on. Jesus.
[McMURPHY LAUGHS]
Tabes.
Cheswick.
Come here, quick.
Aye, aye, sir. I mean, yes, Mac.
Take it easy, Charlie.
You ever driven one of these things?
-Driven one of…
-Yeah.
-No, Mac. I… I…
-Well, it's a lot of fun.
-Lot of fun.
-Come on over here.
Put your hands on the wheel.
-Put your hands on.
-CHESWICK: I never did this.
Put your hands on the wheel
so you don't fall down. All right.
Just hold it steady
right there, like that.
-Steady?
-Steady, yeah.
Now just go straight.
-Straight as an arrow, Charlie.
-Straight, Mac?
-Just straight. That's right.
-But, Mac…
Mac, this thing ain't too steady, Mac.
Mac!
-Mac. Where are we going, Mac?
-McMURPHY: Straight. Just go on.
Oh.
This is the bait.
-Little fishes.
-MARTINI: Dead fishes.
That's right.
Now, what are we gonna
do with these little fishes?
-Catch big fishes.
-That's right. That's right, Mr. Martini.
And hooks.
Hooks.
Now, hold on to your hooks
because here are the fishes.
Tabes.
Get a fish here. There, for you, Martini.
All right, now we each
one of us has got a fish.
What are you laughing at, Martini?
You're not an idiot, huh?
You're not a goddamn loony now,
boy, you're a fisherman. Ha-ha-ha.
-Yes. Yes.
-Huh? Now, take your bottom hook.
-You got it?
-MARTINI: Yes.
You take it,
and you push it all the way through.
Like that.
Wait a second.
Get it through the eyes. Here.
-Right through here.
-MARTINI: In his eye?
McMURPHY: Don't worry about it.
He's dead, Martini.
Jesus Christ, just put it
through his eyeball here.
That's it.
Crunch it right through.
All right. Now you got it, see?
Now, you just pull that baby through.
You see what I mean?
And you wrap it around.
You pull this so it's a little loop.
-That's very good.
-MARTINI: Aah!
McMURPHY: That's very
good, Mr. Fredrickson.
Very good eye work. Good eye work.
That little devil's gonna not even
feel the sting, is he, boy? Huh?
That son of a gun is gonna bite
on you, is he? Let me see that face.
You… You, um… Got…
Got… Got beautiful hair.
Thank you.
McMURPHY: You
gotta pull it tight like this.
And you… You, um, got… [STUTTERING]
Beautiful eyes.
Thank you. Heh-heh.
Billy, what's the matter?
Fishing don't grab you?
[STUTTERING]
Yeah… Yeah… They… They… They do.
McMURPHY: Now, come
on with me, over here.
I'm gonna give each and
every one of youse a rod.
[LAUGHING]
All right. Here are your poles.
[HUMMING]
[SINGING "I'M POPEYE THE SAILOR MAN"]
Now, just keep watching the tip here.
If you get a strike, let me know.
Understand?
Come on, Candy. Just keep fishing, guys.
Don't call me unless you
get something really big
you can't handle yourselves.
Keep on fishing.
That's right.
[McMURPHY LAUGHING]
Mac?
Hey! Where is everybody?
Hey. Hey!
Cheswick! Goddamn it, I told
you to steer that boat straight.
I tried to.
TABER: Fish!
Fish! Help, help!
Goddamn it, he's got a fish. Hold it!
Wait a minute, Tabes. I got it.
Cheswick, get the fuck back up there!
Get up there and drive!
-Fish!
-I got it, Tabes.
Get up, Tabes, I'll get it for you.
Son of a bitch, he's going over here!
Get up, Tabes!
I got it.
I got it. Give it to me.
Hey, Harding, I'm
the skipper of this boat.
HARDING: Ah, shut up.
Well, he said to go
straight out as an arrow.
You're not going
straight, you're kind of…
I'm going straight enough.
Now, Cheesy, stop it.
-It's my duty.
-Cheesy, stop it.
-No!
-Don't you…
CHESWICK: No, you son of a bitch.
All right, Martini.
All right, take him over. Take him over.
That's it. Now play them, boys.
[LAUGHING]
You son of a bitches.
CHESWICK: Keep it straight.
Come back this way.
McMURPHY: Home safe and sound.
Didn't lose a nut.
Beach bowling, you know what I mean?
[LAUGHING]
SEFELT: We caught it, look.
McMURPHY: They're
gonna be trolling this place,
for six months looking for dead bodies.
Whoo!
We caught it. Look.
I think he's dangerous.
He's not crazy, but he's dangerous.
-You don't think he's crazy?
-No, he's not crazy.
Dr. Songee?
I don't think he's overly psychotic,
but I still think he's quite sick.
-Do you think he's dangerous?
-Absolutely so.
Well, John, what do
you wanna do with him?
Well, I think we've had our turn.
I'd like to send him back to
the, uh, work farm, frankly.
MAN: is there anybody
that you have on your staff…
…that could relate to him?
Maybe understand him?
Help him out with some of these problems?
Well, the funny thing is that the
person that he's the closest to
is the one he dislikes the most. Heh.
-MAN: Well, sure.
-That's you, Mildred.
Well, gentlemen, in my opinion,
if we send him back to Pendleton,
or we send him up to Disturbed
it's just one more way of passing
on our problem to somebody else.
You know we don't like to do that.
So I'd like to keep him on the ward.
I think we can help him.
All right, huh? Chief. Chief, come on.
Come with me, huh? All right.
Now, Chief, this is the spot.
Right there is the spot. Remember?
Raise the hands, in the basket.
That's it. Raise the hands up.
All right. Let's have a little ball
from you nuts in here. Here we go.
All right. Let's play some ball, nuts.
Let's make some moves.
Hey, Mac, Mac. Time, time, time.
You got six men on the court.
All right. Harding, out of the ball game.
Hey, why me?
Because I'm the coach.
I'll put you in later.
Oh, no, no. I don't trust you.
[LAUGHING]
Ma… Mac, I'll go.
McMURPHY: Okay, good boy, Billy.
I'll put you in in a minute, all right?
All right, let's play ball.
Harding, break over.
All right, Martini, get it back.
I'm in the open. What are you doing?
You threw the damn ball into the fence!
Christ Almighty, you
threw the ball into the fence!
There's nobody there. We're playing ball.
All right, come on, get in the game.
Defense, nobody's doing nothing here.
-For chrissake.
-HARDING: Hey, Mac, I'm open. I'm open.
All right, Harding, give it back.
Back to me, Harding. Here.
I'm open.
Harding, will you give me the ball?
-Stop dribbling the goddamn ball.
-HARDING: I got it.
McMURPHY: Harding, over here.
Oh, for chrissake, I'm standing…
-HARDING: You were covered.
-I was open.
Just give me the ball.
They're making all over the…
I was open. Give me the ball.
-You were covered, Mac.
-I wasn't covered. Somebody get back.
-Give it to me. Give it to me.
-MAN 1: All right?
-MAN 2: Ow!
-MAN 3: Yeah, we're going.
McMURPHY: Chief. Attababy, put it in.
[CHEERING]
McMURPHY: Get down there.
-MAN 4: Defense.
-MAN 5: Hey!
[MAN WHISTLES]
Get down there, Chief.
All right, all right.
-HARDING: Pick up somebody over there!
-McMURPHY: Get this side.
Get around, Chief.
[YELLING]
McMURPHY: No, no, no.
Get down there, Chief.
The ball's in play. Ball's in play.
-WASHINGTON: That's bullshit.
-Ball's in play.
Oh, fuck that shit. You got to be crazy.
MILLER: Man, that doesn't go.
The ball ain't in play.
-MAN 6: Chief.
-MAN 7: Go on, Chief.
MAN 8: Put it in.
Chief, all right! That was great!
[CHEERING]
What a ball club.
[CHATTERING]
WASHINGTON: McMurphy, get off the side.
-Come on, move it, man.
-Hey, damn it.
Go ahead. Come on. Come on.
There's no one looking.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Go ahead.
I'll be seeing you on the outside.
You know what I mean?
By the time you get out of here
you'll be too old to even get it up.
Sixty-eight days, buddy.
Sixty-eight days.
What the fuck you talking about, 68 days?
That's in jail, sucker.
You still don't know
where you're at, do you?
-Yeah, where am I at, Washington?
-With us, baby, you're with us.
And you're gonna stay
with us until we let you go.
Do you want to say something
to the group, Mr. McMurphy?
Well, ahem, yeah.
I'd like to know why none of
the guys never told me that you
Miss Ratched,
and the doctors could keep me here till
you're good and ready to turn me loose.
-That's what I'd like to know.
-Well, fine, Randall. That's a good start.
Would anyone care to answer Mr. McMurphy?
Answer what?
You heard me, Harding.
You let me go on hassling
Nurse Ratched here
knowing how much I had to
lose and you never told me nothing.
Now, Mac, wait a minute.
Wait a minute, I didn't know
anything about how much…
-Shit. Fuck.
-HARDING: Wait a minute. No, listen.
Now, look. I'm voluntary here, see?
I'm not committed.
I don't have to stay here.
I mean, I can go home any time I want.
You can go home any time you want?
-That's it.
-You're bullshitting me.
He's bullshitting me, right?
No, Randall, he's telling you the truth.
As a matter of fact, there are very
few men here who are committed.
There's Mr. Bromden, Mr. Taber
some of the chronics, and you.
-Cheswick?
-Hmm?
You're voluntary?
Mm-hm.
McMURPHY: Scanlon?
Billy, for chrissakes, you
must be committed, right?
No… No… No.
Oh. Oh, man.
You're just a young kid.
What are you doing here?
You ought to be out in a convertible
bird-dogging chicks and banging beaver.
What are you doing here, for chrissake?
[INMATES LAUGHING]
-What's so funny about that?
-BILLY: Well…
Jesus, I mean, you guys do nothing
but complain about how you can't
stand it in this place here, and then
you haven't got the guts to walk out?
I mean, what do you think you are,
for chrissake? Crazy or something?
Well, you're not. You're not.
You're no crazier than the average
asshole walking around on the streets.
And that's it.
Jesus Christ, I can't even believe it.
Those are very challenging
observations you made, Randall.
I'm sure some of the men
would like to comment.
Mr. Scanlon?
I wanna know why the dorm is
locked in the daytime and on weekends.
[SIGHS]
Yeah.
I would like to know about our cigarettes.
May I have my cigarettes,
please, Miss Ratched?
You sit down, Mr. Cheswick,
and wait your turn.
Go ahead, sit down.
To answer your question
about the dorm, Mr. Scanlon
you know very well
that if we left the door open, you'd
just go right back to bed after breakfast.
-Am I right?
-So what?
May I have my cigarettes,
please, Miss Ratched?
Forget the cigarettes, Cheswick.
Cigarettes are not important.
Sit down, will you?
For chrissake.
Cigarettes.
Remember, Mr. Scanlon,
we've discussed many times
that time spent in the company
of others is very therapeutic
while time spent brooding alone
only increases a feeling of separation.
You remember that, don't you?
Do you mean to say
it's sick to wanna be off by yourself?
CHESWICK: Miss Ratched?
Mr. Cheswick, you sit down.
-But I wanna know about…
-RATCHED: Sit down, Mr. Cheswick.
I wanna…
-Give him a cigarette, will you, Harding?
-It's my last one.
That's a fucking lie.
Why don't you give him a cigarette?
HARDING: Look, I'm not
running a charity ward, see?
Come on.
Look, I don't want his cigarettes,
and I don't want his or his or his,
or his or his or his or
his or his, or even yours.
Do you understand that?
I want my cigarettes, Miss Ratched.
I want my cigarettes.
I want mine, Miss Ratched.
What gives you the damn right
to keep our cigarettes
piled up on your desk,
and to squeeze out a pack
only when you feel like it, huh?
-Miss Ratched.
-Mr… Mr. Harding.
[FREDRICKSON LAUGHING]
Oh, I'm sorry.
-RATCHED: You surprise me.
-No, well, I lost my head. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean… I'm
really very sorry. I just forgot.
I didn't mean… I'm really very sorry.
Just forgot.
-It's all right.
-HARDING: Thank you.
CHESWICK: Miss Ratched!
-Yes, Mr. Cheswick?
-I asked you a question.
I heard your question, Mr. Cheswick,
and I will answer your question
as soon as you've calmed down.
Okay.
Are you calm, Mr. Cheswick?
-I'm calm.
-Good.
Now, as you all know
Mr. McMurphy has been running a
small gambling casino in our tub room.
Now, most of you lost all your
cigarettes to Mr. McMurphy
not to mention a tidy sum
of money to Mr. McMurphy.
And that's why
your tub-room privileges
have been suspended,
and your cigarettes have been rationed.
Mr. Martini?
How we gonna win our money back?
[LAUGHING]
You're not going to win
your money back, Mr. Martini.
That's all over.
If you had obeyed the
rules in the first place
-you wouldn't have lost your money.
-TABER: Oh!
[SCREAMING]
Sit down, gentlemen. Sit down, gentlemen.
-Sit down. Sit down.
-TABER: Oh! Oh!
Oh, God. Oh, my God.
Rules?
Piss on your fucking rules, Miss Ratched.
Sit down, will you, Cheswick?
I want you to know something
here and now, Miss Ratched.
I ain't no little kid.
I ain't no little kid…
RATCHED: You sit down.
…where you're gonna have
cigarettes kept from me like cookies…
…and I want something done!
Ain't that right, Mac?
-That's right. Now, will you sit down?
-I won't! I won't! I want something done!
-McMURPHY: Sit down.
-I want something done!
-RATCHED: Mr. Washington!
CHESWICK: I want something done!
I want something done!
-Here. Here.
-CHESWICK: I want something done!
McMURPHY: Goddamn it, Cheswick, here.
Hey, calm down.
Why don't you leave him alone, Washington?
He's gonna be all right.
[GRUNTING AND YELLING]
Emergency 34-B, 34-B.
WASHINGTON: I'm gonna
break your fucking back.
Punk-ass motherfucker.
[McMURPHY GRUNTING]
WASHINGTON: Forget it.
It's all over, McMurphy.
Warren! Warren!
[YELLING]
Warren.
[INMATE SCREAMS]
Would you move, please?
We need this chair.
Just move right over there, okay.
I see we have Mr. Bromden back.
Yeah, okay.
MAN 1: Don't bother anyone.
-ORDERLY: Mr. McMurphy.
-NURSE: Mr. McMurphy.
-How do you do, Mr. McMurphy?
-McMURPHY: I do real fine.
I know you didn't do anything wrong.
Just sit down.
We're not going to hurt you.
Sit down, right here. That's it.
Nurse, this is Mr. Cheswick.
He's a little upset.
Okay, fine. Thank you very much.
-You'll be okay, Mr. Cheswick.
-MAN 2: Yes.
Would you keep an eye on these three?
[INMATE GRUNTING]
[INMATE MUTTERING]
Would you please take these, gentlemen?
McMURPHY: He can't hear nothing.
NURSE: That's it.
[CHESWICK GASPS]
McMURPHY: Calm down, Ches, will you?
Mr. Cheswick, would you please follow me?
[SOBS]
Mr. Cheswick?
[SOBBING]
CHESWICK: Mac. Mac.
-No!
-ORDERLY: Nobody's gonna hurt you.
-It'll be all right, Ches.
No!
You're all right.
No one's gonna hurt you.
No, leave me alone.
-ORDERLY: Make it easy on yourself.
-CHESWICK: No. Mac. Mac.
[CHESWICK SOBBING]
Come on. Come on, now. Come on.
-Come on.
-No. I didn't do nothing.
Mac. No!
-Come on.
-I won't go. I don't wanna go. I won't go.
[SCREAMING]
Jesus Christ.
All right, then.
Want some gum?
Thank you.
Ah, Juicy Fruit.
Well, you sly son of a bitch, Chief. Ha!
-Can you hear me too?
-Yeah, you bet.
Well, I'll be goddamned, Chief.
And they all… They all
think you're deaf and dumb.
Jesus Christ.
[LAUGHS]
You fooled them, Chief.
You fooled them.
You fooled them all. Goddamn.
What are we doing in here, Chief? Huh?
What's us two guys
doing in this fucking place?
[INMATE MUTTERING]
[INMATE SHOUTING]
Let's get out of here.
Out.
-Canada?
-Canada.
We'll be there before these son
of a bitches know what hit them.
Listen to Randall on this one.
-Mr. McMurphy?
-Huh?
NURSE: Please follow me.
You and me, Chief.
Take a cigarette break, boys. Easy.
I'll be fine, thank you. Seated.
Ah.
-Would you sit up, please?
-Sure. Love to.
Attaboy.
There might be a little fluid in them
boots, you know what I mean, boys?
Just a little leak.
A light shine, boys,
and send the specimen to Nurse Ratched.
[LAUGHING]
Huh?
-NURSE: All right, out with your gum.
-Hmm?
NURSE: Out with your gum.
MAN: Okay, this won't hurt,
and it'll be over in just a moment.
Uh-huh.
-What's that?
-NURSE: Conductant.
A little dab will do you.
Ain't that right, Mr. Jackson?
[McMURPHY CHUCKLING]
NURSE: Open your mouth.
-What's that?
-NURSE: Keep you from biting your tongue.
Now just bite down on it.
That's right. Just bite down.
Now, bite down on it.
[COUGHING]
-Are you ready?
-NURSE: Ready.
[McMURPHY SINGING]
MAN: Here we go.
[GRUNTING]
[CHOKING]
RATCHED: Now, one big breath.
[ALL INHALING AND EXHALING]
Very good.
Gentlemen, I'd like to begin today.
It shouldn't take too long.
Jim, it's been brought to my attention
that you've been giving
Mr. Fredrickson your medication.
Is that true?
SEFELT: No, ma'am.
RATCHED: Jim
are you giving your
medication to Mr. Fredrickson,
or are you not?
[LAUGHING]
How about it, you creeps,
you lunatics, mental defectives.
Let's hear it for Bullgoose Randall,
back in action. Nice shirt, Cheseroo.
[LAUGHING]
McMURPHY: Look at the faces on you.
Look at you.
The feebs' brigade, you ding-a-lings.
The mental defective league in formation.
[LAUGHING]
How are you, Nurse Ratched?
I'm happy to be back.
-We're happy to have you back, Randall.
-Thank you.
Would you like to rest today, or
would you like to join the group?
Uh… Oh, I'd love to join the group.
I'd like…
I'm proud to join the group, Mildred.
Ahem.
-How… How's it going, Mac?
-Perfect, Billy boy. Absolutely perfect.
They was giving me 10,000 watts
a day, you know, and I'm hot to trot.
Next woman takes me on is
gonna light up like a pinball machine,
and pay off in silver dollars.
[LAUGHING]
Well, that's an amusing thought, Randall,
but when you came
in, we were talking to Jim.
He has a problem with his medication,
and we'd like to get back to that.
Oh, I don't mind at all, Nurse Ratched.
I'm, uh, gentle as a puppy dog and…
Please proceed. Thank you.
MAN [ON TV]: The administration
was hopeful but cautious Friday
in its reaction to a possible
opening of the Berlin Wall
during the upcoming Christmas holiday.
Good night, gentlemen.
See you in the morning.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON TV]
MAN [ON TV]: Authorities in Birmingham,
Alabama have arrested three men
in connection with a
church bombing in the city
which killed three Negro children
while they were attending services.
The three men, R.E.
Chambliss, Charles Cagle and John Hall
were arrested Sunday and are
being held in custody in Alabama
by state police on charges of
illegal possession of dynamite.
Police say the men will be held
on this misdemeanor charge
pending full investigation…
[DIALING PHONE]
Yeah, baby, it's Mac.
It's on tonight.
Don't worry about it. Get a car.
I don't give a shit, baby.
Steal it if you have to.
I gotta go. I gotta go.
Uh, don't forget to bring some booze.
Right.
Bye.
[SNORING]
[GASPING]
Chief.
Chief, I can't take it no more.
I gotta get out of here.
I can't. I just can't.
It's easier than you think, Chief.
For you, maybe.
You're a lot bigger than me.
[LAUGHS]
Why, Chief, you're about as
big as a goddamn tree trunk.
My papa's real big.
He did like he pleased.
That's why everybody worked on him.
The last time I seen my father he
was blind in the cedars from drinking.
And every time he put
the bottle to his mouth
he don't suck out of it.
It sucks out of him until he'd shrunk,
so wrinkled and yellow,
even the dogs don't know him.
Killed him, huh?
I'm not saying they killed him.
They just worked on him,
the way they're working on you.
[HORN HONKS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
There they are, Chief.
There they are. They're here.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Hey. Hey. Over here. That's it.
McMurphy, stop all this holy-roller shit,
and get your ass back in bed.
You understand?
Well, uh, my prayers have
been answered, Turkle.
Come on and see.
You'd take, uh, $20
to get down on your knees
and pray, wouldn't you, Turkle?
No, it don't send me, don't send me.
-It don't?
-Don't do nothing to me, no.
Well, you know there'll be more.
I mean, uh, they'll be bringing a
couple of bottles with them, and, uh…
TURKLE: You're getting closer, brother.
You're getting closer,
but they gonna be sharing
more than just bottles, ain't they?
-You know what I mean?
-Yeah.
-I know what you mean.
-You understand?
Yeah, I understand what you mean.
-Anything you say, Turkle.
-I'm on my knees, brother.
-Yeah, all right, all right.
-I'm on my knees.
-All right.
-Let them in.
[TURKLE LAUGHS]
-McMURPHY: Let me give you a hand here.
-TURKLE: I appreciate that.
-WOMEN: Hi.
-McMURPHY: Ladies.
Oh, thank you. I believe this
is your department, Mr. Turkle.
-ROSE: Hi, how you doing?
-Hi, Rose, how you doing?
-Love to give her a hand.
-ROSE: Ow!
[LAUGHING]
-TURKLE: Keep it down.
-McMURPHY: Shh.
-ROSE: I split my pants.
-TURKLE: Keep it down.
McMURPHY: Give it to me.
Give it all to me.
You got to keep it down.
-Hi.
-McMURPHY: Mm.
ROSE: This looks like my high school.
[LAUGHING]
McMURPHY: Shh.
Oh, hey, I take that.
-The barber chair.
-TURKLE: You may have it.
ROSE: It is mine, mine.
You can have it. You can have it, honey.
[LAUGHING]
Ooh.
-Take a load of these tubs.
-CANDY: Real nice place you got here, Mac.
Ooh. Ooh.
-Hey, can I take a bath?
-Sure, you can take a bath. Sure.
Just don't drown your pretty little self.
You know, um
Rose was married to a
maniac once, up in Beaverton.
Oh, really, miss?
What seemed to be the problem?
Oh, nothing, he used to put
frogs in my bra all the time.
[LAUGHING AND CHATTERING]
Very interesting.
-Uh, Mr. Turkle.
-Uh-huh?
Uh, Rose is very interested in
hospitals and hospital facilities.
-I am?
-Yes. Oh, yes, you are.
-I'm going to take Candy…
-Where you going?
Uh, I'm gonna take Candy for a stroll.
I got you, I got you.
-But just don't make too much noise.
-Not a peep, not a peep.
Peep.
-All right.
-McMURPHY: Yes, that's right.
Now, you come over
here, baby, right over here.
-ROSE: Candy?
-Don't worry about Candy, honey.
Sit down and relax. Now…
[CANDY SINGING "ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT"]
McMURPHY [OVER PA]: Wake up, boys.
Wake up.
It's medication time.
Medication time.
The nighttime spirits are here.
It's Randall to say goodbye,
and get you high, and
nighttime angel, Candy. Oh, yes.
That's right, Mr. Martini,
there is an Easter bunny.
[SINGING "ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT"]
[CANDY LAUGHING]
Round the side, boys. Join Mr. McMurphy
in the executive lounge, please.
Round the side.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
McMURPHY: It's gonna be so great.
You like a nip, don't you, Charles?
No trouble at all.
It's Billy the Club of the
fabulous and fantastic 14…
-TURKLE: What the hell's going on?
-McMURPHY: Mr. Turkle.
Ain't this a bitch.
McMurphy, what you trying to do?
Get my ass really fired, man?
Come on, get your ass out of here.
Ain't this a… Come on.
We're just having a party.
Party, my ass. This ain't no
nightclub, this is a hospital.
Man, this is my fucking job.
I don't give a damn,
this is my fucking job.
[FOOTSTEPS]
Oh, shit. The supervisor.
Come on, get your asses back in there.
Come on. Come on there.
Where is that no-talking son of a bitch?
Is he in there? Good. Come on.
Mr. Turkle?
[WHISPERING]
McMURPHY: Where the hell is he?
Why doesn't he answer?
MAN: He's jerking off somewhere.
[LAUGHING]
TURKLE: Ain't nobody jerking
off nowhere, motherfucker.
McMURPHY: Turkle, what
the fuck are you doing here?
Go out there and talk to her.
TURKLE: Doing the same fucking
thing you're doing in here, hiding.
[RUSTLING]
Yes, ma'am?
-Everything all right, Mr. Turkle?
-Oh, everything is just fine, ma'am.
Just fine. Just fine.
[CLATTERING]
[CRASHING]
[CHUCKLES]
Who's there?
-Ain't nobody in there.
-Please open that door.
CANDY: Oh. Heh-heh-heh.
I'm sorry. Heh-heh-heh.
Heh.
I'm sorry, ma'am, but you know, a
man gets awful lonesome at night.
You understand what I mean, don't you?
You understand? I'm sure you understand.
I want that woman off
this ward immediately.
Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am.
[CLATTERING]
[YELLING]
-TURKLE: Jesus.
-INMATE: Mr. Turkle, is she gone?
TURKLE: Shit, yeah,
she's gone, and so am I.
Get your behinds out
of here and back to bed.
Go ahead, move it, move it. Move it.
-INMATE: I knew we were in trouble.
-TURKLE: Let's go.
You and your teddy-bear ass.
Move them on out of here.
Come on, come on.
-Candy?
-Come on, Candy.
Jesus Christ.
McMURPHY: Mr. Turkle, I'm really sorry.
Motherfuckers fucking with my job.
-Get out.
-McMURPHY: I'm really sorry.
What are you…
What the fuck… Get out of here.
Please get out, this is my job.
You fucking it up. You understand?
Get out.
Get out of here, you slim motherfucker.
Fuck it.
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
Good night, good night,
don't let the cooties bite.
There.
Make you get up and dance. Okay?
Right out of the Shock Department.
I got it from…
I got it from Ratched's charts.
Right. There you go, there you go.
Easy now. Don't take it all at once.
Let's try a little over here.
There you go.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
McMURPHY: Let's go.
I'll have to be the one, Chief.
HARDING: Hey, Mac, what's going on? Huh?
McMURPHY: Well, Dale, Lord
Randall is stepping down one.
Fredrickson.
Jimmy.
CHESWICK: You gonna
say goodbye to me, Mac?
Sure, I'm gonna say
goodbye to you, Charles.
-Hey, Mac? Mac?
-Yeah?
Thank you, Mac. Thank you.
-I'll never forget you.
-Settle down, Charles, all right?
Hey, Billy, what's wrong?
Billy, for chrissake…
What's the matter?
I'm… I'm gonna… Gonna
miss you very, very
very, very much, Mac.
Well, why don't you come with us, then?
Think… Think I don't want to?
-So come on, then, let's go.
-Well… Well, it's not… Not that easy.
I'm not… Not… Not ready yet.
Tell you what we'll do.
When I get to Canada,
I'll write you a postcard,
and I'll put my address on it.
That way when you are
ready, you'll know where to go.
What do you say?
Yeah.
Ma… Mac? Is she… She going with you?
Candy?
Yeah, she'll be there when you get there.
She's going with us.
Are you gonna… Gonna marry her?
No. No, we're just good friends. Why?
[GASPS]
[STUTTERING]
No… No… Nothing.
No… No… Don't "nothing" me, all right?
What is it?
Well, it's too… Too late.
You want a date with her?
BILLY: No.
Jesus, I must be crazy to
be in a loony bin like this.
Date, huh?
Well, it'll have to be a
fast date, I'll tell you that.
No… No… Not now.
Not now?
When, then?
Um… Um… [STUTTERING]
When I have a free weekend.
You busy right now, are you?
You got something to do right now?
-You got something to do?
-Uh, no… No.
Good, then don't talk to me about
when you're ready. Yeah, yeah.
-No. No.
-Ready and everything like that.
Candy, come here a minute.
Yes, yes, yes. Candy, I want
you to meet the famous Billy.
Go get him, will you?
Go get him. Get him out of there.
I want you to get ahold of Billy…
All you gotta do is
this one little thing.
-The kid's cute, isn't he? Huh?
-CANDY: Yeah.
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
Think of me the whole time.
There he is. Billy the Club.
Billy, I got $25
that says you are gonna
burn this woman down.
[LAUGHING]
Oh, boy.
McMURPHY: Candy, baby…
I love you.
Hurl the ringer.
[CANDY LAUGHS]
Hey, easy. Back. Back. Come on.
That's enough.
No, no, no, I'll show
you some card tricks.
You ain't seen the Spanish deck yet.
That's 40 percent more torture.
[LAUGHING]
Mr. Scanlon, I'm gonna present you
with this fine deck of cards for playing.
This ain't gonna take long,
Rose, you know what I mean?
[CHATTERING]
When we get to Canada…
[CHUCKLES]
[HORN HONKING]
[CLATTERING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
Out of sight, man. Out of sight.
[GATE CLOSES]
WASHINGTON: Morning, Miss Ratched.
-MILLER: Morning.
-WARREN: Good morning.
Mr. Warren, close the
window and lock the screen.
Right.
[LAUGHS NERVOUSLY]
Mr. Miller, show this woman
the way out of the hospital.
Gladly.
-Come on, lady, let's go.
-ROSE: Oh…
-You're going home.
-Where?
Let her go, Scanlon. You're going home.
-Mr. Washington?
-Yes, Miss Ratched.
-Make sure no one is missing.
-Will do.
-Mac?
-WASHINGTON: Come on, Scanlon, move.
-Everybody out of here.
-WARREN: Come on, move it out.
WASHINGTON: Come on, move it.
Martini, get your butt up. Come on, up.
Colonel, get your dead ass up there.
What the hell's going on here?
Come on, move out.
[CLATTERING]
[GRUNTING]
-WASHINGTON: Move it out of there.
-Miss Ratched?
WASHINGTON: Okay, Martini, let's go.
Move it.
-WARREN: Fredrickson, what you doing?
-Where you going? Back out here.
-WARREN: Let's go. Go on, let's go.
-What the hell is that?
Taber, get up. Come on. I said, get up.
Move it back there. McMurphy, get your
ass over here, and bring Dracula with you.
-Move it.
-WARREN: Come on.
Let's go. Let's go.
WASHINGTON: Stay right there, Bancini.
-Miss Ratched?
-Yes?
Looks like Billy Bibbit's
the only one missing.
-Billy?
-Mm-hm.
-Thank you, Mr. Washington.
-Okay.
Did Billy Bibbit leave the
grounds of the hospital, gentlemen?
[INMATE BURPS]
I want an answer to my question.
Did he leave the grounds of the hospital?
[LAUGHING]
-Mr. Washington?
-Yes.
Miss Pilbow, check all the rooms.
-Mr. Warren?
-Yes.
You'll start with the tub room.
Mr. Martini?
May I have my cap, please?
My cap. My cap. There.
Thank you.
Miss Ratched.
[LAUGHS]
[INMATES CLAPPING AND LAUGHING]
Miss Ratched…
[LAUGHING]
Um, I can explain everything.
Please do, Billy.
Explain everything.
Everything?
[INMATES LAUGHING]
Aren't you ashamed?
No, I'm not.
McMURPHY: Ail right.
[INMATES CLAPPING]
You know, Billy, what worries me
is how your mother's going to take this.
Um… Um, well, you… You don't have to
tell her, Miss Ratched.
I don't have to tell her?
Your mother and I are old friends.
You know that.
Um… Please do… Don't tell my m…
Don't you think you should have thought
of that before you took that woman
in that room?
No, no.
I… [STUTTERING]
I didn't.
You mean she dragged
you in there by force?
She… She…
[STUTTERING]
She… She did.
-Everybody did.
-Everybody? Who did?
You tell me who did.
M… M…
M… McMurphy.
Miss Rat… Miss Ratched, please don't
-tell my mother, please.
-Mr. Warren?
Would you see that the men
are washed and ready for the day?
Miss Ratched, please…
Please don't tell my mother.
-Mr. Washington?
-Yes?
-Put Billy in Dr. Spivey's office.
-No, no. No.
-Stay with him till the doctor arrives.
-No, no, no.
No, no. No.
-Move it. Come on, Martini, get on.
-BILLY: No.
No! No! No!
That way, please. Please, gentlemen. Huh?
Let's go, come on.
Come on, you guys. What is this?
Let's go.
Hey, what the hell is that?
McMurphy, what the hell are you doing?
Aah!
RATCHED [OVER PA]: Washington
to the Day Room. Immediately.
WASHINGTON: Put down
those keys and nobody gets hurt.
Move away from the window
and take that damn Chief with you.
[PILBOW SCREAMS]
ROSE: Mac?
Come on, let's go.
Let me through. Let me through.
RATCHED: Oh.
SPIVEY: Out of the way, McMurphy.
-MILLER: Come on, clear it.
-Get these people out of here.
-Oh, Billy.
-MILLER: Will you guys clear the door?
RATCHED: Everybody out.
Out. Everybody out.
Come on, goddamn it. Get your ass…
Now calm down.
The best thing we can do is
go on with our daily routine.
All right?
CHESWICK: Mac. Don't.
Don't. Mac.
Mac. Don't. Mac. No.
Don't.
[RATCHED COUGHING]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
[SHUFFLING CARDS]
HARDING: And the bets are placed.
There's one for Tabes and
Cheesy and Martini and the dealer.
And a four to Tabes,
and a six and a nine,
-and a 10 to the dealer.
-MARTINI: A nine? Nine?
HARDING: What do you say, Tabes?
A dime apiece.
No? You stick.
-He sticks.
-Sticks with a four.
Chessy's going for the ride.
-What does that mean?
-He wants a hit.
He wants a hit. And a big queen.
I think you're busted.
Buggered, not busted.
-Turn them over.
-Buggered.
And weep.
-Hit me.
-Hit.
I think you're over.
I know you're over.
[SPEAKS CZECH]
That's a three.
RATCHED [OVER PA]: Mr. Sefelt?
Did everything go well?
That's very nice.
Now you feel better, don't you?
Yes, ma'am.
Deuce to the dealer.
Split them. Higher.
McMurphy is out.
McMurphy has escaped.
They were taking him through the tunnel.
He beat up two of the
attendants and escaped.
-McMurphy's upstairs.
-Oh, no, no, no.
Jim, I'm telling you,
McMurphy is upstairs,
and he's as meek as a Iamb.
Really? I mean, how do you know?
-Jack Dunphy told me.
-Jack Dunphy's full of shit.
-Ha.
-Right. Right.
[GATE CLOSES]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[CHATTERING]
ORDERLY: We got you.
There you go.
Mac.
They said you escaped.
I knew you wouldn't leave without me.
I was waiting for you.
Now we can make it, Mac.
I feel big as a damn mountain.
Oh, no.
I'm not going without you, Mac.
I wouldn't leave you here this way.
You're coming with me.
Let's go.
[LAUGHING]
[TABER YELLING]