(lion roars)
♪ They're writing songs of love ♪
(alarm clock rings)
♪ But not for me ♪
♪ A lucky star's above ♪
(alarm clock rings)
♪ With love to lead the way ♪
♪ I found more clouds of gray ♪
♪ Than any Russian play could guarantee ♪
♪ I was a fool to fall, and get that way ♪
♪ Hi-ho, alas, and also lack-a-day ♪
♪ Although I can't dismiss ♪
♪ The memory of her kiss ♪
♪ I guess he's not for me ♪
- [Fiona] Good morning, Mrs. Statons.
- Morning, madam.
- Thank you.
- [Gareth] Late, late!
At last.
♪ It all began so well, but what an end ♪
♪ This is the time a
fella needs a friend ♪
♪ When every happy plot
ends with a marriage knot ♪
♪ And there's no knot for me ♪
- Oh, fuck, fuck!
- Fuck!
- Oh, fuck!
(car engine creaks)
Fuck, right, we take yours.
- It only goes 40 miles an hour.
(car engine revs)
- What turnoff?
Better not be the B359.
- It's the B359.
- [Charles] Fuck it!
- [Scarlett] Fuck!
(horn blares)
- [Charles] Fuck.
(church bells ring)
(car tires screech)
- Come on.
- [Charles] Fuck!
- [Scarlett] Fuck.
- Come on.
- Fuck!
Fuckity fuck.
Bugger.
- [Lydia] Look at you, you look fine.
- [Bride] Is it twisted?
- What?
- Hello, you look lovely.
- [Bride] Hello, Charles!
(mid-tempo elegant music)
- There's a sort of
greatness to your lateness.
- Thanks, it's not achieved
without real suffering.
I am so, so sorry, Angus, inexcusable.
I'll be killing myself after the service,
if that's any consolation.
- Doesn't matter, Tom was standing by.
- Thanks, Tom, you're a saint.
A disastrous haircut.
- As long as you haven't
forgotten the rings?
- No.
Tsk, hate people being late.
("Wedding March" by Felix Mendelssohn)
Here we go.
- Oh, isn't she lovely?
- Scarlett, you're blind, she
looks like a big meringue.
- [Vicar] Dear friends, what
a joy it is to welcome you
to our church on this wonderful
day for Angus and Laura.
(slow organ music)
Before we start the service,
let us all join together
in the first hymn.
♪ And did those feet in ancient time ♪
♪ Walk upon England's mountain green ♪
♪ And was the holy lamb of God ♪
♪ On England's pleasant pastures seen ♪
♪ And did the countenance divine ♪
♪ Shine forth upon our clouded hills ♪
♪ And was Jerusalem builded here ♪
♪ Among those dark satanic mills ♪
- Scarlett.
- [Vicar] Dearly beloved, we
are gathered together here
in the sight of God and in
the face of this congregation
to join together this man and
this woman in holy matrimony.
Which is an honorable estate instituted
in the time of man's innocence.
- Back in a sec.
- Therefore if any man can show
any just cause or impediment
why they may not be
lawfully joined together
let him speak now or
forever hold his peace.
Do you promise to love her comfort her,
honor and keep her in
sickness and in health
and forsaking all others
keep thee only unto her
for as long as ye both shall live?
- I do.
- [Laura] To love and to cherish.
- [Vicar] Till death us do part.
- [Laura] Till death us do part.
- [Vicar] Thereto, I pledge thee my troth.
- And thereto, I pledge thee my troth.
- Do you have the ring?
With this ring, I thee wed.
- With this ring, I thee wed.
- [Vicar] With my body, I thee worship.
- With my body, I thee worship.
- [Vicar] And with all my
worldly goods, I do thee endow.
- [Angus] And with all my
worldly goods, I thee endow.
- [Charles] Mm.
- If I speak with the
tongues of men and of angels,
but have not love I am become
a sounding brass or a clanging cymbal.
- Good point.
♪ You know I can't smile without you ♪
♪ Can't smile without you ♪
♪ I can't laugh and I can't sing ♪
♪ I'm finding it hard to do anything ♪
♪ You see, I feel sad when
you're sad, I feel sad ♪
♪ I feel glad when you're glad ♪
♪ If you only knew what
I'm going through ♪
(joyful organ music)
- Great hat.
- Thanks, I bought it specially.
- [Photographer] You a hand, there
All right, get in position, please.
Thank you, smile.
- Splendid, I thought.
What did you think?
- I thought, splendid.
- Splendid, I thought.
- Scarlotta, fabulous dress!
Ecclesiastical purple and the pagan orange
symbolizing the magical
symbiosis in marriage
between heathen and Christian traditions?
- That's right.
- [Photographer] Lovely, and again.
(camera clicks)
- Any idea who the girl
in the black hat is?
- [Fiona] Name's Carrie.
- [Charles] Pretty.
- [Fiona] American.
- Interesting.
- Slut.
- Really?
- Used to work at Vogue,
lives in America now.
Only goes out with very glamorous people.
Quite out of your league.
- Well, that's a relief, thanks.
(guests cheer)
- See you there.
- Off you go, off you go!
- Right, reception.
- [Woman] Bye! Bye!
- Anyone else tread in a cowpat?
No, I thought not.
See you in a mo.
- Do you think I'd hate him as
much if he wasn't my brother?
(Gareth laughs)
- Don't want to blow chances for romance
by smelling of dung all the
way through the reception.
- [Fiona] Oh, God, I
never know what to say
in these wretched lineups.
- It's a cinch, give a big, warm hug
and say the bride looks pregnant.
- Or you could stick with tradition,
and go for you must be very proud.
- Heaven preserve us.
You must be very proud.
- Thank you.
- Hello.
- Hi, we've met at the ranch,
it's Richard, Richard Maples.
- Oh, yes.
- Bastard.
Hello, Bern.
- [Bern] Hello, Chuck.
- Two, please.
- [Man] You have fun, now.
- [Woman] Take care.
- Oh, hello.
- Hi.
- Uh, you want one of these?
- [Carrie] Oh, thank you.
- Um, I--
- [John] Hello, Charles.
- Hello, dear John, how
are you, how are you?
Good, good.
This is, um--
- Carrie.
- Delighted, I'm John.
- [Carrie] Hi, John.
(all chuckle)
- So John, how's that
gorgeous girlfriend of yours?
- She's no longer my girlfriend.
- Ah, dear, still I wouldn't
get too gloomy about it,
rumor had it she never stopped
bonking old Toby de Lisle,
just in case you didn't work out.
- She is now my wife.
- Excellent, excellent, congratulations.
- [Carrie] Excuse me.
- Any kids or anything, John?
Do we hear the patter of tiny feet?
No.
Well, there's plenty of
time for that, isn't there?
No, uh, no hurry.
(grunts)
Hi, how are you?
- My name's Fiona.
- Um, I'm Gerald.
- [Fiona] What do you do?
I'm training to be a priest.
- Good lord!
Do you do weddings?
- No, no, not yet, I
will, though, of course.
Jolly nerve-racking.
- Yes, rather like the
first time one has sex.
- Um, well, well, I suppose so.
- Though rather less messy, of course.
And far less call for condoms.
(Gerald giggles)
- Who's that boy over there in the gray?
- [Matthew] His name's David.
- Something of a dish, isn't he?
- Well, I've always thought so.
- [Serena] Why are they, um?
- Oh, the dish can't hear.
- Oh!
Gosh.
- Yeah, silent, but deadly attractive.
(gong bangs)
- Bang, bang, bang, that's right.
Into the marquee, please,
ladies and gentlemen.
Dinner is served.
- How do you do?
- Hello, Tom, splendid to
meet you, very exciting.
- Hi.
My name's Scarlett.
Don't let me drink too much,
'cause I'll get really flirty.
- How do you do, my name is Charles.
- Don't be ridiculous,
Charles died 20 years ago.
- Must be a different Charles, I think.
- Are you telling me I
don't know my own brother?
- [Charles] No, no.
(glass clinks)
- Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm sorry to drag you from
your delicious desserts.
There are just one or two little things
I feel I should say as best man.
This is only the second time
I've ever been a best man.
I hope I did the job all right that time.
The couple in question are
at least still talking to me.
(guests laugh)
Unfortunately, they're not
actually talking to each other.
The divorce came through
a couple of months ago.
(guests laugh)
But I'm assured it had
absolutely nothing to do with me.
Apparently, Paula knew
that Pierce had slept
with her younger sister before
I mentioned it in the speech.
(guests laugh)
The fact that he slept with
her mother came as a surprise
but I think was incidental to
the nightmare of recrimination
and violence that became
their two-day marriage.
Anyway, enough of that.
My job today is to talk about Angus.
And there are no skeletons in
his cupboard or so I thought.
- [Guests] Ooh!
- I'll get to that in a minute.
I would just like to say this,
I am, as ever, in bewildered awe
of anyone who makes
this kind of commitment
that Angus and Laura have made today.
I know I couldn't do it,
and I think it's wonderful they can.
So anyway, back to Angus and those sheep.
(all laugh and applaud)
So, ladies and gentlemen,
if you'd raise your glasses,
the adorable couple.
- [All] Yes, the adorable couple!
(all cheer and applaud)
- [Man] Get one for me, Angus!
(upbeat energetic music)
♪ I remember when rock was young ♪
♪ Me and Suzie had so much fun ♪
♪ Holding hands and skipping stones ♪
♪ Had an old gold Chevy
and a place of my own ♪
♪ But the biggest kick I ever got ♪
♪ Was doing a thing called
the crocodile rock ♪
♪ While the other kids were
rocking round the clock ♪
♪ We were hopping and bopping
to the crocodile rock ♪
♪ From outer space ♪
♪ I just walked in to find you here ♪
♪ With that sad look upon your face ♪
♪ I should have changed that stupid lock ♪
♪ I should have made you leave your key ♪
♪ I should have known
for just one second ♪
♪ You'd be back to bother me ♪
- I remember the first time I
saw Gareth on the dance floor
I feared lives would be lost.
(both laugh)
She's a pretty girl.
The one you can't take your eyes off.
Is it love at first sight?
- Oh, good lord, no, no, uh, it's the um,
it's the bloke she's dancing with.
I used to play rugby with him at school.
I'm just trying to remember
what position he played in.
Though, let's say one,
for the sake of argument,
one did take a fancy to
someone at a wedding.
I mean, do you think
there really are people
who can just go up and say,
hi, babe, my name's Charles,
this is your lucky night?
- Well, if there are, they're not English.
- Well, quite.
Three weeks is about my
question-popping minimum.
- You know I love you, Jean, don't you?
I love you, I love you.
And Mike, I've never met you before
but I love you very much, I really do.
- [Woman] Silly girl.
- Ignore her, she's drunk.
At least I hope she is.
Otherwise, I'm in real trouble.
- How's it going, Lyds?
- Bloody awful.
- Oh, dear, what's the problem?
- I was promised sex.
Everybody said it,
you be a bridesmaid, you'll get sex.
You'll be fighting them off.
But not so much as a tongue in sight.
- Well, I mean, if you fancy anything.
I could always--
- Oh, don't be ridiculous, Bernard.
I'm not that desperate.
- No, right, of course, fair enough.
It's a good point.
(wedding guests cheer)
(sheep bleats)
- [Woman] Bye!
- Bye, have a lovely, lovely time!
(car horn lares)
Bye!
♪ I feel it in my toes ♪
(Lydia laughs)
♪ Love is all around me ♪
♪ And so the feeling grows ♪
♪ It's written on the wind ♪
♪ It's everywhere I go ♪
- [Tom] Where are you
staying tonight, Charles?
- Oh, Scarlett and I are at some pub,
The Lucky Boat, something like that.
Aren't we all?
- Ah no, slight change of plan.
The others are, in fact,
coming back to my place.
Nancy's in residence, might knock us up
a quick plate of eggs and bacon
over a late-night Scrabble.
I wondered if you'd like to join.
- Oh, yeah, that would be great.
Thanks very much.
Is there room for Scarlett?
- Oh, absolutely, 137 rooms actually.
- (chuckles) Tommy, are you
the richest man in England?
- Oh, no, no, I believe
we're about seventh.
The queen, obviously.
- [Charles] That's right.
- That Branson bloke's
doing terribly well.
Well, excellent news.
I'll go tell Scarlett.
- [Charles] Yeah.
- That's unless you get lucky first.
- [Man] Forget about it!
Get out, get out, go on,
all right then go on.
- [Carrie] Hi.
- Hi, hi, I thought you'd gone.
- No, not yet, I was just wondering
where you were staying tonight.
- Well, I was staying at some pub called
The Lucky Boat or something like--
- [Carrie] Boatman.
- Right, but now I'm gonna stay
at some friend's house with some friends.
Well, I say house, I
think enormous castle is
a more accurate description.
- That's too bad 'cause
I'm at The Boatman.
- Oh.
- Well, it was nice not quite meeting you.
It was a great speech.
- Thanks.
- Well, I'm going now.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
don't, don't go, we can meet now.
The evening's just getting going.
- Oh, I think we both
know that's a big lie.
♪ So if you really love me ♪
♪ Come on and let it show ♪
- Fuck.
(charlie gags)
♪ Sometimes it's hard to be a woman ♪
♪ Giving all your love to just one man ♪
- The castle beckons, I think, Tom.
Are you sober?
- Absolutely, orange juice all night.
- [Gareth] Come on.
♪ 'Cause after all, he's just a man ♪
- [Scarlett] Bye, everybody!
- [Male Singer] All together now.
♪ Stand by your man ♪
♪ Give him two arms to cling to ♪
- (gasps) Bernard!
♪ When nights are cold and lonely ♪
♪ Stand by your man ♪
♪ Wah, wah, wah ♪
♪ And tell the world you love him ♪
♪ And give him all the love you can ♪
♪ Stand by your man ♪
- [Charlie] Tom, Tom,
can you stop the car?
Stop the car!
Sorry, sorry, I just think
I might stay in that pub after all.
- [Tom] Why on earth?
(all vocalizing)
- No, no, no, seriously,
I'm doing some research on pubs
with word boat in the title.
I hope to produce the definitive work.
- Oh, well, please yourself.
- It's a silly thing, you know?
Right.
Odd decision.
Hello.
- Hi.
In the end, it turned out
there wasn't room for all of us, so--
- You said it was a castle.
- No, it is a castle.
It's just a very, very small one.
Tiny, in fact, just one up,
one down, which is rare.
- Drink, sir?
- Yeah, I'd like a glass
of whiskey, please, thanks.
Do you want?
- Yeah, sounds good.
- [Charlie] And make
another one for the lady.
- Doubles, sir?
- [Charlie] Hm, thanks.
- (whistles) Ah, you here too, are you?
- Hello, I'm fine.
- Haven't seen Carrie, have you?
- Who?
- Carrie, American girl, lovely legs,
wedding guest, nice smell.
- No, sorry.
- Damn, blast, I think I was in there.
Look if you do see her,
could you tell her I've
gone up to my room?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Your whiskey, sir.
- Thank you.
- And one for the--
- Road, lovely.
- Actually, I think I
might have one those.
Do you mind if I join you?
- No, that'd be lovely.
- Another glass of whiskey and a cigar.
Hold on, make that a bottle of whiskey.
We might as well settle in, eh?
Let's see if we can push on
through till dawn, shall we?
Lovely wedding.
- [Charlie] Yes, yes, yes.
- I was at school with his
brother Bufty, tremendous bloke.
He was head of my house,
buggered me senseless.
Still, taught me a
thing or two about life.
- [Charlie] Mm.
- [George] Where you know him from?
- University.
- Mm, splendid, splendid, yep.
I didn't go myself, I
couldn't see the point.
You see, I mean when you're
working the money markets
what use are the novels of
Wordsworth gonna be, eh?
- Excuse me, sir, your wife says,
could you come upstairs at once?
Room 12, in case you're so
drunk you can't remember.
- My wife?
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, my wife, (laughs) my wife!
- My God, you are drunk,
you can't even remember you got a wife.
- Yeah, yeah, zzz (laughs).
Do you mind if I?
- No, no, off you go, off you go.
Best of luck.
- [Charlie] Thanks, yeah.
- Lucky bachelor me,
I'll think I'll have another
search for that Katie creature.
- Carrie.
- That's the one, damn fine filly.
I think I'm in there.
- [Carrie] Hi.
- Hello, sorry about that.
- No, that's fine, he
was hard to get rid of.
- Yeah, so, um,
(slow gentle music)
maybe we could just skulk
around here for a bit,
and then go back down.
- Now that's a thought.
I don't usually skulk a lot
but I suppose I could skulk
if skulking were required.
Do you skulk regularly?
- No, no, I don't normally think of myself
as a skulker, but, um.
- Well, why don't you come in
and skulk for a while and we'll see.
(door thuds)
So I noticed the bride and
groom didn't kiss in the church
just kind of strange.
Where I come from, kissing is very big.
- Is it?
Yes, well, I think you're right.
I think we are probably more reserved.
You know, and you may now kiss the bride,
isn't actually in the
book of common prayer.
- I always worry I'll go too far,
you know, in the heat of the moment.
- Uh huh, how far do you
think too far would be, then?
- Oh, I don't know.
Maybe,
that would be all right.
- Yeah, I think that would be fine.
- In fact, it might be a bit dismissive.
Maybe this
would be better.
- Yeah, I think, I think
it would be dangerous
to take it any further.
I mean, um, you know.
That might be taking it a little far.
- [Carrie] What about this?
Do you think the vicar would think
things had slipped a
bit out of his control?
- [Charles] I think he might.
- This kind of thing
is really better suited
to the honeymoon than
to the service itself.
- Why do you think it's
called a honeymoon?
- [Charlie] Um, I don't
know, I suppose it's honey
'cause it's sweet as honey.
And moon because it was the first time
a husband got to see his wife's bottom.
(slow serene music)
What's happening?
- I have to go.
- [Charlie] Where?
- America.
- That is a tragedy.
- Just before I go,
when were you thinking of
announcing the engagement?
- Huh?
Sorry, whose engagement?
- Ours, I assumed since we slept together,
and everything, we'd be getting married.
What did you think?
- What?
I, um,
gosh, you know, that, that's, um,
takes a lot of thinking
about that kind of thing.
Obviously, I'm, I'm, uh,
you're joking.
(Carrie laughs)
God, for a moment there,
I thought I was in Fatal Attraction.
I thought you were Glenn Close,
and I was gonna get home
and find my pet rabbit on the stove.
- Oh, no, but I think we've both missed
a great opportunity here.
Bye.
(slow subdued music)
(alarm clock rings)
(mid-tempo cheerful music)
- [Charles] Oh, fuck!
- Huh?
Fuck.
- [Charlie] Fuck.
Fuckity, fuck.
- Fuck, fuck!
Car or taxi?
- Taxi, we could never park.
Car seems a good idea.
- [Both] Fuck.
- Leave it, no one will notice.
(church bells ring)
- [Man] Sorry, madam.
(uptempo organ music)
- Well, sorry I'm late, traffic.
Yeah, who is it today?
- [Photographer] One more, please.
(uplifting organ music)
- In the name of the
Father, and of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit, amen.
- [Wedding Guests] Amen.
- Let us pray.
Father, you have made the bond of marriage
a holy mystery, a symbol of
Christ's love for his church.
Hear our prayers for Bernard and Lydia
through your son, Jesus Christ our lord
who lives and reigns with
you and the Holy goat, ghost.
One God, forever and ever, amen.
- It's his first time, he's
a friend of the family.
- Ah, excellent.
- Bernard and Lydia,
I shall now ask if you freely
undertake the obligations of marriage.
Bernard, repeat after me,
I do solemnly declare.
- I do solemnly declare.
- [Gerald] That I know not
of any lawful impediment.
- That I know not of any lawful impediment
- Why I, Lydia.
- [Bernard] Why I, Bernard.
- Sorry.
(men laugh)
Why I, Bernard Godfrey Saint John Delaney.
- Why I, Bernard Geoffrey
St. John Delaney.
- May not be joined in
matrimony to Lydia John Hibbott.
matrimony to Lydia Jane Hibbott.
- Lydia repeat after me,
I do solemnly declare.
- I do solemnly declare
- [Gerald] That I know not
of any lawful impediment.
- That I know not of
any lawful impediment.
- Why I, Lydia Jane Hibbott.
- [Lydia] Why I, Lydia Jane Hibbott.
- May not be johned in matrimony.
- May not be joined in matrimony.
- To Bernard Geoffrey
(mumbles) John Delaney.
- [Lydia] To Bernard
Geoffrey St. John Delaney.
- [Gerald] I call upon those persons
here present to witness.
- I call upon those persons
- That I, Bernard
Delaney.
- (sighs) That I, Bernard Delaney.
- Do take thee, Lydia Jane Hibbott.
- To be my awful wedded wife.
- To be my lawful wedded wife.
- That's right, that's right.
May almighty God bless you all.
The Father, the Son and
the Holy spigot, Spirit.
- [Wedding Guests] Amen.
- Bravo!
- [Man] Bravo!
(joyful organ music)
(wedding guests applaud)
- [Tom] Thanks.
We're coming, Bernie.
- Come here!
- Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
That way?
Yes, of course.
Sorry, could you two, um, thanks, sorry.
- [Woman] Tom, don't go away.
- [Tom] Sorry.
- I've got a new theory about marriage.
Two people are in love,
they live together,
and then suddenly one day
they run out of conversation.
- [Charlie] Uh huh.
- Totally, I mean, they can't think
of a single thing to say to each other.
That's it, panic.
Then suddenly it occurs
to the chap that there is
a way out of the deadlock.
- [Charlie] Which is?
- He'll ask her to marry him.
- [Charlie] Brilliant, brilliant!
- [Gareth] Suddenly, they've
got something to talk about
for the rest of their lives.
- Basically, you're saying
marriage is just a way
of getting out of an embarrassing
pause in conversation.
- Yep, the definitive icebreaker.
Tom, how's the speech coming along?
It's pretty good, I think.
Something for everyone, tears, laughter.
- (laughs) Excellent.
- Well, I think it's a
very good theory, Gareth.
- Well, there is another
argument, of course,
that it does have something
to do with true love.
- Well, there's a thought.
- [Bartender] Can I help you, sir?
- Can I have three
glasses of brandy, please?
- [Bartender] Certainly, sir.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine, fine.
Yeah, sorry, I'm overwhelmed to see you.
Um, look, don't go back
to America, please.
I'll be back in two secs, okay?
- Okay.
- Hi, Fi.
That's yours and that's yours.
See you in five hours.
- [Gareth] Something happened?
- Yeah, has a bit, this is a
bloody great wedding, you know.
(grunts)
Hi.
Well, you look perfect.
You, in fact, you probably are perfect.
Well, how are you?
- I'm really well.
Charles, I'd like for you
to meet Hamish, my fiance.
(slow subdued music)
- Excellent, excellent.
How do you do, Hamish?
Pleasure to meet you.
Charming surprise to find
Carrie back in the country.
- Yes, well, it took a lot of
persuading, I can tell you.
Come on, darling, I told
James I was gonna get you.
He'll begin to think
I've totally lost control of you already.
- I'll see you later.
- How are you doing, Charles?
- Not great, actually, suddenly.
I don't know.
I mean, um, what the hell's going on here?
Why am I always at weddings
and never actually getting married, Matt?
- It's probably because
you're a bit scruffy.
- Yeah.
- Or it could also be 'cause
you haven't met the right girl.
- But you see, is that it?
Maybe I have met the right girls.
Maybe I meet the right girls all the time.
Maybe it's me.
- Nonsense.
- My lords, ladies, and
gentlemen, dinner is served.
- Come on, odds on you
meet your wife at dinner.
- Yes.
Oh, my God.
- Charles?
- Hi.
- [Alistair] Hello, I'm Alistair.
- [Charlie] Great.
- And I believe you know Veronica.
- Yeah, hi, Vee, hi.
Nicki, hi.
Great.
- [Woman In Hat] Tell me, are you married?
- No.
- [Woman In Hat] Are you a lesbian?
- Good lord!
Well, what made you say that?
- Well, it's one of the
possibilities for unmarried girls.
And it is a bit more
interesting than saying,
oh, dear, just never found
the right chap, eh (chuckles).
- Quite right, why be dull?
- Thank you.
- The truth is, the truth is
I have met the right person,
only he's not in love with me,
and until I stop loving
him, no one stands a chance.
- [Woman In Hat] Oh, bad luck.
- Yes, isn't it?
I was a lesbian once at school,
but only for about 15 minutes.
I don't think it counts.
- There are 400 different kinds of tea
and that's not including all
these so-called fruit teas.
I took Veronica out to India at Christmas
to look at the plantations.
- Oh, excellent.
- I believe you and her went there once.
- That's right.
- Charles was vile.
He insisted on cracking
jokes all the time I was ill.
- I was just trying to cheer you up, Vee.
- Oh, you're that Veronica!
- Which Veronica?
Charlie?
- Remember Bombay?
- When Charles and I were going out,
he told me he'd had
this interesting journey
around India with Vomiting Veronica.
I think that was it.
- I don't remember ever
mentioning it, maybe I did.
- Oh, come on, Charles.
I don't think I've been out
with anyone less discreet.
- Well, I think that's probably
a bit of an exaggeration, is it not?
- It is not.
- I remember you going on
about this girl, Helena was it?
Whose mother made a pass at you.
- I remember this!
You couldn't work out whether it would
be impolite not to accept her advances!
(all laugh)
- That's right!
Mrs. Piggy, Helena was Miss Piggy,
so her mother was Mrs. Piggy.
(all laugh)
- I think perhaps it was a, it was a--
- We've both lost a lot
of weight since then.
(claps)
- Ah, great, the speeches.
- My lords, ladies, and gentlemen
pray silence for the best man.
(wedding guests applaud)
- When Bernard told me he
was getting engaged to Lydia,
I congratulated him, because
all his other girlfriends
had been such complete dogs.
(Lydia laughs)
Although, may I say how delighted we are
to have so many of them here this evening.
(Gareth laughs)
I'm particularly delighted to see Camilla,
who many of you will probably
remember as the first person
Bernard asked to marry him.
If I remember rightly,
she told him to sod off.
(Gareth laughs)
And lucky for Lydia that she did.
- [Man Walking With Tom]
It's very disappointing.
- We had the most adorable girl
at our table called Carrie.
Apparently her fiance's awfully grand
and he owns half of Scotland.
How are you?
- Well, I'm stuck in
the wedding from hell.
Ghosts of girlfriends past at every turn.
Next thing you know,
I'll bump into Henrietta,
and the horror will be complete.
- [Henrietta] Hello, Charles.
- Hello, Hen, how are you?
(Henrietta sobs)
Oh, Hen, I--
- Why can't you leave her alone?
Haven't you hurt her enough?
- Excuse me, I think I'd better be
where other people are not.
(mid-tempo band music)
- Hello.
(women giggle)
- [Woman] She did not.
- [Woman] She did too.
- [Doorman] Taxi!
Good night, sir.
- [Carrie] Thanks.
- [Doorman] Thank you.
- [Carrie] (chuckles) Come on now.
I They asked me how I knew I
♪ My true love was true, ooh ♪
♪ I of course replied ♪
♪ Something here inside cannot be denied ♪
(Bernard speaks faintly)
(Bernard and Lydia groan and giggle)
- [Lydia] Oh, wait a
minute, wait a minute.
This is no fun, I want
to see my lovely husband!
(Bernard and Lydia grunt and groan)
Who's a very bad bridegroom, indeed?
♪ Uh huh hm hm ♪
♪ Gonna get along without you now ♪
- Have you got a boyfriend?
- Yes.
- What's his name?
- Dolph, he's good at table tennis.
What about you?
- No, afraid not.
- [Girl] Why not?
I don't know.
Because most of the blokes I fancy think
I'm stupid and pointless
and so they just bonk
me and then leave me.
And the kind of blokes that do
fancy me, I think are drips.
I can't be bothered to bank them
which does sort of leave me a bit nowhere.
- What's bonking?
- Well, it's kind of like table tennis
only with slightly smaller balls.
(Bernard and Lydia groan and giggle)
- So good!
I love my wife!
- [Lydia] And I love my husband!
- Do you think we'd
better be getting back?
- Or we could just wait a few
minutes and have another go.
- You naughty, naughty little rabbit.
- Found it.
- Charles, Charles, we must talk.
- Right, you're right.
- The thing is, Charlie,
I've spoken to lots of people about you.
- [Charlie] Oh, God.
- And everybody agrees you're
in real trouble, Charles.
- Am I?
- The thing is, you see,
you're sort of turning into
a kind of serial monogamist.
One girlfriend after another,
yet you'll never love anyone
'cause you never let them near you.
- On the contrary, Hen--
- You're affectionate to
them and sweet to them.
You were even sweet to me,
although you thought I was an idiot.
- [Charles] I did not.
- You did, I thought U2
was a type of submarine.
- Well, in a way you were right,
their music has a very naval quality.
- Be serious, Charles, you
must give people a chance.
You don't have to think,
I must get married.
But you mustn't start every
relationships thinking,
I mustn't get married.
- [Charles] Hen, you
know, most of the time
I don't think at all.
I, I just, you know, putter along.
- Oh, Charlie!
Oh, God, the way you used to look at me!
I just misread it, that's all.
All that time I thought
you were going to propose
and all that time you were
just working out how to leave.
- [Charlie] No, no, I wasn't.
- [Henrietta] Oh, God, this is ridiculous.
- [Charles] Hen--
- [Hen] No.
- No, Hen, Hen.
- [Henrietta] No!
- Hen?
- No.
- [Carrie] Having a good night?
- Yes, yes, it's right up
there with my father's funeral
for sheer entertainment value.
I thought you'd gone.
- No, Hamish has to take
the Edinburgh sleeper.
I'm off now, keep me company?
(tapping on window)
Here, please.
You wanna come up for a nightcap?
- You sure?
- Well, yes, I think we can risk it.
I'm pretty sure I can resist you.
You're not that cute.
- Sorry, yeah, great.
(slow delicate music)
- Morning, Charles.
Breakfast's up.
Well, it's a bit burnt.
- [Charlie] Excellent.
♪ Going to the chapel ♪
- What are you up to today?
- Oh, yeah.
I'm, uh, well, I'm taking
advantage of the fact that
for the first time in my
entire life it's Saturday
and I don't have a wedding to go to.
All I have to do is not be late for David.
- I was gonna go for a job.
There's shop called Spank
that wants a sales assistant.
I think I'd be great.
They sell all this funny rubber stuff.
- Oh, no, another wedding
invitation and a list, lovely.
- I mean, they say rubber's
mainly for perverts.
I don't know why, I think
it's very practical, actually.
I mean, you spill anything
on it, and it just comes off.
I suppose that could be
why the perverts like it.
You all right?
Yeah, yeah, it's that girl, Carrie,
you remember the American.
Excuse me, sorry to interrupt.
Do you have the wedding list for Banks?
- Certainly, sir.
Lots of beautiful things for around
about the 1000 pound mark.
- Uh huh, what about things
around the sort of 50
pound mark, is there much?
- [Sales Assistant] Well, you could get
that pygmy warrior over there.
- [Charles] This, excellent (chuckles).
- If you could find someone
to chip in the other 3,950.
Or our carrier bags are 1.50 pound each.
Why don't you just get 33 of them?
- Yes, well, I think
I'll probably leave it.
Thanks very much, you've been very, um--
- What'd you get?
- Blimey!
(both laugh)
Well, I never.
Nothing yet. I'm just, you know, deciding.
- It's nice to see you.
- This present thing is great.
I should've gotten married years ago.
Did anybody go for the pygmy?
- The young man was thinking about it.
- Oh, no (laughs), just get me an ashtray.
Are you free for about a half-hour?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm supposed
to meet my brother,
but I can be a bit late.
- Oh good, come with me.
You have an important decision to make.
Now the crucial thing is
that you mustn't laugh.
- Okay, right.
♪ They're writing songs
of love, but not for me ♪
- What do you think?
♪ A lucky star's above ♪
- Divine.
- Bit of a meringue?
- Um?
- Ugh, oh, don't worry,
we've only just begun.
♪ I found more clouds of gray ♪
- What do you think?
- You're kidding.
- But it would be wonderful, wouldn't it?
Maybe next time.
What do you think?
♪ I was a fool to fall ♪
- Um.
- I knew it.
- But look, if you could
find a little staff,
it'd be great for looking after sheep.
- Don't be rude.
It's a bit sexy, this.
- (chuckles) Well, if I were your husband,
I would die of pride.
You may be right, it is dangerous.
You know, there's nothing more off-putting
than a priest with an
enormous erection (gags).
(Carrie laughs)
♪ I guess she's not for me ♪
One strange thing is thinking
you'll never sleep with anyone else.
You don't think you'll be unfaithful?
- No, not once I'm married.
I told Hamish I'll kill him if he does,
so I better stick to that.
- Quite right, yes.
- Anyway, I reckon I've
had my fair run at it.
- What is a fair run
these days down your way?
- Oh, I don't know, more than one?
- Well, come on, tell me.
I've seen the dress,
we have no secrets now.
- Well, the first one, of course,
not easily forgotten, was kinda nice.
Two, hairy back.
Three, four, five,
six was on my birthday
in my parents' room.
- Which birthday?
- [Carrie] 17th.
- Oh, we've only reached 17?
- Well, you know, I
grew up in the country,
lots of rolling around in haystacks.
Okay, seven, mm.
(slow mellow music)
Eight, unfortunately, was quite a shock.
Nine, against a fence, very
uncomfortable, don't try it.
- I won't.
- 10, ugh, was gorgeous, just
heaven, oh, he was wonderful.
- I hate him.
(Carrie laughs)
- 11, obviously, after 10, disappointing.
12 through 17, the university years,
sensitive, caring, intelligent boys.
Sexually speaking, a real low patch.
18 broke my heart, years of yearning.
- I'm sorry.
- 20, oh my God, I can't
believe I've reached 20.
21, elephant tongue.
22 kept falling asleep, that
was my first year in England.
- I do apologize.
- 23 and 24 together, that was something.
- Seriously?
- 27, oof, now that was a mistake.
- Suddenly, at 27, you make a mistake?
- Well, yes, he kept screaming,
it was very off-putting.
I nearly gave up on the whole thing,
but Spencer changed my mind.
That's 28, his father, 29.
- His father?
- Um, 30, ugh, 31, oh my God.
32 was lovely.
And then my fiance, that's 33.
- Wow!
So I came after your fiance?
- No, you were 32.
- Oh.
- So there you go, less than Madonna,
more than Princess Di, I hope.
And how 'bout you, how
many have you slept with?
- Christ, nothing like that many.
I don't know what the fuck
I've been doing with my time, actually.
Work probably, yeah,
that's it, work, work.
I have been working late a lot.
I wish I'd rung you,
but then you never rang me.
You ruthlessly slept with
me twice and never rang me.
Oh, bollocks!
Help me, please, please.
Carrie, this is David, my brother.
- Hi.
- I was just telling him
about you marrying Hamish
and he said it couldn't have
happened to a nicer fellow,
so that's nice.
Where are you doing it?
- [Carrie] Scotland.
- He says that's a beautiful place, hilly.
- You should come to the wedding, too.
I want many friends as possible to make up
for the gruesome stiffs that Hamish knows.
Well, you better go in, bye.
Bye.
- Bye.
Fuck it.
Um, look, sorry, sorry.
I just, well, this is a
really stupid question,
particularly in view of our
recent shopping excursion.
But, I just wondered if by any chance,
um, I mean obviously not,
because I'm just some git
who's only slept with nine people.
But I just wondered, I really feel,
in short, to recap in a
slightly clearer version
in the words of David Cassidy, in fact,
while he was with The Partridge Family,
I think I love you.
And I just wondered whether by any chance
you wouldn't like to, um,
uh,
no, no, no, of course not.
I'm an idiot, he's not.
Excellent, excellent,
fantastic, obviously.
Lovely to see you.
Sorry to disturb, better get on, fuck.
- That was very romantic.
(slow tender music)
- Well, I thought it over a lot.
You know, I wanted to get it just right.
Important to have said it, I think.
- Said what, exactly?
- Said you know, what I just
said about David Cassidy.
- You're lovely.
- It was ordained for lifelong
faithful relationship of conjugal love.
It was ordained for the
welfare of human society
which can be strong and happy
only when the marriage
bond is held in honor.
Into this holy estate these two
persons now desire to enter.
Wherefore if anyone
can show any just cause
why they may not lawfully be
joined together in marriage
let him now declare it.
(door clangs)
- Sorry.
- [Vicar] Please rise.
Do you, Hamish take this woman, Caroline,
to be your wedded wife?
And do you, in the presence of God
and before this congregation
promise and covenant to be to her,
a loving and faithful husband
until God shall separate you by death?
- [Hamish] I do.
- [Vicar] Do you, Caroline
take this man, Hamish,
to be your wedded husband?
And do you, in the presence of God
and before this congregation
promise and covenant to be to him
a loving and faithful wife
until God shall separate you by death?
- I do.
- [Vicar] As a token of the covenant.
- Fuck-a-doodle-doo.
- [Vicar] These rings
are given and received
by these signs you take each other.
(traditional Scottish music)
- How awfully nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
How do you do?
- How do you do?
- Hello.
- Fred.
- You look beautiful.
Not a meringue in sight.
- Thanks.
- [Charles] Blimey.
- It's Brigadoon.
It's bloody Brigadoon!
Dear old things, as you
know, I've always been proud
there isn't a wedding ring
between the lot of us.
Over the passing of years,
it's suddenly beginning to distress me.
I'd like to go to the wedding
of someone I really loved, for a change.
- Well, don't blame me,
I've asked practically everyone I know.
- You haven't asked me.
- Haven't I?
- No.
- Oh, Scarlett, would you like to?
- No, thank you, it was
very nice of you to ask.
- Well, anytime.
- Quite right, Tom, that's the spirit.
Now, tonight, these are your orders,
go forth and conjugate,
find husbands and wives.
- Excellent plan, what do you think, Fifi?
Spot a potential hubby in the throng?
- Bugger off, Tom.
- Quite right.
- A toast before we go into battle
True love, in whatever
shape or form it may come.
May we all in our dotage be proud to say
I was adored once too.
(all laugh)
- [All] True love.
(uptempo lively music)
- Apparently, an enormous number of people
actually bump into their
future spouses at weddings.
Which is interesting.
- Yes, I met my husband at a wedding.
- Ah.
Good lord, I seem to
have finished my drink.
If you'll excuse me.
- Hello, my name's Scarlett.
Named after Scarlett O'Hara,
but much less trouble.
What's your name?
- My name's Rhett.
- No, not really!
- No, not really, in fact, it's Chester.
- You kidder (laughs),
I always imagine Americans
are gonna be dull as shit.
I mean, of course you're not, are you?
Steve Martin's American, isn't he?
- Yes, he is.
- You're lovely.
- [Woman] Come on!
- Hello, Charles.
- Oh, Hen, hi.
Look, I'm sorry, I couldn't
really bear a scene today.
I know, you know, we probably
got tons to talk about,
and all that kind of stuff--
- Did I behave that atrociously last time?
- Well, you remember the
shower scene in Psycho?
- Yeah.
- Scarier.
(both laugh)
Oh, God, I'm depressed, Hen, how are you?
- I'm cheerful, actually,
I weigh almost nothing.
And I've got a divine new boyfriend.
- Perhaps you were right, Hen,
perhaps we should've married.
- Good God, no, marry you
and I'd have had to marry your friends.
And I'm not quite sure I could take Fiona.
- Fiona loves you.
- Fiona calls me duck face.
- Well, I never heard that.
- Look, darling, come to lunch soon.
Give me a ring, okay?
Oh, still cute!
- How's duck face?
- Good form, actually, not too mad.
(traditional Scottish music)
- Ladies and gentlemen,
the bride and groom.
(guests applaud)
- You like this girl, don't you?
- Yes.
Yes, it's a, it was a strange thing
when at last it happens.
And, huh, she's marrying someone else.
How about you, Fifi?
You identified a future
partner for life yet?
- No need, really, the deed is done.
I've been in love with
the same bloke for ages.
- [Charlie] Have you, who's that?
- You, Charlie.
It's always been you.
Since first we met, oh, so many years ago.
I knew the first moment,
across a crowded room, or lawn, in fact.
Doesn't matter,
(slow melancholy music)
nothing either of us can do on this one,
such is life.
Friends isn't bad, you know?
Friends is quite something.
- Oh, Fi.
Fi.
It's not all easy, is it?
- No.
Just forget this business, not to be.
Matthew, darling, where's Gareth?
- Torturing Americans.
- How thoughtful of him.
- Do you actually know Oscar Wilde?
- Not personally, no.
But I do know someone who could
get his fax number for you.
Shall we dance?
(upbeat jubilant music)
(woman in black laughs)
Well, any rings on fingers?
- Oh, Gareth, you don't
know how lucky you are.
Finding someone to marry
is a very tricky business.
- It's hell out there.
Matthew's trapped with an
evangelist from Minnesota.
- Come down, sweet Jesus,
and cast out the devil!
- My lords, ladies, and gentlemen,
please charge your glasses.
First, and rather unusually,
we have the bride.
(guests applaud)
- Excellent, I love this girl.
- Thank you.
First of all, I'd like to thank all of you
who've flown in from the States.
I'm really touched.
And as for the rest of you,
I would have the fact that
lots of frightful Americans
were flying in was a perfect
excuse for staying away,
so I thank you too.
(guests laugh)
If my darling dad had been here today,
he would have been speaking now.
And I know what he would have said,
great dress, babe,
but why in the hell are you
marrying the stiff in the skirt?
(guests laugh)
And I would have given him the
same answer that I give you,
because I love him.
As John Lennon said, who
died the same year as my dad,
“Love is the answer.
"And you know that for sure."
(guests applaud)
Oh, oh, and one more thing,
someone told me here,
confidentially, that if things
with Hamish didn't work out
that he would step in.
And I just wanted to say thanks,
and I'll keep you posted.
(all laugh)
- Bravo!
- [Best Man] And now, my lords,
ladies and gentlemen, Sir Hamish Banks.
(guests applaud)
- Anyone involved in politics
for the last 20 years
has gotten used to being
upstaged by a woman, isn't it?
I didn't expect it to happen
to me on my wedding day.
However, I must also
say that I'm quite happy
(Gareth gasps)
to be upstaged by this woman
for the rest of my life.
Oh, clear, is that some
barracking at the back?
Again, something we
politicians are used to.
- Shit, find a, find a doctor.
- [Man] Right, okay.
- First of all, I want to extend
my compliments to the bridesmaids.
You did your duty superbly.
And obviously, I intend
to use you every time
I get married from now on.
(guests laugh and applaud)
(slow uneasy music)
And also, I want to thank
all those wonderful ladies
of the parish who did the
flowers in the church.
The stern old building took on a look
of flushing youth today.
(guests laugh and applaud)
The first time I laid eyes on her,
I thought to myself, if by
any chance she's shortsighted
I might just be happy
for the rest of my life.
I thought I could see my
future for the first time.
It was a joyful one for
years and years to come.
(guests applaud)
♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For they are jolly good fellows ♪
♪ And so say all of us ♪
(slow somber music)
- Good morning, and a warm welcome
to you all on this cold day.
Our service will begin in a few minutes.
But first we have asked Matthew,
Gareth's closest friend,
to say a few words.
- Gareth used to prefer
funerals to weddings.
He said it was easier to get
enthusiastic about a ceremony
one had an outside chance of
eventually being involved in.
(guests chuckle)
In order to prepare this speech,
I rang people to get a general picture
of how Gareth was regarded
by those who met him.
Fat seems to have been a word
people most connected with him.
Terribly rude also rang a lot of bells.
So very fat and very rude seems
to have been the stranger's viewpoint.
On the other hand,
some of you have been
kind enough to ring me
and let me know that you loved him,
which I know he would have
been thrilled to hear.
You remember his fabulous hospitality.
His strange experimental cooking.
The recipe for duck la
banana fortunately goes
with him to his grave.
Most of all, you tell me of
his enormous capacity for joy.
And when joyful, when joyful,
for highly vocal drunkenness.
But I hope joyful is how
you will remember him,
not stuck in a box in a church.
Pick your favorite of his waistcoats
and remember him that way.
The most splendid, replete, big-hearted,
weak-hearted, as it turned out,
and jolly bugger most of us ever met.
As for me, you may ask
how I will remember him.
What I thought of him.
Unfortunately, there I run out of words.
Perhaps you will forgive me
if I turn from my own feelings
to the words of another
splendid bugger, W.H. Auden.
This is actually what I want to say,
stop all the clocks.
Cut off the telephone.
Prevent the dog from
barking with a juicy bone.
Silence the pianos, and with muffled drum
bring out the coffin.
Let the mourners come.
Let the airplanes circle,
moaning overhead scribbling
on the sky the message,
he is dead.
Put great bows around the white
necks of the public doves.
Let traffic policemen
wear black cotton gloves.
He was my north, my
south, my east and west.
My working week and my Sunday rest.
My noon, my midnight, my talk, my song.
I thought that love would last forever
I was wrong.
The stars are not wanted
now, put out every one.
Pack up the moon and dismantle the sun.
Pour away the ocean and sweep up the wood.
For nothing now can ever come to any good.
(slow somber music)
- [Man] Bye, now.
- It was good of you to come.
Must have been the shortest
honeymoon in history.
- No, it's fine, we'll
do it some other time.
You know, that thing
you said in the street?
- Yes, I'm sorry about that.
- No, I liked it, I liked you saying it.
- Charlie, I'll take
Scarlett home, all right?
- [Charlie] Yeah, darling Fi.
- Walk, Charlie?
- Yeah, yeah, that would be grand.
- Never felt like that.
I mean, something vaguely similar
for Jilly when I was young.
- Jilly?
- Labrador.
- Yes, it's odd, isn't it?
For all these years we've
been single and proud of it
and never noticed that two of us were,
for all intents and purposes,
married all this time.
- Traitors in our midst.
You know, in a way,
I think death is hardest
for the parents, don't you?
I hope I die before my children.
- Tom, there's one
thing I find really, uh,
well, it's your total confidence
that you will get married.
I mean, what if you never
find the right girl?
- Sorry?
- Surely, if that service shows anything
it shows that there is such
a thing as a perfect match.
If we can't be like Gareth and Matthew
then maybe we should just let it go.
Some of us are not gonna get married.
- Well, I don't know, Charlie.
The truth is, unlike you, I
never expected the thunderbolt.
I always just hoped
that I'd meet some nice,
friendly girl, like the look of her.
Hope the look of me didn't
make her physically sick.
Then pop the question and
settle down and be happy.
It worked for my parents.
Well, apart from the divorce and all that.
- I'll give you six months
at the outside, Tom.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
Maybe all this waiting
for one true love stuff
gets you nowhere.
(alarm clock rings)
(alarm clock clicks)
(multiple alarm clocks ring)
Ah, what the fuck is going on?
(grunts) What?
- I thought we'd better make
absolutely sure we weren't late.
Excellent wedding hairstyle by the way.
(mid-tempo joyous music)
- Matthew, the best-looking
best man in the world.
Listen, thank you for doing this today.
- Of course.
- I wish Gareth was here.
- Bet he does too.
I'm sorry I was so late.
The others are just parking the car.
I thought we'd all go with Tom.
- Late, so late?
- Yeah, it's 9:45.
- 9:45?
- Yep, 45 minutes till I do.
- Bloody Tom, I told him
to set the alarm for 8:00!
Fuck it!
Fuck!
- [Matthew] Scarlett.
- Oh, hi.
- [Matthew] You ready?
- Absolutely, give me 20 seconds.
(car tires screech)
- Time?
- Honestly?
- Yes, time?
- It's about 10 to 9:00.
- Oh!
(all laugh)
Bastards.
- [Woman] Jessica, stop
jumping up and down, please.
(Jessica laughs)
Settle down, Tommy, you've got two arms.
- [Photographer] One, two, three, smile!
Brilliant.
- This is splendid stuff.
- Yes, I think I might say a little word.
Well, as many of you know,
I have been a close observer
Charles' love life for many years now.
But recently, I'd started to despair
and fear that really he
was married to us lot,
apart from the fact that
we won't have his babies.
- I don't know about that.
- Fortunately, it's turned out splendidly.
The girl in question is sadly crazy
but perhaps that's why he loves her.
So I'd like to propose a toast
to my Charlie and his beautiful
girl on this tragic day.
So be happy and don't forget us.
- [Charles] Thank you.
- To Charles and duck face.
- [All] To Charles and duck face!
- What do you think?
- You look divine.
- It does work, doesn't it?
Yes.
- Well, I'd like to thank
Fiona for those charming words
words about my future wife.
I'd like to take this
opportunity before the day starts
to read a little message
from her to you all.
- Oh, this is exciting.
- She says, any of you
come near the house,
I'll set the dogs on you.
I think that's rather--
- That's a nice touch.
(all laugh)
- I'll set the dogs on you.
- [Matthew] John, hi, you made it, good.
- Oh, yes, I hope me damn sister turns up.
Not much of a wedding without a bride.
Tom.
Charlie.
Bit of a poor show, you
not having a stag night.
- Oh, we did, we did, we did, we did,
we didn't think it was a very good idea
in this day and age, uh, so.
- Really?
Oh.
(slow tranquil music)
- Fi, you do look lovely today.
- Yes, as you can see I've
abandoned my traditional black.
- (chuckles) Yes, so you have.
- From now on, I shall be
all the colors of the rainbow
and fall in love with someone
who fancies me for a change.
- Darling Fi.
- Oh, look.
- What?
- Lipstick everywhere, that
won't do at all, will it?
(church bells ring)
- Hi, hi.
- Good luck.
- [Scarlett] Hello, glad you could come.
Groom's on the right, bride's on the left.
- Groom right inside.
- Oh, my God!
I thought you'd gone back to Texas.
- [Chester] Without you, never.
- Good luck.
- [Matthew] The bride or groom?
Bride or groom?
- It should be perfectly
obvious I'm neither.
Great God!
- Bride or groom?
- Bride.
(slow organ music)
- Yes, um, fine.
You know, I've got a
feeling we've met before.
We have, about 25 years ago.
I'm second cousin Harold's
daughter, Deirdre.
You're Tom.
- Good lord, so you're family.
- Yes, only very distant.
- Well, yes, of course.
You said you were bride?
- Yes.
- Well, well, do sit.
Do sit here, Deirdre.
Golly, thunderbolt city.
- [Bernard] Hello, Matthew.
Hello, Charles.
- Bernard, how are you?
- Exhausted, actually.
- [Lydia] That's funny, Charles.
- Hello, Lyd.
- Stick with me.
- Hi.
- Hi
- You look lovely.
But then as you know I did
like you dressed for weddings.
And on time!
- Yep, extraordinary thing, isn't it?
How's Hamish?
- Oh, he's fine, I believe.
- You believe?
- Well, yes, he wasn't
the man for me after all.
- You left him?
- We left each other.
- When?
- Oh, a few months now.
March was hell, by April it was sordid.
It's absolutely the last time
I marry someone three times my age.
- [Matthew] Charlie,
Charles, time to travel.
- Yeah, yeah.
Coming, good, good.
So why didn't you get in touch, then?
- I did think about it.
I wanted to, but, um, I was in a state.
So anyway, I don't wanna keep you.
And I'll see you afterwards.
- Yeah, fine, excellent.
Wait.
I'll show you to your seat.
Just showing her to her seat.
- Our timing's been really bad, hasn't it?
- It's been bad, yes.
- It's been a disaster.
- It has, as you say,
been very bad indeed.
God, it's lovely to see you.
- Well, good luck.
It's pretty easy.
Just say I do whenever
anyone asks you a question.
- Um, could you just
give me a sec, Matthew?
- Yes, of course, freshen up at will.
- Dear lord, forgive me
for what I'm about to say
in this magnificent place of worship.
Bugger!
Bugger, bugger, bugger, bugger!
- Can I help at all?
- Huh, no, thanks.
Sorry, vocal exercises, big church.
- Excellent, often do the same myself.
Not exactly the same vocab, obviously,
rather more hallelujahs.
(Charles chuckles)
I'll leave you.
(church bells ring)
- Bride's arriving.
- Oh, fabulous!
We seem to have lost the groom.
- Do you wanna see if you can stall her,
and I'll see if I can find him.
- Roger.
- Wilco.
(knocking on door)
Charles.
- [Charles] Hm?
- It's good to see you.
- Yeah, yeah.
Matt, what do we think about marriage?
- (sighs) Gosh, well, I
think it's really good
if you love the person
with all your heart.
- Well, exactly.
Quite.
All these weddings, all these years,
all that blasted salmon and champagne.
Here I am on my own wedding
day and I'm still thinking.
- Well, can I ask about what?
- No, no, I think best not.
- I'm terribly sorry,
there's a bit of delay,
there's just a slight
problem with the flowers.
- Flowers, what?
- Unfortunately, there seems to be
a staggeringly high proportion
of hay fever sufferers
in the congregation,
and they've been stuck right
next to the damn flowers.
So we're just moving
them, the congregation.
Don't want the damn vows to be obliterated
by the sound of sneezing.
- Charles, would it be
out of place for me to say
that time is ticking by?
- They should've started by now.
- I think I've fooled them so far.
The great advantage of having
a reputation for being stupid,
people are less suspicious of you.
(knocking on door)
- Hello.
- Here you are.
Ready to face the enemy?
- Are we?
- Yes.
Excellent.
("Wedding March" by Felix Mendelssohn)
- Not so tight, Dad!
- Dearly beloved we are
gathered together here
in the sight of God and in
the face of this congregation
to join together this man and
this woman in holy matrimony
which is an honorable
estate instituted of God
in the time of man's innocence.
Signifying unto us the mystical union
that is betwixt Christ and His church
and therefore is not by
any to be enterprised
nor taken in hand unadvisedly,
lightly, or wantonly
but reverently, discreetly,
advisedly, soberly,
and in the fear of God.
Therefore, if any man
can show any just cause
why they may not lawfully
be joined together
let him speak now or else
hereafter forever hold his peace.
(knocking)
I'm sorry, does someone
have something to say?
Yes, what is it?
- One second.
- What's going on, Charles?
- [Henrietta] Charles, what?
- He wants me to translate
what he's saying.
- What is he saying?
- He says, I suspect the
groom is having doubts.
I suspect the groom would like to delay.
I suspect the groom, I suspect the groom.
- What's he saying?
- He says he suspects the
groom loves someone else.
(guests chatter)
- And do you?
Do you love someone else?
Do you, Charles?
- I do.
(Henrietta screams)
(guests chatter)
- [Henrietta] Get out of my
way, get out of my way, oh!
(thunder crackles)
- Blimey.
- At least it's one we won't forget.
I mean, a lot of weddings just blend
into each other, don't they?
- Oh, for God's sake.
- But this one will really
stick out in the memory.
- For not actually
including a wedding service.
- Poor girl.
No, I mean it, poor girl!
I mean, she's not my
favorite person in the world,
but I think that may have been
an unforgivable thing that you did today.
- I can't bear to think about it.
Poor Hen.
- Though, let's face facts.
I mean, if you weren't sure
you wanted to marry her today
of all days, i.e., your wedding day
then it must be the right
decision, mustn't it?
- Quite right, Tom.
- It was a lovely dress.
I'm sure she'll find
it useful for parties.
- What did he say, Charles?
- Says he blames himself.
- [Matthew] Absolutely not,
no, you mustn't, David.
(doorbell buzzes)
Uh, no, it's okay--
- No, no, no, if there's
music to be faced,
I should be facing it.
- Hello.
- Hi, you're soaking, come in--
- No, no, I'm fine, I'm fine.
Comes a point you're so
wet, you can't get wetter.
- Okay, I'll come out.
- No, please don't.
I just wanted to check you're okay.
Not busy killing yourself
or anything, but,
but you're fine, so.
(slow tender music)
I shouldn't have come to the
church this morning, I'm sorry.
- No, no!
Wait, it was all my fault.
I mean, I'm the bastard here.
And it definitely sorted out one thing,
which is marriage and
me we're very clearly
not meant for one another.
Sorted out another big thing as well.
There I was, standing there in the church
and for the first time in
my whole life I realized
I totally and utterly loved one person.
And it wasn't the person
standing next to me in the veil,
it's the person standing
opposite me now in the rain.
- Is it still raining?
I hadn't noticed.
- The truth of it is I've loved you
from the first second I met you.
You're not suddenly going
away again, are you?
- No, I might drown, but otherwise, no.
- Okay, okay, we'll go in.
But first, let me ask you one thing,
do you think after we've dried off
after we've spent lots more time together
you might agree not to marry me?
And do you think not being
married to me might maybe
be something you could consider doing
for the rest of your life?
Do you?
- I do.
(thunder crackles)
♪ Spring is here, the
sky is blue, whoa-oh-oh ♪
♪ Birds will sing as if they knew ♪
♪ Today's the day we'll say I do ♪
♪ And we'll never be lonely anymore ♪
♪ Because we're goin' to the chapel ♪
♪ And we're gonna get married ♪
♪ Goin' to the chapel and
we're gonna get married ♪
♪ Gee, I really love you ♪
♪ And we're gonna get married ♪
♪ Goin' to the chapel of love ♪
♪ Bells will ring, the sun
will shine, whoa-oh-oh ♪
♪ I will be hers and she'll be mine ♪
♪ We'll love until the end of time ♪
♪ And we'll never be lonely anymore ♪
♪ I feel it in my fingers ♪
♪ I feel it in my toes ♪
♪ The love that's all around me ♪
♪ And so the feeling grows ♪
♪ It's written on the wind ♪
♪ It's everywhere I go, oh, yes it is ♪
♪ So if you really love me ♪
♪ Come on and let it show ♪
♪ You know I love you, I always will ♪
♪ My mind's made up by
the way that I feel ♪
♪ There's no beginning,
there'll be no end ♪
♪ 'Cause on my love you can depend ♪
♪ I, I've been watching you ♪
♪ But so far you never seem to care ♪
♪ You better stop to deny me ♪
♪ Ooh, why don't you try me ♪
♪ Get up and dance ♪
♪ Slammin', jammin' to
the pumped up funk ♪
♪ It's the right time to fall in love ♪
♪ And you know what I want ♪
♪ And you know what I need ♪
♪ So take my body baby ♪
♪ And burn me up ♪
♪ Get the message through ♪
♪ That I'm waiting just for you ♪
♪ Get up and dance ♪
♪ Come on and dance ♪
♪ Slammin', jammin' to
the pumped up funk ♪
♪ It's the right time to fall in love ♪
♪ Funky ♪
♪ Yo, baby, get funky ♪
♪ Yo, baby get funky ♪
♪ Oh, go, go, go, go, go ♪
(lion roars)