Mummy got sick.
And it happened just like that.
There's nothing anybody could do.
It isn't fair.
There's no reason.
And if we start asking why, we'll go crazy.
Five minutes in the microwave.
Any one of them. Five
minutes, and ready to eat.
Do you know how to make juice?
Microwave. Five minutes.
Here. It's my shrink. Call him.
Loss of Spouse Support Group.
Chicago Cancer Family Network.
Parents without Partners.
Partners without Parents.
"Hug Yourself," "Hug a
Friend," "Hug a Shrink." Or work.
Work hard, work will save you. Work is the
only thing that will see you through this.
Don't mind him, he's just a guy
who's lost his wife.
What I think we really need is change.
Good idea. Take a couple of weeks
off, get some sun, take Jonah fishing.
No, real change. A new city.
Some place where every time I go
around a corner I don't think of Maggie.
Where are you gonna go?
I was thinking about Seattle.
Eventually, in a few months, you'll
start seeing women. You'll meet someone.
Right, right. Move on, right,
that's what I'm gonna do.
And then in a few months, boom,
I'll be fine. I'll just grow a new heart.
Sam, I'm sorry...
She didn't mean that.
I know, I know. Look, it
just doesn't happen twice.
♪ You must remember this, ♪
♪ A kiss is still a kiss ♪
♪ A sigh is just a sigh ♪
♪ The fundamental things apply ♪
♪ As time goes by ♪
♪ And when two lovers woo ♪
♪ They still say "I love you" ♪
♪ On that you can rely ♪
♪ No matter what the future brings ♪
♪ As time goes by ♪
♪ Moonlight and love songs ♪
♪ Never out of date ♪
♪ Hearts full of passion ♪
♪ Jealousy and hate ♪
♪ Woman needs man ♪
♪ And man must have his mate ♪
♪ That no one can deny ♪
♪ It's still the same old story ♪
♪ A fight for love and glory ♪
♪ A case of do or die ♪
♪ The world ♪
♪ Will always welcome lovers ♪
♪ As time goes by ♪♪
The tall one with red
hair is your cousin Irene.
You'll recognise her by the
disappointed look on her face.
Married to Harold, who
ran off with the secretary.
Who came back because Irene threatened
to put the dog to sleep if he didn't.
Your brother Dennis is
professor at Johns Hopkins.
He's married to, uh, Betsy.
The most competitive woman in the world.
I don't see how I'm
gonna remember all this.
Oh, well, Walter, you will!
Your Uncle Milton lost all of his money.
And some other people's.
In a pyramid scheme. Don't mention
the IRS or the federal prisons system.
Your mother's Barbara, your father's Cliff.
My father has electric trains.
Really?
Am I what they had in mind?
Oh, Walter, they're gonna love you!
Everybody,
Annie has an announcement.
Oh... Walter and I are engaged.
Thank you. Thank you.
Mum knew. Dad, Mum knew.
I don't see a ring, Annie.
Congratulations, Walter.
Bless you. Bless you!
Are you all right?
It's nothing. It's nothing.
Maybe it's the flowers.
We'll move them.
No, don't touch them! I feel
terrible, sneezing at a time like this.
This is a very important moment for me.
He's allergic to everything,
don't worry about him.
Bees. I'm allergic to bees.
Harold is allergic to every type of bee.
We always have to carry a
hypodermic of adrenalin wherever we go.
If he eats even one tiny piece of a nut...
My head swells up like a
watermelon and I drop dead.
It's the same with him and bees.
Your mother and I had
salmon at our wedding.
I really think a wedding
without cold salmon is...
I'm not allergic to salmon.
Oh, he's not allergic...
I don't think.
But you never know.
You never know.
Harold wasn't always allergic to bees.
Oh, honey, what a shame.
We had some champagne.
What did we use it for?
Uncle Milton's parole.
And it was delicious.
It was, wasn't it, Milton?
When are you getting married?
In early June, in the garden.
Oh...
What about Harold and bees?
I'm allergic to bees.
We'll spray you.
Cold salmon, a lovely
cucumber salad, strawberries.
I'm afraid I am allergic to strawberries.
Is this all right with you?
Today, I'm consider myself the luckiest
man-man-man on the face of the earth-earth-earth.
The Lou Gehrig line from...
Remember, Dad, the
Lou Gehrig line from, uh...
Pride of the Yankees.
Pride of the Yankees!
Yeah. Yeah.
Baseball. It's baseball.
Historical reference.
I would like to propose a toast.
Hear, hear. To my kid sister.
To Walter and my baby.
To Walter and Annie.
Everyone, please eat before it gets cold.
Here it is. The Historical
Society wanted this
and I never would give it to them.
Oh, Mum...
I noticed these things
are back in fashion.
Grandmother's dress.
Oh, honey.
He's a lovely man, Annie.
I know he is wonderful, isn't he?
And he's such a wonderful athlete.
Are his folks nice?
You'll love them.
We're going down to DC tonight
to be with them Christmas morning.
How did it happen?
It's silly, really.
I mean, I'd seen him at the office.
Obviously I'd seen him.
He's the associate publisher.
And then one day we both ordered
sandwiches from the same place
and he got my lettuce and tomato on whole
wheat, which, of course, he was allergic to.
And I got his lettuce and tomato on white.
How amazing. It is, isn't it?
You make a million
decisions that mean nothing
and then one day you order
takeout that changes your life.
Destiny takes a hand.
Mum, destiny is something we've invented
because we can't stand the fact that
everything that happens is accidental.
Then how do you explain that you
both ordered exactly the same sandwich
except for the bread?
How many people in this world
like lettuce and tomato without
something else, like tuna?
Well, it wasn't a sign.
It was a coincidence.
I was in Atlantic City with
my family, Cliff was a waiter.
He wasn't even supposed to
work that night. Suppose he hadn't?
He asked me to take a
midnight walk on the Steel Pier.
I probably told you this a
million times, but I don't care.
Then he held my hand.
At one point I looked down and I couldn't tell
which fingers were his and which were mine.
And I knew. What?
You know.
What? Magic. It was magic.
Magic.
I knew we'd be together forever.
And that everything would be wonderful.
Just the way you feel about Walter.
Walter. It's quite a formal name.
One of the things I truly
knew was that your father and I
were going to have a wonderful time in
the sack, I believe you call it.
Mum.
Of course it took several
years before everything
worked like clockwork in that department.
So don't be worried if it takes a while.
We already...
Fine, fine. Fiddly-dee. How's it working?
Like clockwork. Oh, honey...
It's a sign.
You don't believe in signs.
They loved you. I told you they
would love you, and they loved you.
I love you. I love you, Walter.
Did anyone ever call you
anything other than Walter?
No.
Not even when you were young?
No, not even when I was young.
You sure you don't want to drive with me?
Oh, how will I get back
to Baltimore on Friday?
I forgot the present. Walter, I left your
stepmother's present inside by accident.
I swear, when we're old and grey
you gonna have to remind
me to put my teeth in.
I'll be walking all over town smacking
my gums together, not even noticing.
I'll wait.
You'll wait? Oh, right.
No, don't wait, Walter. Really, it's
silly, you go ahead. We're late anyway.
I'll be ten minutes behind you.
♪ Sleigh bells jingle-ing ♪
♪ Ring ting tingle-ing too ♪
♪ Horses, horses, horses ♪
♪ It's lovely weather ♪
♪ For a sleigh ride together with you ♪
♪ Giddy-up, giddy-up ♪
♪ The snow is falling ♪
♪ And friends are calling "Yoo Hoo" ♪
♪ Friends are calling "Yoo Hoo" ♪
♪ Ding-a-ling-a-ling ♪
♪ Sleigh ride together with you ♪
♪ Horse, horses, horses ♪
♪ Horse, horses ♪♪
♪ Jingle bells, jingle bells ♪
♪ Jingle all the way ♪
♪ Oh, what fun, it is to ride ♪
♪ In a one horse open sleigh, hey ♪
♪ Jingle bells ♪♪
Welcome back to
"You and Your Emotions."
I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone,
broadcasting live across America
from the top of the Sears Tower in Chicago.
Tonight we're talking
about wishes and dreams.
What's your wish this Christmas Eve?
What's your wish?
My wish is to turn the radio station.
Subject of this evening's medical
update is: "You and your spleen."
And your host is...
Not on your life.
Coming up, "Jingle Bells"
backwards, sung by the New Jersey...
- Seattle, go ahead.
- Hello, this is Jonah...
No last names, Jonah.
You sound younger than our
usual callers. How old are you?
I'm 8.
Eight? How come you're up so late?
It's not that late in Seattle.
Oh, of course,
you're absolutely right.
All right, what's your
Christmas wish, Jonah?
It's not for me, it's for my dad.
I think he needs a new wife.
You don't like the one he has now?
- He doesn't have one now.
- That's the problem.
Where's your mum?
She died.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Well, who can believe this?
I've been pretty sad,
but I think my Dad's worse.
Have you talked to your dad about it?
- No.
- Why not?
It's like it makes him sadder.
- Aw, I can understand that.
- Jonah, is your dad home right now?
Yeah.
What's he doing? Is he busy?
Not really, he's out on the deck.
- I'm sure that I can help.
- But I'm gonna need you to help me...
- Wretched woman! Hang up, Jonah!
- No way, he'd kill me.
Trust me, Jonah.
He won't be angry when he realises
how concerned you are about him.
Wanna bet?
But if I get yelled at, I'm never
gonna listen to your show again.
Okay, fair enough.
- Dad?
- Yeah.
There's someone
on the phone for you.
- His name is Sam.
- Sam.
If you've just tuned in,
this is Dr. Marcia Fieldstone
and tonight's topic is
your wishes and dreams.
I got it.
We're on the line now
with someone from Seattle.
Hello.
Hello, Sam, this is Dr. Fieldstone
on Network America.
Okay. What are you selling tonight?
Micro-hibachis or knives?
- No, I'm not selling anything.
- I just wanna help.
I want you to know that your son called
and he asked me for some advice
on how you might find a new wife.
Who is this?
Dr. Marcia Fieldstone of Network
America. And you are on the air.
- You called a radio station?
- Sam, are you with me?
Yeah. Yes.
Your son feels that since your wife's
death you've been very, very unhappy.
And he is genuinely worried about you.
Get out here. Get out here. Come on,
now, I'm not gonna go through this alone.
I think it's very hard for him
to talk to you about all this.
I thought maybe you and I could talk, it
would make Jonah feel a little better. Sam?
Talk to her, Dad. She's a doctor.
Of what?
Her first name could be Doctor.
Please.
Sam. Sam, it's his Christmas wish.
Okay. Okay. Good.
- Now, I know this is difficult.
- But how long ago did your wife die?
About a year and a half ago.
Aw. Have you had any relationships?
No. No? Why not?
Uh, Marcia, or Dr. Fieldstone?
Dr. Marcia.
- Dr. Marcia.
- I don't mean to be rude...
And I don't want to invade
your privacy...
- Sure you do.
Go on, Sam. I'm listening. Sam.
We had a pretty tough time at first.
But we're dealing with it.
And Jonah and I will get along just
fine again, as soon as I break his radio.
I have no doubt that
you're a wonderful father.
You know, you can tell a lot
from a person's voice.
You certainly can.
But something must be missing if Jonah
still feels that you're under a cloud.
Just a few questions:
Are you sleeping at night?
He doesn't sleep at all.
How do you know that?
I live here, Dad.
Look, it's Christmas.
Maggie, my wife.
She really did it...
I mean, she loved...
She made everything beautiful.
It's just tough this time of year.
Every kid needs a mother.
Could it be that you need someone
just as much as Jonah does?
- Yes.
- Don't answer that.
Let's get into that right
after these messages.
Sam, Jonah, don't go away.
If you've have just tuned in,
we are talking to Sleepless in Seattle.
And we'll be right back after this
break with your listener response.
What is she talking about?
This is when other people get to
call in and dump on what you said.
Oh. Oh. Well, this is
really fun. And helpful.
I bet he's tall
with a cute butt.
I bet he hasn't bathed
in weeks and he stinks.
Harriet, shut up. Hi, can I help you?
Tea, with the bag out.
You know, maybe I'll just go up to Seattle,
give him a little gift for New Year's Eve.
Yeah, you go on out there if you
want to. But don't open his refrigerator.
They don't cover anything
when they put it in the fridge
they just stick it in there and
leave it till it walks out by itself.
All I'm saying is I wouldn't kick this
guy out of my bed for eating crackers.
You know what I'm saying?
Sixty five cents.
Let's take a call
before we get back to Sleepless.
Ooh!
Tennessee, you are on the air.
Yes, I would just like to know
where I could get this man's address.
Honey, get in line.
Next caller, go ahead.
If there was one question
I was allowed to ask...
Oh, go ahead.
People who truly loved once
are far more likely to love again.
Sam, do you think that there is someone out
there you could love as much as your wife?
Well, Dr. Marcia Fieldstone,
that's hard to imagine.
What are you going to do?
Well, I'm going to get
out of bed every morning
and breathe in and out all day long.
And after a while I won't
have to remind myself
to get out of bed every morning
and breathe in and out.
And then after a while I won't
have to think about
how I had it great and perfect for a while.
Sam, tell me what was
so special about your wife.
Well, how long is your program me?
Oh, well, it was a
million tiny, little things.
When you added them all up, it just
meant we were supposed to be together.
And I knew it, I knew it
the very first time I touched her.
It was like coming home,
only to no home I'd ever known.
I was just taking her hand
to help her out of a car.
And I knew it.
It was like magic. Magic.
Well, folks, it's time to wrap it up.
I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone in Chicago.
And to all my listeners,
a magical and merry Christmas.
And to you, Sleepless in Seattle,
we hope you'll call again soon
and let us know how it's going.
Oh, you can count on it.
♪ I know ♪
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ The blue birds fly ♪
♪ Birds fly ♪
♪ Over the rainbow ♪
♪ Why then, oh why can't I? ♪
This man sells the greatest soup you've ever
eaten, and he is the meanest man in America.
I feel very strongly about this,
Becky. It's not just about soup.
Do it. What else?
New Year's Eve. Please
don't make me write it.
Listen to this: "Phone service in the Chicago
area was tied up for two hours Christmas Eve
when some kid calls a radio show
and says that his dad needs a new wife."
Two thousand women called the
station asking for the guy's number.
I heard it. This kid calls up
and says, "My dad needs a wife."
And the shrink practically forces the guy
and says, "Do you want to talk about it."
And he says,
"No, as a matter of fact, I don't."
And then suddenly for no
reason at all he start to talk
about how much he loved his wife
and how he just fell in love with her like
he was one of those cows in Michigan.
What cows in Michigan?
It was on 60 Minutes over those
cows that got zapped by stray voltage.
No one knows why.
And maybe it was Wisconsin.
But, anyway, I was listening to him
talk about how much he loved his wife
and suddenly I was crying.
It's like what happens when I
watch those phone company ads.
I don't have to see the
whole thing, just the part
where the daughter gives the mother
the refrigerator with the big red bow.
Yes. The Polaroid commercial, two 5-year-olds
at their grandfather's birthday party.
They're making the album.
That kills me!
You should write something about this.
- About what?
- Whatever it is.
I tell you what it is: Two thousand women
calling a radio station for a husband?
There are a lot of desperate
women out there looking for love.
Especially over a certain age.
You know it's easier to be killed by a
terrorist than it is to get married over 40.
That is not true.
That statistic is not true.
That's right, it's not true.
But it feels true.
It feels true because it's true.
There is practically a whole book
about how that statistic is not true.
Calm down, you brought it up.
I did not, Wyatt.
Did you even read that book?
Did anybody read that
book all the way through?
Are you two finished?
Fine, now where were we?
If someone's a widower, why do
they say that he was he "widowed"?
Why don't they say he was "widowered"?
I was just wondering.
What was that about up there?
What was what? What's with you?
Nothing's with me.
Something's with you.
What are you saying?
Whatever it is, you can tell me.
Sleepless in Seattle?
That's what she called him on
the show because he can't sleep.
And now 2000 women want his
number. The guy could be a crackhead,
a transvestite, a flasher, a junkie,
a chainsaw murderer
or someone really sick,
someone like my Rick.
Actually, he sounded nice.
Oh? Oh, really?
Now we're getting down to it.
Please, Becky. I'm madly in love with Walter.
He did the craziest thing the other night.
What was that?
Oh, it was so funny. We
were hysterical. What was that?
You know, I was thinking, I've gotta go
to Boston for the AAB convention, right?
And then I gotta visit Winston-Hughes
about switching over our computers, but...
Why don't we meet in New
York for Valentine's Day weekend.
Walter, I'd love to!
We can stay at the Plaza.
Ice skate in Central Park.
Register.
Yeah, for dishes,
glasses, silver, everything.
How about it?
I'll take you to Chinatown for dim sum.
Does it have wheat in it?
I don't think so.
♪ Dim sum, dim sum ♪
♪ Dooby-doo-bop ♪
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six
five, four, three, two, one.
Hey, Jonah, wake up, wake up.
The ball's dropping.
It's okay. Ohh. There we go.
Happy New Year.
Kiss Howard.
Good night, Howard.
♪ Sometimes I wonder ♪
♪ Why I spend ♪
♪ The lonely nights ♪
♪ Dreaming of a song ♪
♪ The melody ♪
♪ Haunts my reverie ♪
♪ And I am once again with you ♪
♪ When our love was new ♪
♪ And each kiss an inspiration ♪
♪ But that was long ago ♪
♪ Now my consolation ♪
♪ Is in the stardust of a song ♪
♪ Beside a garden wall ♪
♪ When stars are bright ♪
♪ You are in my arms ♪
♪ The nightingale ♪
♪ Tells his fairy tale ♪
♪ Of paradise where roses grew ♪♪
Can I have half your beer?
Sure, go ahead.
What did I used to say?
"Here's looking at you"?
"Here's mud in your eye."
"Here's to us."
You used to say, "Here's to us."
Oh, babe.
I miss you so much it hurts.
What do you wanna do?
Tell him when he gets here.
You want to tell him?
You can tell him?
She's back.
She has another idea.
No, no, no. I don't need this.
Sam, I'm so glad you're here.
How are you?
I heard you on the radio.
I told everyone about it.
We already knew. How did you...?
Grace. The dispatcher?
Yeah. All of Seattle knows.
I was brushing my teeth
and, suddenly, there you were.
I just couldn't believe my ears. I
called my mother in Las Vegas.
I said, "Mother, turn on the
radio. That's my architect."
You know, it's so nice when a
man can express his feelings.
It's wonderful.
I wish I could express my feelings.
So, Claire, is there a problem?
I was tossing and turning last
night. You know what that's like, Sam.
Because I realise I'm
never going to fit my platters
in that refrigerator we ordered.
And when I give parties,
I always put in platters.
So I thought I would get the
sub-zero refrigerator instead.
And the only problem...
We have to redo all the cabinets.
We're gonna...
We'll be into this wall.
- That's bearing wall.
- That's a delay, Claire, of...
Two, three... Five, six...
Twelve weeks. I don't mind.
The important thing is to get it right.
Absolutely. Your words.
Oh, I've gotta rush.
La décorateur calls.
Bye. Bye.
Well, this is fate. She's divorced,
we don't wanna redo the cabinets,
and you need a wife. What do they
call that, when everything intersects?
The Bermuda Triangle.
And here's another one. Do
you got room for one more here?
Here you go. Right there.
Look at this, Dad.
They're all for you.
Yes, sir. Here you go.
"Sleepless in Seattle,"
c/o Dr. Marcia Fieldstone.
If you're having trouble
sleeping, you might wanna try
drinking a glass of
water from the other side.
I thought that was for hiccups.
Does it work for hiccups?
For hiccups, take a spoonful of
sugar, hold it in your mouth for a minute.
Really?
Thank you.
What possessed you
to give them our address?
They called and asked for it.
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle
"you're the most attractive man
I ever lay ears on." Pfft.
Wait, wait. They called?
How did they get our number? Oh,
let me guess. You gave it to them.
You have to give them your
number or they won't let you on the air.
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle. I
live in Tulsa." Where's that?
It's in Oklahoma.
You know where Oklahoma is?
Somewhere in the middle.
I'm not even gonna think about
what they're not teaching you in school.
Yeah, somewhere in the middle.
And, generally speaking
we should rule out anyone
that doesn't live near here.
She's willing to fly anywhere.
She looks like my third-grade
teacher. I hated my third-grade teacher.
Wait a minute.
She is my third-grade teacher!
Aren't you gonna read any of these?
No. This is not how it's done.
I'd much rather just see somebody I like
and get a feeling about them,
ask them if they wanna have a drink.
Or a slice of pizza? Not dinner.
Not on the first date, because halfway
through dinner, you could be really sorry.
Whereas, if it's just a drink
if you like them, you can
always ask them to dinner.
If not, you can say, "Well, that
was great," and then you go home.
You see what I mean?
I wonder if it still works this way.
It doesn't. They ask you.
I'm starting to notice that.
If you get a new wife, I guess
you'll have sex with her, huh?
I certainly hope so.
Will she scratch up your back?
What?
In movies, women always scratch
up the man's back and screaming.
How do you know this?
Jed's got cable.
Oh, Jed's got...
Hand me that towel behind you.
Thank you. I need it too.
Here, let me get you.
"Jed's got cable!" Come on.
♪ Another bride ♪
♪ Another groom ♪
♪ Another sunny honeymoon ♪
♪ Another season, another reason ♪
♪ For makin' whoopee ♪♪
♪ When the sun is high ♪
♪ In the afternoon sky ♪
♪ You can always find ♪
♪ Something to do ♪
♪ But from dusk till dawn ♪
♪ As the clock ticks on ♪
♪ Something happens to you ♪
♪ In the wee small hours ♪
♪ Of the morning ♪
♪ While the whole wide world ♪
♪ Is fast asleep ♪
♪ You lie awake ♪
♪ And think about the boy ♪
♪ And never ever think ♪
♪ Of counting sheep ♪♪
Welcome back
to the best of Dr. Marcia Fieldstone
clinical psychologist
and the friend you never had.
Remember Marooned in Miami?
He says he doesn't love me anymore.
Why would you wanna be with
someone who doesn't love you?
Disappointed in Denver.
Every time I come close to orgasm,
he goes to make himself a sandwich.
Why don't you make him
a sandwich beforehand.
Sleepless in Seattle.
Well, I'm going to get out
of bed every morning.
Breathe in and out all day long.
And then after a while,
I won't have to remind myself
to get out of bed every morning
and breathe in and out.
And then after a while,
I won't have to think about
how I had it great and perfect for a while.
Sam, tell me what was
so special about your wife?
Well, how long is your program me?
Oh, well, it was...
Oh, it was a million tiny, little things.
When you added them all up
it just meant that we were
supposed to be together.
And I knew it.
I knew it the first time I touched her.
It was like coming home,
only to no home I'd ever known.
I was just taking her hand,
to help her out of a car.
And I knew it.
It was like
magic.
Well, I think I'm going crazy, Dennis.
I really do. Are you happily married?
What? I mean...
Why did you get married?
Was it trumpets and fireworks?
I got married because Betsy said we had to
break up or get married. So we got married.
But when you first met her, did you believe
that she was the only person for
you, that in some mystical, cosmic way
it was fated? Annie,
when you're attracted to someone,
it means your subconscious
is attracted to their subconscious,
subconsciously.
What we think of as fate is just two
neuroses knowing they're a perfect match.
I don't even know him.
I'm having all of these fantasies
about some man I've never even met,
who lives in Seattle!
It rains nine months
of the year in Seattle.
I know. I know.
I do not wanna move to Seattle.
But what I really don't wanna do
is end up always wondering
what might've happened
and knowing I could've done
something. What do you think?
It's just cold feet, isn't it? Everybody
panics before they get married.
I mean, didn't you? Yes, I did.
Yes, you did. Thank
you very much, Dennis.
I feel so much better
just having blown this off.
Anytime.
Sandy has a girlfriend,
Glenda. She's a weightlifter.
Her neck isn't bigger than her head...
No, I'm not asking you to set me up.
I don't need your help with that. I
wanna know what it's like out there.
That's what I'm trying to tell you what
women are looking for: Pecs and a cute butt.
Like, "He has the cutest butt."
Yeah.
Where did I hear that recently?
Everywhere.
You can't even turn on the news
without hearing some babe
thought some guy's butt was cute.
Who the first woman to say this was, I
don't know, but somehow it caught on.
So how's my butt?
Not bad. Really?
Yeah. Is it cute though?
I don't know. Are we
grading on a curve?
When was the last time you were out there?
Uh... Uh, uh...
Jimmy Carter, 1978.
Things are a little different now.
First, you have to be friends.
You have to like each other.
Then you neck.
This could go on for years.
Then you have tests, then
you get to do it with a condom.
The good news is you split the cheque.
I don't think I could let
a woman pay for dinner.
Great! They'll throw a parade
in your honour.
You'll be Man of the
Year in Seattle Magazine.
Tiramisu.
What is tiramisu?
You'll find out.
Well, what is it? You'll see.
Some woman is gonna want me to
do it to her, and I'm not gonna know.
You'll love it.
Oh, this is gonna be tough.
Tough, tough. It's gonna be
much tougher than I thought.
What about that decorator
on the Bennett job?
Victoria? Yeah. She's perky.
Oh, no, I don't... What?
I'm far away from that.
What? No.
I'm just assembling notes. I'm not...
Notes.
How would I do that?
What do you mean? Call her up.
You say, "Come, let's get
together. We'll look at swatches."
Call her on the phone to say,
"Let's look at swatches"?
Yeah, you know, colour schemes.
She's not gonna see through that?
No, you don't do it like I do it.
You do it in your own suave way.
Think Cary Grant.
Cary Grant would call up and say,
"Come over and look at my swatches"?
How do you know? Maybe he
did. He didn't do it in the movies.
Gunga Din? He didn't call...?
Gunga Din is not a swatch kind of movie.
Who knows what he did in real life.
He did that with Dyan Cannon?
Yeah, sure.
"Hello, Dyan!
Take a look at these swatches."
Jonah, I'm home!
Hey, Jonah!
Jonah?
Hey, Jonah.
Hi, Dad. This is Jessica.
Well, it's nice to meet you, Jessica.
Dad, this is amazing.
If you play this backwards,
it says "Paul is dead."
Yeah, yeah. I know.
How do you know?
Dad, could you shut the door?
Sure. Sure.
H and G.
Hi and goodbye.
♪ I'm back in the saddle again ♪
♪ Out where a friend is a friend ♪
♪ Where the longhorn cattle feed ♪
♪ On the lowly gypsum weed ♪
♪ Back in the saddle again ♪
♪ Ridin' the range once more ♪
♪ Totin' my old.44 ♪
♪ Where you sleep out every night ♪
Hello, Victoria?
This is Sam Baldwin. I don't
know if you remember me, but...
Oh, great.
Hi. Uh...
I was wondering if, uh...
If you would like to have a drink with me?
Dinner?
Dinner would be even better.
Friday would be great, yeah.
How...? I hear
that's a good place.
7:30 would be fine.
And I'll, uh...
Okay, I'll meet you there.
Okay. All right.
Um... So it's Friday
at 7:30 for dinner.
Great.
Me too. Bye.
♪ Back in the saddle again ♪♪
Are you in love with him?
I'm not now.
Now those were the days when
people knew how to be in love.
You're a basket case.
They knew it.
Time, distance, nothing could
separate them because they knew.
It was right. It was real. It was...
It's a movie.
That's your problem.
You don't wanna be in love.
You wanna be in love in a movie.
Read it to me.
"Dear Sleepless and Son. I've never
written a letter like this in my life..."
That's what everyone writes at
the beginning of letters to strangers.
I know that. You
think I don't know that?
What about Walter? Oh, Walter.
Oh, I'd give anything to marry Walter.
He's so unexpected.
You think you can tell what he's like
by just looking at him, but you can't.
I should write something
in this about magic.
What?
Something! What if I never meet him?
What if this man is my destiny,
and I never meet him?
Your destiny can be your
doom. Look at me and Rick.
"I want to meet you"...
Top of the Empire State Building.
On the top of the Empire State Building.
Sunset, Valentine's Day.
I'll be in New York with
Walter. I can squeeze it in.
I'll be in New York with Walter!
Do you wanna hear about destiny?
If I hadn't married Martin
I never would've bought
the house with the dead tree.
On account of which I got divorced.
On account of which I hit a car and
met Rick while buying a neck brace.
Wait a minute. You never told me you
got a divorce because of a dead tree?
The tree man.
You fell in love with the tree man?
I did not say "love."
Did I say "love"?
This is my favourite part.
It's now or never.
Never is a frightening word.
We'd be fools to let happiness pass us by.
Uh-huh.
Winter must be cold for
those with no warm memories.
- We've already missed the spring.
- Yes.
Men never get this movie.
I know.
Mummy! Mummy!
Mummy! It's okay. It's okay.
I'm here. I'm coming. Dad!
It's all right. It's okay.
It's okay.
Hey, it's all right. It's okay.
What was that about, huh?
It was sinking.
What was? Our house.
There was water coming in all the windows.
Oh.
Well, it's okay now.
So, what should we do?
Your mother used to sing to
you when you had bad dreams.
"Bye Bye Blackbird."
Yeah.
I miss her.
What do you think happens
to someone after they die?
I don't know.
Like, do you believe in heaven?
I never did.
Or the whole idea of an
afterlife. But now, I don't know.
Because I have these dreams
about your mum.
Yeah. And we have long talks.
About you. How you're doing.
Which she sort of knows,
but I tell her anyway.
So, what is that?
It's sort of an afterlife, isn't it?
I'm starting to forget her.
She could peel an apple
in one long, curly strip.
The whole apple.
♪ Pack up all my cares and woes ♪
♪ Feeling low ♪
♪ Here I go ♪
♪ I said bye ♪
♪ Bye ♪
I love you, Jonah.
I love you, Dad.
♪ Where somebody waits for me ♪
See you tomorrow.
♪ Sugar sweet so is she ♪
♪ Bye ♪
♪ I said bye ♪
♪ Blackbird ♪
♪ No one seems to love ♪
♪ Or understand me ♪
♪ And all the hard luck stories ♪
♪ They keep handing me ♪
♪ Where somebody shines the light ♪
♪ I'm be coming on home tonight ♪
♪ Bye, bye ♪
♪ I wanna say ♪
♪ Blackbird ♪
♪ Lord have mercy ♪
♪ Wait for me darling, yeah ♪♪
Laurie?
Hi, it's Annie.
Fine, fine. I'm fine.
Listen, I'm doing an article
on call-in radio shows.
Do you know anyone who works for
someone named Dr. Marcia Fieldstone?
I'm a writer for the Baltimore Sun,
and a friend of Laurie Johnson's.
I'm doing a piece on how people
handle bereavement.
And I understand you had a caller
the other night, some guy from Seattle.
- This is Jonah Baldwin.
- We're not in right now, but you can...
Baldwin.
Architect.
- Psst.
- Okay, Clarise.
I'm gonna be back either by
midnight or 8:30, if disaster strikes.
Here's one for the both of us.
"Sleepless and Son, Baltimore."
If there's any problem, here's
the number to the paediatrician.
Here's a bottle of Ipecac if anybody drinks
poison. It's right next to the juice glasses.
Fine. How do I look?
Great.
Do I look okay? I look all right?
I look stupid. I look stupid. I
look like I'm trying too hard.
I was gonna get a haircut, but
I'd just look like I got a haircut.
This is a good letter, Dad.
The heels on these are grotesque.
I look like I'm trying to be tall.
Her name is Annie Reed.
Now I'm late. Bye.
Dad, read this.
Read this!
"Sleepless and Son..."
I've been an excellent third baseman, and
while we're on it, let's just say right now:
Brooks Robinson was the
best third-base men ever.
"It's important you agree with me
on that because I'm from Baltimore."
She thinks Brooks Robinson
is the greatest. So do you.
Everyone thinks so. It's a sign.
Come here.
I'll show you a sign.
Here's a sign.
All right.
Where's Seattle?
Right. Where is Baltimore?
Ah! It's right there! Look!
One, two, three. There's, like, 26 states
between here and there. Now, that's a sign.
I'm out of here. Goodbye!
Good night! I love you.
Clarise, did you move your car?
Huh?
Thank you, Derrick.
You're welcome.
I'll have...
White wine spritzer?
Yes. And you, sir?
I'm fine. Thank you.
Hi. Hi.
You look good.
You look good yourself.
I thought you'd never call me.
You did? I really wanted you to.
And I thought you were never going to.
Excuse me, Mr. Baldwin? Yes.
There's a phone call for you.
Excuse me.
Thank you. Hello.
Dad, can we go to New
York City for Valentine's Day?
What? Annie Reed from Baltimore
wants to meet us at the top of the
Empire State Building on Valentine's Day.
Jonah? What?
Have you fallen down?
Are you bleeding?
Is Clarise there?
Has she been strangled?
No.
This is the only reason for this call?
If we book now, we can
get an excursion fare.
Jessica's parents are travel agents...
I'm not having this conversation.
We'll talk about it at a later time.
I can't believe this conversation
has lasted this long. You go to bed.
Everything all right? Oh, yeah.
Do you have kids? No.
Do you want mine?
I'll have an Absolut straight up, please.
Hey, hey! Put that down.
Stop it!
There she is.
Why is she bringing
those groceries?
She's gonna cook us something
so be prepared. Hi, Sam. Thanks.
Thanks. And let me guess.
You must be Jonah.
Hi.
So this it? Yeah.
The car's down this way. Great.
She's on her sixth painter and
we are never going to finish this job.
Now she wants the fireplace rebricked.
I know her.
I could give her a call.
No, I've got it solved. I'll just
hit her with one of those bricks.
That's so funny.
You're so funny.
When she wants something done she says, "Oh, I
don't know. I'm stupid. You know what's best.
But couldn't we flip the house around so
that everything in the back is now in front?
And could the whole front of the house open on
a hinge so I can get in with a garage opener."
"Yes, we can. We'll just..."
"Move the kitchen cabinets."
Hey, Jonah, bring some of
that stuff around, all right?
Do you like baseball?
Yes, I do. In fact my firm has box seats to
the Mariners. Why don't we all go some time.
Hey!
What about camping?
What about it?
Do you like camping?
I went camping once.
You know, Dad, we should
start camping more often.
You're right. Camping is good.
Time for bed.
It's only 10:00.
Yeah, 10:00. Time for bed.
Good night.
Hey, don't you wanna thank
Victoria for this delicious dinner?
Thanks for dinner. I never saw
anybody cook potatoes that way.
I'm glad you liked it.
Good night, Jonah.
Yeah, we don't see a lot of
potatoes around here. We're rice men.
Oh, God.
Oh! Oh! Ow.
I'm sorry, Walter. I'm sorry.
- Hello.
- Turn on your radio.
What? The kid is on.
You've got me listening to
this garbage. Go, turn it on.
Who is it?
It's Becky. She's having
trouble with Rick again.
I'll go downstairs.
Becky, I'll call you back.
I'm sorry, Walter.
Are you bleeding?
He's kissing her right this minute!
Oh, really?
Jonah, tell the truth:
Are you spying on your father?
- Who is he kissing?
- I have to make them stop.
How will I explain this to Walter?
She came over and cooked dinner.
She brought two bags of groceries
like she was staying here for a year!
Jonah, it's good that your
father's dating. It's just hard on you.
It's something you think you want,
but then when it happens, it scares you.
That's not true.
Okay, now think.
Shouldn't your father be the judge of
whether someone is right or wrong for him?
He's not sane enough
to judge anything.
Now he's kissing her on the lips. My dad's
been captured by a ho! What am I going to do?
Jonah, calm down. Tomorrow,
when you're sitting down to breakfast,
tell him how you feel. It's not good
to keep your feelings inside you.
Miss Scarlet. In the broom
closet. With the radio.
Walter, you scared me.
Don't ever do that again.
I thought I saw a black widow spider.
You scared me to death.
You scared Victoria to death.
It was right over there.
Next time you think you see a
black widow spider I want you to say:
"Dad, excuse me, but I believe a
poisonous insect is in the house."
And I will calmly come and take care of it.
You scream like that again, I'll kill you.
Becky heard this guy on the
radio, she was sure it was Rick.
She was completely hysterical.
And then it turned out the guy
lived in Duluth. Where's Duluth?
That doesn't make any sense.
I know. I know, Walter.
It doesn't make any sense at all.
Thank God my life is in place.
Duluth? That's in North Dakota.
I love this letter.
You have to write to her.
You think so?
It's Y-O-H. Yeah. What's that?
Your only hope.
I thought I would look into doing
a story on those radio shows.
You'd have to go somewhere
to really look into them.
Definitely.
Couldn't you do a phone interview?
Not for the kind of piece I wanna do.
I won't be in Chicago long.
When you get back, I'll be gone.
Then I'll see you in New York.
I'll get it.
- This is Captain Browning.
- We're cruising at 35,000 feet.
The weather is clear to the west
and we'll be in Seattle on schedule.
Don't you hate flying?
Yes, I do.
And I've just told the most terrible
one to the man I'm about to marry.
Do you feel that any lie is a betrayal?
I said flying. Oh.
Thanks for bringing me here.
Well, he likes the planes.
Can I bring something
back for you? A souvenir?
Does he like those little snow globes?
You know, you shake them up
and then the snow floats down.
Sure, I'd really like that.
Thank you so much.
He's 8. He's good at it.
I've read an article about this.
Children are hideous at the age of 8.
It's quite normal. Well...
Maybe when I come back, the two of us
ought to spend some time together
on our own. What do you think?
Bye. Bye, Jonah.
Bye.
Jonah.
Listen to me.
You don't know Victoria.
I hardly know her myself.
She's, in fact, a mystery to me.
She tosses her hair a lot.
Why does she do this?
I have no idea. Is it a twitch?
Does she need a haircut?
Could she use a barrette
to keep her hair out of her face?
These are the things I'm
willing to get to the bottom of.
That is why I am dating her.
That's all I'm doing. I'm not
living with her. I'm not marrying her.
Can you appreciate the difference?
This is what single people do. They
try other people on and see how they fit.
But everybody's an adjustment. Nobody's
perfect. There's no such thing as a perfect...
Come on.
Dad, I was talking to
Jessica about reincarnation.
She says you knew Annie in another life.
Who's Annie?
The one who wrote us.
But Jessica says, you and Annie
never got together in that life.
So your hearts are like
puzzles with missing pieces.
And when you get together,
the puzzle's complete.
Goddamn it.
The reason I know this and you don't,
is because I'm younger and pure, so
I'm more in touch with cosmic forces.
Who told you this stuff?
Jessica.
I sincerely hope you're
not marrying Jessica.
♪ I remember the days ♪
♪ Of just keeping time ♪
♪ Of hanging around ♪
♪ In sleepy towns forever ♪
♪ Back roads empty for miles ♪
♪ Well, you can't have a dream ♪
♪ And cut it to fit ♪
♪ But when I saw you, I knew ♪
♪ We'd go together ♪
♪ Like a wink and a smile ♪
♪ Leave your old jalopy ♪
♪ By the railroad track ♪
♪ We'll get a hip double-dip tip-toppy ♪
♪ Two-seat Pontiac ♪
♪ So you can rev her up ♪
♪ Don't go slow ♪
♪ It's only green lights and all rights ♪
♪ Let's go together ♪
♪ With a wink and a smile ♪
♪ Give me a wink and a smile ♪
♪ We go together ♪
♪ Like a wink and a smile ♪
♪ Now my heart is music ♪
♪ Such a simple song ♪
♪ Sing it again ♪
♪ The notes never end ♪
♪ This is where I belong ♪
♪ Just the sound of your voice ♪
♪ The light in your eyes ♪
♪ We're so far away from yesterday ♪
♪ Together with a wink and a smile ♪
♪ We go together ♪
♪ Like a wink and a smile ♪♪
I watched him play with
his son at the beach.
Did you talk to him?
Couldn't do it.
How did I get here?
You told a lie and got on a plane.
That's not what I mean.
I'm going back over there tomorrow
and talk to him. I am.
Okay. Good. Goodbye. Beck.
What?
Is this crazy?
No, that's the weirdest part about it.
Thank you. I love you.
I love you too.
Good night. Bye.
It's so good to see you.
Where's Greg?
Hello.
- So then what happened?
- So then I left, obviously.
You were standing in
the middle of the street?
You know that dream when you're walking down
the street naked and everyone is looking at you.
I love that dream.
That was nothing compared
to this humiliation. Nothing!
But he saw you, right?
He saw me.
You were face to face.
He said hello.
And what did you say?
And all I could say was hello.
Oh, my God.
All I could say was hello.
It's a sign.
It's a sign that I have watched
this movie too many times.
So stupid! From the minute
I listened to that stupid program me
on the radio, I've been a complete jerk.
You are not a jerk.
Thank you. An idiot!
You don't know who she was, Annie.
I saw her. I have a picture of her.
I'll show you a picture of her.
That detective in Seattle
sent me a picture of her.
Here! See, that's
exactly what she looks like.
This is a picture of someone's back.
Well, it's her and he was crazy about her.
What's this?
This is from Seattle.
Becky.
So I mailed your letter.
"Dear Annie. Thanks for
your letter. It was great."
You sound neat.
We're very excited about meeting you in New
York on Valentine's Day and seeing if we are...
M-F-E-O.
"See you soon.
Sleepless in Seattle."
M-F-E-O?
Made for each other.
It's cute. It's like a little clue.
So he can't write. Big deal.
Verbal ability is a highly
overrated thing in a guy.
And our pathetic need for it is
what gets us into so much trouble.
I'm going to run back to
Walter's arms, if he'll still have me.
What about the letter?
It's nothing. It was written before
I went out there. Before the ho.
The only thing is, she
didn't look like a ho.
She looked like somebody we
would have been friends with.
Ugh!
You saw her in the airport and then here?
And I tried to talk to her. It was like I
knew her or something. It was weird.
You mean like a déjà-vu thing?
It was very French déjà-vu-ish
kind of thing. Oui?
Oui. At least you're out there seeing
people again. That's terrific.
Well, I mean, there's really just the one.
Victoria.
You don't like Victoria?
She laughs like a hyena.
Is this true?
No!
Sort of. Yeah, a little bit.
But, tell them what you did.
- Dad...
- Tell them about the radio show.
Go ahead. Dad...
They wanna hear it. Go
ahead. Tell them. Tell them.
Christmas Eve, he phones in
one of those radio call-in shows.
And tells them I need a new wife.
Oh, you're kidding.
That's so sweet.
Now he's obsessed with
this one woman who wrote me.
Are you serious? Yeah.
She wants to meet me at the
top of Empire State Building.
On Valentine's Day.
It's like that movie.
What movie?
An Affair to Remember.
Did you ever see it?
Oh, God. Cary Grant and Deborah
Kerr. Is that "Karr" or "Kerr"?
Kerr. Karr.
Okay. She's gonna meet him at
the top of the Empire State Building.
Only she got hit by a taxi.
And he waited and waited.
And it was raining, I think.
And then she's too proud
to tell him that she's
crippled. And he's too proud
to find out why she doesn't come.
But he comes to see her anyway.
And I forget why, but...
Oh, it's so amazing
when he comes to see her.
Because he doesn't even notice
that she doesn't get up to say hello.
And he's very bitter.
You think he's just going to walk
out the door and never know why.
She's just lying there, you know.
Like, on the couch with this
blanket over her shrivelled little legs.
And...
Are you all right? She's fine.
And suddenly, he goes,
"I saw the painting".
And he, like, goes to the bedroom.
And he looks, and he
comes out and looks at her.
And he kind of just...
They know and hug and it's so...
That's a chick's movie.
I would say so.
What kind of a person would write
to someone they heard on the radio?
I got hundreds of letters
from women all over the country.
Desperate women.
Just because someone is looking for a
nice guy, it doesn't make them desperate.
How about rapacious
and love-starved?
No.
It's easier to be killed by a
terrorist than to find a husband
after the age of 40...
That is absolutely untrue!
Right, honey. Right.
Well, I'm not looking
for a mail-order bride.
I just want somebody that I can have
a decent conversation with over dinner.
You know, without it falling down into weepy
tears over some movie that she just saw.
She's very emotional.
Although, I cried at the
end of The Dirty Dozen.
Well, who didn't?
Jim Brown was throwing
these hand grenades down these air shafts.
And Richard Jaeckel and Lee Marvin we sitting
on top of this armoured personnel carrier.
They were dressed up like Nazis.
And it was...
Trini Lopez... Trini Lopez...
He busted his neck when they were
parachuting down behind the Nazi lines.
Stop it!
Richard Jaeckel, at the beginning, he had
on a shiny helmet, because he was an MP.
Please, no more.
God, I love that movie.
This is the best movie
I've ever seen in my life.
What's so great about it?
You have to find her, Jonah.
You have to go to her.
Do you know how much money
it costs to go to New York?
Nobody knows.
It changes practically every day.
How much money do you have?
80 dollars.
I have 42. That'll probably cover cabs.
But how would I get there?
Honey, I have to run these
tickets over to someone.
Can you keep an eye on things
out front till I get back?
Sure, Mum.
You want a window seat or aisle?
Window.
You want a fruit plate?
I don't know. Do I?
I'd rather die than eat airplane food.
I'm telling them you're 12
so you can fly unaccompanied
and the stewardess won't carry
you around and stuff like that.
Are you crazy?
Who'd believe I'm 12?
If it's in the computer,
they'll believe anything.
Are you sure?
Do you want me to say that you're
really, really short for your age,
and they shouldn't say anything
because it would hurt your feelings?
Yeah. That's a great idea!
♪ Sometimes it's hard to be a woman ♪
♪ Giving all your love to just one man ♪
Walter.
You're gonna miss the train.
No, I'm not.
I'm so happy, Becky. Finally, I
feel happy. This is right. This is real.
Everything else is what happens
when you watch too many movies.
And you completely
lose sight of what counts.
Please, don't tell anybody what happened.
Because I would be so absolutely
mortified if anyone knew I did anything
even remotely close to what I have done.
Thank you, thank you.
Do you promise?
I promise.
Sleepless in Seattle is history.
♪ ... hard to understand ♪
♪ And if you love him ♪
♪ Oh, be proud of him ♪
♪ 'Cause after all he's just a man ♪
♪ Stand by your man ♪♪
I was just... I was just...
Go ahead. No, you go.
Okay. Well, I was just gonna
say that ever since Christmas
you've been different,
kind of distracted, distant.
But now it feels as if you're coming
back from wherever you were.
I am.
I was just...
I just... I just got...
I think I got nervous.
But that's normal, right?
I mean, don't you ever
feel nervous about... you know?
What? Forever.
No.
Well...
I did.
And... You know what I think? I think
I thought it was too perfect, you know.
I started to wonder if
we were the human equivalent
of two rights making a wrong.
You know what it was?
It was like kismet, but not,
if you see what I mean.
You have to grow up.
You just can't keep having all
these adolescent fantasies about
how exciting life is gonna be.
Don't hate me, but I love this pattern.
You couldn't. I do.
This is just like my grandmother's china.
How many place settings?
Ten. Ten.
Exactly. Eight is too few,
twelve is.
Too many.
Walter. It was my mother's.
I had them size it down.
She had really fat fingers.
It's so beautiful.
It's exactly what I'd pick out
if I had every ring in the whole
world to choose from.
You see what I mean?
There are people who would like
a relationship to be full of surprises,
but I am not one of
those people. No, siree.
Surprises are highly overrated.
I'm leaving first thing
in the morning,
but I'm only gonna be gone one night.
Clarise is gonna be here.
So you'll be able to see plenty of Geraldo and
Nightmare on Elm Street 12. I will never know.
Are you going with her?
I'm going with Victoria, yes.
Don't try anything tricky.
Understand?
Don't go rolling in poison ivy
as soon as I leave the house.
Or lock yourself in the closet or do
anything that makes you need stitches.
If your finger falls off, it's staying off.
No one's gonna pack it on
ice and take you to hospital,
so that you can be a
breakthrough in laser surgery.
Is this about that woman in Baltimore?
Annie.
I don't care what you do!
Good! Fine!
I'll tell you what I'm doing this weekend.
I'm getting laid.
1990s and nobody's getting laid.
I'm the only man in the America
who's getting laid this weekend.
And I haven't been laid that much.
Six girls in college. Maybe seven.
How long have you been there?
Forever.
What did you hear me just say?
"Six girls in college.
Maybe seven."
Seven. Eight! Mary Kelly.
This is the one I like.
Jonah, the fact is, you're
not gonna like any woman,
because it isn't your mother.
How do you know?
What's wrong with Annie?
Oh, Jonah, shut up!
Shut up? Shut up? Mum
never said shut up to me.
Mum never yelled at me.
This conversation is finished.
Why can't we go to New York?
There is no way that
we are going on a plane
to meet some woman who
could be a crazy, sick lunatic.
Didn't you see Fatal Attraction?
You wouldn't let me.
Well, I saw it!
And it scared the shit out of me.
It scared the shit out of
every man in America!
I'm not leaving till you say yes.
I hate you! I hate you!
I hate you!
That's good!
You'll have a lot to tell Oprah
how your dad destroyed your life
because he had to go off for a
weekend special at the Holiday Inn!
Jonah, Clarise is here and I've got to go.
Hey, Jonah.
Jonah?
All right. Jonah, listen,
I've got to go.
Jonah.
Hey, Jonah.
Jonah!
Jessica, honey.
You have tell us where he is.
Jonah's daddy is very upset.
Jessica, this is your father. Tell
us where he is. Right this minute!
- N-Y.
- What is that?
"No way."
That's N-W!
New York. He's on
his way to New York.
What? How?
- United, 597.
- Jessica.
When does it leave?
Seven thirty.
Here you go.
Here's a nice pin for you
for flying with us. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Can I take this for you?
No.
Where to, kid?
Empire State Building.
Hold on.
Get a little further away
from the curb next time, mac.
There it is. What are you going
to do up there? Spit off the top?
No, I'm going to meet my new mother.
Excuse me. I'm Jonah.
Are you Annie?
No, I'm Cynthia.
Excuse me, are you Annie?
Great table. Thanks.
Is something wrong?
Can I get you a drink?
Some champagne?
Fine. Fine.
Can we have a bottle of Dom DeLuise.
Just kidding. It was a joke.
He meant Dom Perignon. I got it.
Ohh. Beautiful view.
Walter... There's
something I have to tell you.
Hey! Sorry, I have an emergency.
Money, money, money, see?
So he could be on top of
the Empire State Building now?
No.
I guess he could be.
It's not him, Walter. It's me.
I can't do this.
Look, Annie, I love you.
But let's leave that out of this.
I don't want to be someone
that you're settling for.
that anyone settles for.
Marriage is hard enough without
bringing such low expectations into it.
Isn't it?
Walter, I don't deserve you.
No, I wouldn't put it that way.
But okay.
You okay?
Yeah.
What? Look.
It's a sign. Who needed a sign?
Walter, I have to go.
Jonah!
Dad! Dad! Jonah?
What if something happened to you?
What if I couldn't get to you?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
What would I have done?
You are my family.
You're all I've got.
I thought she'd be here.
I thought she'd come.
We're doing okay, aren't we?
I mean, are we okay?
Aren't we all right? So far,
have I done anything stupid?
No.
Have I screwed it up for the both of us?
Observation deck?
Sorry, ma'am, but it's too late.
Oh. No, please.
I really need to get up there.
We're closing up.
No more runs tonight.
Listen
can I just take a look? There's
someone I was supposed to meet.
He's probably not there, but if I don't
at least look, I'll always wonder about it.
Cary Grant, right?
You know that movie?
It's one of my wife's favourites.
Maybe when we get home, we'll get a dog.
Okay.
What do you mean, okay?
- Wouldn't you like to have a dog?
- Sure.
I'm sorry, ma'am. Empty.
Can I take a minute? Go ahead.
I left it by the telescopes.
It's you. It's me.
I saw you in the street.
Are you Annie? Yes.
You're Annie?
This must be yours. I'm Jonah.
This is my dad. His name is Sam.
Hi, Jonah.
Sam.
And who's this? Howard.
Oh, Howard. Hello, Howard.
We'd better go.
Shall we?
♪ It's so important ♪
♪ To make someone happy ♪
♪ Make just one someone happy ♪
♪ Make just one heart to heart you ♪
♪ You sing to ♪
Sam, it's nice to meet you.
♪ One face that lights ♪
♪ When it nears you ♪
♪ One girl you're ♪
♪ You're everything to ♪
♪ Fail if you win it ♪
♪ Comes and goes in a minute ♪
♪ Where's the real stuff in life ♪
♪ To cling to ♪
♪ Love is the answer ♪
♪ Someone to love is the answer ♪
♪ Once you've found her ♪
♪ Build your world around her ♪
♪ Make someone happy ♪
♪ Make just one someone happy ♪
♪ And you will be happy too ♪♪
♪ When I fall in love ♪
♪ It will be forever ♪
♪ Or I'll never fall in love ♪
♪ I'll never, never fall in love ♪
♪ In a restless world ♪
♪ Like this is ♪
♪ Love is ended before it's begun ♪
♪ And too many ♪
♪ Moonlight kisses ♪
♪ Seem to cool ♪
♪ In the warmth of the sun ♪
♪ When I give my heart ♪
♪ It will be completely ♪
♪ Or I'll never give my heart ♪
♪ And the moment I can feel ♪
♪ That you feel that way too ♪
♪ Is when I fall in love ♪
♪ When I fall in love ♪
♪ With you ♪♪
♪ Give me a kiss ♪
♪ To build on and my imagination ♪
♪ Will thrive upon that kiss ♪
♪ Sweetheart I ask no more than this, ♪
♪ A kiss to build a dream on ♪
♪ Give me a kiss ♪
♪ Before you leave me ♪
♪ And my imagination ♪
♪ Will feed my hungry heart ♪
♪ Leave me one thing before we part ♪
♪ A kiss to build a dream on ♪