I should have known
that you would be here,
Professor McGonagall.
Good evening, Professor Dumbledore.
Are the rumors true,
Albus?
I am afraid so, professor.
The good...
and the bad.
And the boy?
Hagrid is bringing him.
Do you think it wise,
to trust Hagrid with something
as important as this?
Oh, professor,
I would trust Hagrid, with my life.
Professor Dumbledore, sir.
Professor McGonagall.
No problems, I trust Hagrid?
No, sir.
Little tyke fell asleep just
as we were flying over Bristol.
Try not to wake him.
There you go.
Albus,
do you really think it's safe,
leaving him with these people?
I have watched them all day.
They are the worst sort of Muggles,
imaginable.
They really are...
The only family he has.
This boy will be famous.
There won't be a child in our world
who doesn't know his name.
Exactly.
He is far better off,
growing up away from all of that.
Until he is ready.
There, there Hagrid.
It's not really goodbye, after all.
Good luck...
Harry Potter.
Up. Get up!
Now!
Wake up cousin!
We are going to the zoo!
Here he comes,
the birthday boy.
Happy birthday son.
Why don't you just cook the breakfast,
and try not to burn anything.
Yes, Aunt Petunia.
I want everything to be perfect...
for my Dudley's special day!
Hurry up!
Bring my coffee boy.
Yes Uncle Vernon.
Aren't they wonderful darling?
How many are there?
36.
Counted them myself.
36? But last year...
last year I had 37!
Yeah but some of them
are quite a bit bigger than last year's.
I don't care how big they are!
Oh, now, now, now.
This is what we are going to do...
is that when we go out,
we are going to buy you
two new presents.
How is that pumpkin?
It should be a lovely day at the zoo.
I am really looking forward to it.
I am warning you now boy.
Any funny business,
any at all,
and you won't have any meals,
for a week.
Get in.
Make it move.
Move!
He is asleep!
He is boring.
Sorry about him.
He doesn't understand what it's like,
lying there day after day...
watching people press
their ugly faces in on you.
Can you hear me?
It's just,
I have never talked to a snake before.
Do you...
I mean,
do you talk to people often?
You are from Burma, are not you?
Was it nice there?
Do you miss your family?
I see.
That's me as well.
I never knew my parents either.
Mummy, Dad, come here!
You won't believe
what this snake is doing!
Thanks.
Anytime.
Snake!
Mum! Mummy!
Help me!
Please, please.
My darling boy!
Help me! Help me!
How did you get in there?
Who did this? How did you get in there?
Is there a snake?
It's alright, sweetheart.
We will get you out of these cold clothes.
What happened?
I swear, I don't know!
One minute the glass was there
and then it was gone,
it was like magic.
There is no such thing as magic.
And smile!
Vernon, just look at him!
I can't believe it!
In just a week, he will be off to Smeltings.
Caveat Smeltonia.
Proudest moment of my life.
Will I have to wear that too?
What? You?
Go to Smeltings?
Don't be so stupid!
You are going to go to the state
school where you belong.
This is what you will going to be wearing
when I finish dyeing it.
That's Dudley's old uniform.
It will fit me like bits
of old elephant skin.
It will fit you well enough.
Go get the post.
Go!
Marge is ill. Ate a funny whelk.
Dad, look! Harry's got a letter!
Hey, give it back! It's mine!
Yours? Who would be writing to you?
No more mail through this letterbox.
Have a lovely day at the office, dear.
Shoo! Go on.
Fine day, Sunday.
In my opinion, best day of the week.
Why is that, Dudley?
Because there is no post on Sundays?
Right you are Harry!
No post on Sunday.
No blasted letters today!
No, sir.
Not one single bloody letter.
Not one!
No sir.
Not one blasted miserable...
No! Make it stop please!
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
Mummy, what's happening?
Give me that!
Give me that letter!
Get off!
They are my letters!
Let go of me!
That's it!
We are going away!
Far away!
Where they can't find us!
Daddy is gone mad, hasn't he?
Make a wish, Harry.
Who is there?
Sorry about that.
I demand that you leave at once, Sir!
You are breaking and entering!
Dry up, Dursley, you great prune.
Mind I have not seen you
since you was a baby Harry but...
you are a bit more along than I would have
expected particularly around the middle.
I am, I am not Harry.
I-I am.
Well, of course you are.
Got something for you.
Afraid I might have sat on it
at somepoint but...
I imagine it will taste fine just the same.
Baked it myself, words and all.
Thank you.
It's not every day that your young man
turns 11, now is it?
Hey...
Excuse me,
who are you?
Rubeus Hagrid,
Keeper of Keys and Grounds at Hogwarts.
Of course, you know all about Hogwarts.
Sorry, no.
No?
Blimey, Harry didn't you ever wonder
where your mum and dad learned it all?
Learnt what?
You are a wizard, Harry.
I am a what?
A wizard.
And a thumping good one, I would wager,
once you are trained up little.
No.
You have made a mistake, I mean...
I...
can't be a-a...
a wizard.
I mean I am...
just...
Harry.
Just Harry.
Well, Just Harry,
did you ever make anything happen?
Anything you could not explain,
when you were angry or...
or scared?
Dear Mr. Potter,
We are pleased to inform you
that you have been accepted
at Hogwarts School
of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
He will not be going there, I tell you!
We swore when we took him in
we would put a stop to all this rubbish.
You knew?
You knew all along
and you never told me?
Of course we knew.
How could you not be?
My...
perfect sister being who she was.
Oh, my mother and father were so...
proud the day she got her letter.
We have a witch in the family.
Isn't it wonderful?
I was the only one to see her
for what she was.
A freak!
Then she met that Potter,
and then she had you
and I knew you would be the same.
Just as strange, just as...
abnormal.
And then, if you please,
she went and got herself blown up!
And we got landed with you.
Blown up?
You told me my parents
died in a car crash.
A car crash?
A car crash killed Lily and James Potter?
We had to say something.
It's an outrage!
It's a scandal!
He will not be going.
Oh, and I suppose a great Muggle like yourself
is going to stop him, are you?
Muggle?
Non-magic folk.
This boy's had his name down
ever since he were born.
He is going to the finest school,
of witchcraft and wizardry
in the world, and...
he will be under the finest headmaster,
that Hogwarts has ever seen,
Albus Dumbledore.
I will not pay to have some crackpot
old fool teach him magic tricks.
Never...
insult Albus Dumbledore...
in front of me.
What's that tail!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
Oh...
I would appreciate it
if you didn't tell anyone...
at Hogwarts about that.
Strickly speaking,
I am not allowed to do magic.
Ok.
We are a bit behind schedule.
Best be off.
Unless you'd rather stay, of course.
First year students will require...
three sets of plain work robes...
one wand.
Essential bit of equipment, Harry.
One pair of dragon hide gloves.
Hagrid, do they mean from a real dragon?
Oh, they don't mean a penguin, do they?
Crikey.
I would love a dragon.
You would like a dragon?
Vastly misunderstood beasts, Harry.
Vastly misunderstood.
All students must be equipped with...
one standard size 2 pewter cauldron...
and may bring if they desire,
either an owl, a cat or a toad.
Can we find all this in London?
If you know where to go.
Hagrid!
The usual, I presume?
No thanks, Tom.
I am on official Hogwarts business.
Just helping young Harry here
buy his school supplies.
Bless my soul.
It's Harry Potter!
Welcome back, Mr. Potter.
Welcome back.
Doris Crockford, Mr Potter.
I can't believe I am meeting you at last.
Harry...
Potter.
Can't tell you how pleased
I am to meet you.
Hello professor.
I didn't see you there.
Harry, this is Professor Quirrell.
He will be your Defense Against
the Dark Arts teacher,
at Hogwarts.
Oh, nice to meet you.
Fearfully...
fascinating subject.
N... Not that you need it, eh... Potter.
Yes well,
must be going now.
Lots to buy.
Goodbye.
See Harry? You are famous.
But why am I famous Hagrid?
All those people back there,
how is it they know who I am?
I am not sure I am exactly the right person
to tell you that, Harry.
Welcome Harry,
to Diagon Alley.
Here is where you will get
your quills and your ink.
And over there, all your bits and bobs
for doing your wizardry.
It's a worldclass racing broom.
Look at it!
The new Nimbus 2000!
It's the fastest model yet.
But Hagrid,
how am I to pay for all this?
I have not any money.
Well there is your money, Harry.
Gringotts, the wizard bank.
Tain't no safer place, not one.
Except perhaps Hogwarts.
Hagrid?
What exactly are these things?
They are goblins, Harry.
Clever as they come goblins
but not the most friendly of beasts.
Best stay close.
Mr. Harry Potter wishes
to make a withdrawal.
And does Mr. Harry Potter
have his key?
Oh, wait a minute.
Got it here somewhere.
Here is the little devil.
Oh and there is something else as well.
Professor Dumbledore gave me this.
It's about You-Know-What,
in vault... You-Know-Which.
Very well.
Vault 687.
Lamp, please.
Key, please.
Didn't think your mum and dad
will leave you with nothing, now did you?
Vault 713.
What's in there Hagrid?
Can't tell you Harry.
Hogwarts business.
Very secret.
Stand back.
Best not to mention this to anyone Harry.
I still need...
a wand.
A wand?
Well, you will want Ollivanders.
There ain't no place better.
Why don't you run along there and wait.
I just got one more thing I got to do.
Won't be long.
Hello?
I wondered when
I would be seeing you, Mr. Potter.
It seems only yesterday,
that your mother and father were
in here buying their first wands.
Here we are.
Give it a wave.
Apparently not.
Perhaps...
this.
No, no, definitely not.
No matter.
I wonder...
Curious.
Very curious.
Sorry,
but what's curious?
I remember every wand
I have ever sold, Mr. Potter.
It so happens,
that the phoenix...
whose tail feather resides in your wand,
gave another feather.
Just one other.
It is curious that
you should be destined for this wand...
when its brother...
gave you that scar.
And who owned that wand?
We do not speak his name.
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
It's not always clear why.
But...
I think it is clear...
that we can expect great things from you.
After all,
He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named...
did great things.
Terrible...
yes...
but great.
Harry! Harry!
Happy birthday.
You alright, Harry?
You seem very quiet.
He killed my parents, didn't he?
The one who gave me this.
You know Hagrid.
I know you do.
First, and understand this Harry
because it's very important:
Not all wizards are good.
Some of them go bad.
A few years ago...
there was a one wizard
who went as bad as he can go.
His name was V...
Maybe if you wrote it down?
No, I can't spell it.
Alright.
Voldemort.
Voldemort?
It was dark times, Harry. Dark times.
Voldemort started
to gather some followers.
Brought them over to the Dark Side.
Anyone that stood up to him,
ended up dead.
Your parents fought against him.
Nobody lived once
he decided to kill them.
Nobody,
not one.
Except you.
Me?
Voldemort tried to kill...
me?
Yes.
That ain't no ordinary cut
on your forehead, Harry.
A mark like that only comes from being
touched by a curse,
and an evil curse at that.
What happened to V...
To You-Know-Who?
Well,
some say he died.
Codswallop, in my opinion.
Nope,
I reckon he is out there still...
too tired to carry on.
But one thing is absolutely certain.
Something about you
stumped him that night.
That's why you are famous.
That's why everybody knows your name.
You are the boy who lived.
What are you looking at?
Blimey, is that the time?
Sorry, Harry, I am gonna have to leave you.
Dumbledore will be wanting his...
Well, he will be wanting to see me.
Now...
your train leaves in 10 minutes.
Here is your ticket.
Stick to it, Harry that's very important.
Stick to your ticket.
Platform 9 3/4?
But Hagrid,
there must be a mistake.
This says platform 9 3/4.
There is no such thing, is there?
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Right on your left Madam.
Excuse me Sir.
Can you tell me where
I might find platform 9 3/4?
9 3/4?
Think you are being funny, do you?
It's the same every year,
packed with Muggles of course.
Come on!
Muggles?
Platform 9 3/4, this way.
Alright Percy,
you first.
Fred, you next.
He is not Fred, I am.
Honestly woman,
you call yourself our mother?
Oh, I am sorry, George.
I am only joking. I am Fred.
Excuse me.
Could, could you tell me...
how to...
How to get onto the platform?
Not to worry, dear.
It's Ron's first time to Hogwarts as well.
Now all you have got to do...
is walk straight at the wall,
between platforms 9 and 10.
Best do it at a bit of a run
if you are nervous.
Good luck.
Excuse me.
Do you mind?
Everywhere else is full.
Not at all.
I am Ron by the way.
Ron Weasley.
I am Harry. Harry Potter.
So...
it's true!
I mean,
do you really have the...
The...
The what?
Scar?
Wicked!
Anything off the trolley, dears?
No thanks.
I am all set.
We will take the lot.
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans?
They mean every flavor.
There is chocolate and peppermint,
and there is also...
spinach,
liver and tripe.
George sweared he got
a bogey flavoured one once!
These are not real
frogs, are they?
It's just a spell.
Besides, it's the cards you want.
Each pack's got a famous witch or wizard.
I have got about 500 myself.
Watch it!
Oh, that's rotten luck.
They ave only got one
good jump in them to begin with.
I have got Dumbledore!
I got about six of him.
Hey, he is gone!
Well, you can't expect him
to hang around all day,
can you?
This is Scabbers by the way.
Pathetic, isn't he?
Just a little bit.
Fred gave me a spell as
to turn him yellow.
Want to see?
Yeah.
Has anyone seen a toad?
A boy named Neville's lost one.
No.
Are you doing magic?
Let's see then.
Sunshine, daisies,
butter mellow.
Turn this stupid fat rat yellow.
Are you sure that's a real spell?
Well, it's not very good, is it?
Of course, I have only tried
a few simple ones myself...
but they ave all worked for me.
For example.
Oculus Reparo.
That's better, isn't it?
Holy cricket,
you are Harry Potter!
I am Hermione Granger.
And...
you are?
I am, Ron Weasley.
Pleasure.
You two better change into robes.
I expect we will be arriving soon.
You have got dirt on your nose, by the way.
Did you know?
Just there.
Right then!
First years!
This way please!
Come on now, first years don't be shy.
Come on now, hurry up. Out!
Hello Harry.
Hey Hagrid.
Right then. This way to the boats.
Come on now, follow me.
Wicked.
Welcome to Hogwarts.
Now, in a few moments,
you will pass through these doors,
and join your classmates.
But before you can take your seats,
you must be sorted into your houses.
They are Gryffindor,
Hufflepuff,
Ravenclaw,
and Slytherin.
Now, while you are here,
your house will be like your family.
Your triumphs will earn you points.
Any rule breaking,
and you will lose points.
At the end of the year,
the house with the most points
is awarded the house cup.
Trevor!
Sorry.
The Sorting Ceremony
will begin momentarily.
It's true then,
what they are saying on the train.
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts.
Harry Potter?
This is Crabbe,
and Goyle.
And I am Malfoy.
Draco Malfoy.
Think my name's funny, do you?
I have no need to ask yours.
Red hair...
and a handmedown robe?
You must be a Weasley.
We will soon find out
that some wizarding families
are better than others Potter.
You don't want to go making friends
with the wrong sort.
I can help you there.
I think I can tell the wrong sort
for myself, thanks.
We are ready for you now.
Follow me.
It's not real, the ceiling.
It's just bewitched
to look like the night sky.
I read about it in Hogwarts.
A History.
Alright, will you wait along here, please?
Now,
before we begin...
Professor Dumbledore would like
to say a few words.
I have a few start of term notices
I wish to announce.
The first years, please note...
that the Dark Forest is...
strictly forbidden to all students.
Also, our caretaker,
Mr. Filch,
has asked me to remind you...
that the third floor corridor,
on the right hand side,
is out of bounds...
to everyone who does not wish
to die a most painful death.
Thank you.
When I call your name,
you will come forth.
I shall place the Sorting Hat
on your head...
and you will be sorted into your houses.
Hermione Granger.
Oh, no.
Ok, relax.
Mental that one, I am telling you.
Right then...
right.
Ok.
Gryffindor!
Draco Malfoy.
Slytherin!
There isn't a witch or wizard who went bad
who was not in Slytherin.
Susan Bones.
Harry, what is it?
Nothing.
Nothing, I am fine.
Let's see...
I know!
Hufflepuff!
Ronald Weasley.
Another Weasley!
I know just what to do with you.
Gryffindor!
Harry Potter.
Difficult, very difficult.
Plenty of courage, I see.
Not a bad mind, either.
There is talent.
Oh, yes.
And a thirst to prove yourself.
But where to put you?
Not Slytherin.
Not Slytherin, eh?
Are you sure?
You could be great, you know.
It's all here, in your head.
And Slytherin will help you on the way
to greatnesses, no doubt about that.
No?
Well, if you are sure.
Please. Not Slytherin. Not Slytherin.
Not Slytherin.
Better be...
Gryffindor!
Your attention, please.
Let the feast...
begin.
I am half and half.
Me dad is a Muggle.
Mum is a witch.
Bit of a nasty shock for him
when he found out.
Say Percy,
who is that teacher
talking to Professor Quirrell?
Oh, that's Professor Snape,
head of Slytherin house.
What's he teach?
Potions.
But everyone knows,
its the Dark Arts he fancies.
He is been after Quirrell's job for years.
Hello!
How are you?
Welcome to Gryffindor.
Look, It's the Bloody Baron!
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
Have a nice summer?
Dismal. Once again, my request
to join the Headless Hunt
has been denied.
I know you.
You are Nearly Headless Nick.
I prefer Sir Nicholas, if you don't mind.
Nearly headless?
How can you be nearly headless?
Like this.
Gryffindors, follow me please.
Keep up. Thank you.
Ravenclaw, follow me.
This way.
This is the most direct path
to the dormitories.
Oh, and keep an eye on the staircases.
They like to change.
Keep up, please and follow me.
Quickly now, come on.
Come on.
That picture is moving.
Look at that one.
I think she fancies you.
Oh, look! Look!
Who is that girl?
Welcome to Hogwarts.
Password?
Caput Draconis.
Follow me, everyone.
Keep up.
Quickly, come on.
Gather around here.
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room.
Boys' dormitory is upstairs
and down to your left.
Girls, the same on your right.
You will find that your belongings
have already been brought up.
Made it! Made it!
Can you imagine the look on old
McGonagall's face, if we were late?
That was bloody brilliant!
Thank you for that assessment, Mr Weasley.
Perhaps, it would be more useful
if I were to transfigure
Mr. Potter and yourself
into a pocket-watch.
That way, one of you might be on time.
We got lost.
Then perhaps a map?
I trust you don't need one
to find your seats.
There will be no foolish wandwaving,
or silly incantations in this class.
As such,
I don't expect
many of you to appreciate,
the subtle science and exact art,
that is potion making.
However for those...
select few...
who possess...
the predisposition...
I can teach you,
how to bewitch the mind...
and ensnare the senses.
I can tell you how to bottle fame,
brew glory and even put a stopper...
in death.
Then again,
maybe some of you
have come to Hogwarts
in possession of abilities
so formidable
that you feel confident enough...
to not...
pay attention.
Mr. Potter.
Our...
new celebrity.
Tell me, what would I get if I added powdered root
of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?
You don't know?
Well, let's try again.
Where Mr Potter, would you look
if I asked you to find me a bezoar?
I don't know, Sir.
And what is the difference
between monkshood and wolfsbane?
I don't know, Sir.
Pity.
Clearly,
fame isn't everything...
is it, Mr. Potter?
Clearly, Hermione knows.
Seems a pity not to ask her.
Silence.
Put your hand down, you silly girl.
For your information Potter...
asphodel and wormwood
make a sleeping potion so,
powerful it is known
as the Draught of the Living Dead.
A bezoar is a stone,
taken from the stomach of a goat,
and it will save you from most poisons.
As for monkshood and wolfsbane,
they are the same plant,
which also goes by the name of aconite.
Well...
why are not you all copying this down?
And Gryffindors...
note that five points will be taken
from your house...
for your classmate's cheek.
Eye of rabbit,
harp string hum.
Turn this water into rum.
Eye of rabbit, harp string hum.
What's Seamus trying to do
to that glass of water?
Turn it into rum.
Actually managed a weak tea yesterday,
before...
Mail is here.
Can I borrow this?
Thanks.
Hey, look!
Neville is got a Remembrall.
I have read about those.
When the smoke turns red,
it means you have forgotten something.
The only problem is,
I can't remember what I have forgotten.
Hey Ron!
Somebody broke into Gringotts.
Listen.
Believed to be the work
of Dark wizards or witches unknown,
Gringotts goblins while acknowledging
the breach,
insist nothing was taken.
The vault in question number 713,
had in fact been emptied earlier
that very same day.
That's odd.
That's the vault Hagrid and I went to.
Good afternoon, class.
Good afternoon, Madam Hooch.
Good afternoon, Amanda.
Good afternoon.
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Everyone step up to the left side
of their broomstick.
Come on now, hurry up.
Stick your right hand over the broom
and say, up.
Up!
Up.
With feeling.
Up! Up!
Up!
Up.
Shut up, Harry.
Now,
once you have got hold of your broom,
I want you to mount it.
And grip it tight,
you don't wanna be sliding off the end.
When I blow my whistle,
I want each of you,
to kick off from the ground, hard.
Keep your broom steady,
hover for a moment...
then lean forward slightly,
and touch back down.
On my whistle.
Three, two...
Mr. Longbottom.
Mr-Mr-Mr-Mr. Longbottom!
Mr. Longbottom!
Down, down!
Neville!
Come back down this instant!
Help!
Mr. Longbottom.
Everyone out of the way!
Is he alright?
Oh dear, it's a broken wrist.
Poor boy. Come on now, up you get.
Everyone is to keep their feet
firmly on the ground while I take
Mr Longbottom to the hospital wing.
Understand?
If I see a single broom in the air...
the one riding it will find themselves out
of Hogwarts before they can say, Quidditch.
Did you see his face?
Maybe if the fat lump
had given this a squeeze,
he would have remembered
to fall on his fat arse.
Give it here Malfoy.
No.
I think I will leave it somewhere
for Longbottom to find.
How about on the roof?
What's the matter, Potter?
Bit beyond your reach?
Harry, no way!
You heard what Madam Hooch said.
Besides, you don't even know how to fly.
What an idiot.
Give it here Malfoy
or I will knock you off your broom!
Is that so?
Have it your way, then.
Nice going, Harry.
That was wicked, Harry!
Harry Potter!
Follow me.
You wait here.
Professor Quirrell, excuse me, excuse me.
Could I borrow Wood for a moment please?
Oh yes, of course.
Potter, this is Oliver Wood.
Wood, I have found you a Seeker.
Have you heard?
Harry Potter is the new Gryffindor Seeker.
I always knew he would do well.
Seeker?
But first years never make their house teams.
You must be the youngest
Quidditch player in...
A century,
according to McGonagall.
Hey, well done Harry.
Wood is just told us.
Fred and George are on the team too.
Beaters.
Our job is to make sure that you
don't get bloodied up too bad.
Can't make any promises, of course.
Rough game, Quidditch.
Brutal, but no one is died in years.
Someone will vanishes occasionally.
But they will turn up in a month or two.
Oh, go on Harry.
Quidditch is great.
Best game there is,
and you will be great too.
But I have never even played Quidditch.
What if I make a fool of myself?
You won't make a fool of yourself.
It's in your blood.
Harry,
you never told me your father
was a Seeker too.
I didn't know.
I am telling you, it's spooky.
She knows more about you than you do.
Who doesn't?
What's happening?
The staircases change,
remember?
Let's go this way.
Before the staircase moves again.
Does anybody feel like...
we should not be here?
We are not supposed to be here.
This is the third floor.
It's forbidden.
Let's go.
It's Filch's cat!
Run!
Quick,
let's hide through that door!
It's locked!
That's it, We are done for!
Oh, move over!
Alohomora.
Get in.
Alohomora?
Standard Book of Spells, chapter seven.
Anyone here, my sweet?
Come on.
Filch is gone.
Probably thinks this door is locked.
It was locked.
And for good reason.
What do they think they are doing?
Keeping a thing like that
locked up in a school.
You don't use your eyes, do you?
Didn't you see
what it was standing on?
I was not looking at its feet!
I was a bit preoccupied with its heads.
Or maybe you didn't notice.
There were three!
It was standing on a trap door.
Which means it was not there by accident.
It's guarding something.
Guarding something?
That's right.
Now, if you two don't mind,
I am going to bed...
before either of you come up with
another clever idea to get us killed.
Or worse, expelled.
She needs to sort out her priorities.
Quidditch, is easy enough to understand.
Each team has seven players.
Three Chasers,
two Beaters,
one Keeper and a Seeker.
That's you.
There are three kinds of balls.
This one is called the Quaffle.
Now the Chasers,
handle the Quaffle...
and try to put it through one
of those three hoops.
The Keeper, that's me,
defends the hoops.
With me so far?
I think so.
What are those?
You better take this.
Careful now, it's coming back.
Not bad Potter.
You would make a fair Beater.
What was that?
Bludger.
Nasty little buggers.
But you...
are a Seeker.
The only thing,
I want you to worry about...
is this.
The Golden Snitch.
I like this ball.
You like it now.
Just wait.
It's wicked fast
and damn near impossible to see.
What do I do with it?
You catch it.
Before the other team's Seeker.
You catch this, the game is over.
You catch this Potter,
and we win.
One of a wizard's most rudimentary skills
is levitation,
or...
the ability to make objects, fly.
Do you have your feathers?
Good.
Now,
don't forget the nice wrist movement
we have been practicing.
The swish and flick.
Everyone.
Good.
Oh, and enunciate.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Off you go, then.
Wingardium Leviosar.
No, stop, stop, stop!
You are going to take someone is eye out.
Besides, you are saying it wrong.
It's Leviosa,
not Leviosar.
You do it then, if you are so clever.
Go on, go on.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Oh, well done!
See here everyone,
Miss Granger is done it!
Splendid!
Wingardium Leviosa.
Well done, dear.
Wingar...
I think we are going to need
another feather over here, Professor.
It's Leviosa,
not Leviosar.
She is a nightmare, honestly!
No wonder she hasn't got any friends.
I think she heard you.
Where is Hermione?
Parvati Patil said that she would not
come out of the girl's bathroom.
She said that she had been in there
all afternoon, crying.
Troll!
In the dungeon!
Troll in the dungeon!
Thought you ought to know.
Silence!
Everyone will please,
not panic!
Now...
prefects,
will lead their house
back to the dormitories.
Teachers,
will follow me to the dungeons.
Gryffindors keep up,
please and stay alert.
How could a troll get in?
Not on its own.
Trolls are really stupid.
Probably people playing jokes.
What?
Hermione!
She doesn't know.
I think the troll's left the dungeon.
It's going into the girl's bathroom.
Hermione, move!
Help!
Hey,
pea brain!
Help!
Do something!
What?
Anything!
Hurry up!
Swish and flick.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Cool.
Is it... dead?
I don't think so.
Just knocked out.
Troll bogies.
Ok.
Oh, my goodness!
Explain yourselves, both of you!
Well, what it is...
It's my fault, Professor McGonagall.
Miss Granger?
I went looking for the troll.
I had read about them
and thought I could handle it.
But I was wrong.
If Harry and Ron had not come
and found me,
I would probably be dead.
Be that as it may,
it was an extremely foolish thing to do.
I would have expected more
rational behavior on your part
and am very disappointed
in you, Ms. Granger.
Five points will be taken
from Gryffindor...
for your serious lack of judgment.
As for you two gentlemen...
I just hope you realize
how fortunate you are.
Not many first year students
could take on a full grown mountain troll...
and live to tell the tale.
Five points...
will be awarded to each of you...
for sheer dumb luck.
Perhaps you ought to go.
It might wake up.
Good of you to get us
out of trouble like that.
Mind you, we did save her life.
Mind you, she might not have needed saving
if you had not insulted her.
What are friends for?
Take a bit of toast, mate. Go on.
Ron is right Harry.
You are gonna need your strength today.
I am not hungry.
Good luck today, Potter.
Then again, now that you have
proven yourself against a troll.
A little game of Quidditch
should be easy work for you.
Even if it is against, Slytherin.
That explains the blood.
Blood?
Listen, last night.
I am guessing Snape let
the troll in as a diversion.
So he could try and get past
that 3 headed dog.
But,
he got himself bitten,
that's why he is limping.
But why would anyone go near that dog?
The day I was at Gringotts, Hagrid took
something out of one of the vaults.
He said it was Hogwarts business,
very secret.
So you are saying...
That's what the dog is guarding.
That's what Snape wants.
Bit early for mail, isn't it?
But I... I never get mail.
Let's open it.
It's a broomstick.
That's not just a broomstick, Harry,
it's a Nimbus 2000!
But who...?
Scared Harry?
A little.
That's alright.
I felt the same way
before my first game.
What happened?
I don't really remember.
I took a Bludger to the head
two minutes in.
Woke up in the hospital a week later.
Hello! Welcome to Hogwarts' first
Quidditch game of the season.
Today is game,
Slytherin versus Gryffindor!
The players take their positions
as madam Hooch
steps out onto the field,
to begin the game!
Now, I want a nice, clean game...
from all of you!
The Bludgers are up,
followed by the Golden Snitch.
Remember the Snitch
is worth 150 points.
The Seeker who catches the Snitch
ends the game.
The Quaffle is released,
and the game begins!
Angelina Johnson scores!
Ten points for Gryffindor!
Yes.
Well done!
Slytherin takes possession of the Quaffle.
Bletchley passes to Captain Marcus Flint.
Yes.
Another 10 points to Gryffindor!
Give me that!
Take that side!
What's going on
with Harry's broomstick?
It's Snape.
He is jinxing the broom!
Jinxing the broom?
What do we do?
Leave it to me.
Come on, Hermione!
Lacarnum lnflamarae.
Fire!
You are on fire!
Go, go, go, go!
Looks like he is gonna be sick.
He is got the Snitch!
Harry Potter receives 150 points
for catching the Snitch!
Gryffindor wins!
Yes!
Nonsense!
Why would Snape
put a curse on Harry's broom?
Who knows?
Why was he trying to get past
that three-headed dog on Halloween?
Who told you about Fluffy?
Fluffy?
That thing has a name?
Of course he is got a name. He is mine.
I bought him off an Irish feller
I met down at the pub last year.
Then I lent him to Dumbledore
to guard the...
Yes?
Shouldn't have said that.
No more questions!
Don't ask any more questions.
That's top secret, that is.
But Hagrid,
whatever Fluffy is guarding,
Snape is trying to steal it.
Codswallop.
Professor Snape is a Hogwarts teacher.
Hogwarts teacher or not,
I know a spell when I see one.
I have read all about them.
You have got to keep eye contact,
and Snape was not blinking.
Exactly.
Now you listen to me,
all three of you.
You are meddling in things that ought
not to be meddled in.
It's dangerous.
What that dog is guarding is strictly
between Prof. Dumbledore
and Nicholas Flamel.
Nicholas Flamel?
I should not have said that.
Nicholas Flamel.
Who is Nicholas Flamel?
I don't know.
♪ Merry Christmas spell ♪
♪ Merry Christmas ring the Hogwart bell ♪
♪ Merry Christmas Merry Christmas. ♪
♪ Cast a Christmas spell. ♪
Knight to E5.
Queen to E5.
That's totally barbaric!
That's wizard's chess.
I see you have packed.
I see you have not.
Change of plans. My parents decided
to go to Romania,
to visit my brother Charlie.
He is studying dragons there.
Good. You can help Harry then.
He is going to go and look in the library,
for information on Nicholas Flamel.
We have looked a hundred times!
Not in the restricted section.
Happy Christmas.
I think we have had
a bad influence on her.
Harry, wake up!
Come on Harry, wake up!
Happy Christmas, Harry.
Happy Christmas, Ron.
What are you wearing?
Oh, my mum made it.
Looks like you have got one too.
I have got presents?
Yeah.
There they are.
Your father left this
in my possession before he died.
It is time it was returned to you.
Use it well.
What is it?
Some kind of cloak.
Well, let's see then. Put it on.
My body is gone!
I know what that is.
That's an invisibility cloak!
I am invisible?
They are really rare.
I wonder who gave it to you.
There was no name.
It just said...
Use it well.
Famous FireEaters.
FifteenthCentury Fiends.
Flamel.
Nicholas Flamel.
Where are you?
Who is there?
I know you are in there.
You can't hide.
Who is it?
Show yourself.
Severus, I...
You don't want me
as your enemy, Quirrell.
I don't know what you mean.
You know perfectly well what I mean.
We will have another little chat soon.
When you have had time to decide
where your loyalties lie.
Professors.
I found this, in the restricted section.
It's still hot.
That means there is a student out of bed.
Mum?
Dad?
Ron?
You have really got to see this!
Ron, you have got to see this!
Ron?
Ron, come on, get out of bed!
Why?
There is something you have got to see.
Now, come on!
Come on! Come!
Come look, it's my parents!
I only see us.
Look in properly.
Go on, stand there.
There.
You see them, don't you?
That's me!
Only I am head boy.
And I am holding the Quidditch Cup.
And bloody hell!
I am Quidditch captain too!
I look good.
Harry,
do you think this mirror shows the future?
How can it?
Both my parents are dead.
Do you like yours, Ron?
Ron?
I will be right back.
Wanna play chess?
No.
Wanna go and visit Hagrid?
Harry, I know what you are thinking,
but don't.
There is something not right
about that mirror.
Back again, Harry?
I see that you,
like so many before you...
have discovered the delights
of the Mirror of Erised.
I trust by now you realize what it does.
Let me give you a clue.
The happiest man on earth...
would look into the mirror
and see only himself...
exactly as he is.
So then, it shows us what we want.
Whatever we want.
Yes.
And no.
It shows us, nothing more or less...
than the deepest and most...
desperate desires of our hearts.
Now you, Harry,
who have never known your family...
you see them...
standing beside you.
But remember this, Harry.
This mirror...
gives us neither...
knowledge...
or truth.
Men have wasted away in front of it.
Even gone mad.
That is why, tomorrow...
it will be moved to a new home.
And I must ask you...
not to go looking for it again.
It does not do to dwell on dreams, Harry...
and forget to live.
Hi, Hedwig.
Look at you,
playing with your cards.
Pathetic!
We have got final exams coming up soon.
I am ready.
Ask me any question.
Alright, what are the 3 most crucial
ingredients in a Forgetfulness Potion?
I forgot.
And what may I ask, do you plan to do
if this comes up in the final exam?
Copy off you.
No, you won't.
Besides, according to Professor McGonagall,
we are to be given special quills
bewitched with an AntiCheating Spell.
That's insulting!
It's as if they don't trust us!
Dumbledore again!
LegLocker Curse?
Malfoy.
You have got to start
standing up to people, Neville.
How?
I can barely stand at all!
I will do the countercurse!
No, that's all I need!
You to set my bloody kneecups on fire!
I don't appreciate
the insinuation Longbottom.
Besides,
if anyone cared to notice...
my eyebrows have completely grown back!
I found him!
Dumbledore is particularly famous
for his defeat
of the dark wizard Grindelwald in 1945.
Go on!
For the discovery of the twelve uses
of dragon blood...
and his work on alchemy
with his partner, Nicholas Flamel!
I knew the name sound familiar.
I read it on the train that day.
Follow me!
Hey!
Wait!
Where are you going?
What about the countercurse?
I had you looking in the wrong section.
How could I be so stupid?
I checked this out weeks ago
for a bit of light reading.
This is light?
Of course!
Here it is!
Nicholas Flamel is the only known maker
of the Sorcerer's Stone.
The what?
Honestly, don't you two read?
The Sorcerer's Stone
is a legendary substance,
with astonishing powers.
It will transform any metal into pure gold...
and produces the Elixir of Life...
which will make the drinker immortal.
Immortal?
It means you will never die.
I know what it means!
The only Stone currently in existence
belongs to Mr. Nicholas Flamel...
the noted alchemist,
who last year celebrated
his 665th birthday.
That's what Fluffy is guarding
on the 3rd floor.
That's what's under the trap door.
The Sorcerer's Stone.
Hagrid.
Oh hello.
Sorry, don't wish to be rude,
but I am in no fit state to entertain today.
We know about the Sorcerer's Stone.
We think Snape is trying to steal it.
Snape?
Blimey, you are not
still on about him, are you?
Hagrid, we know he is after the Stone.
We just don't know why.
Snape is one of the teachers
protecting the Stone.
He is not about to steal it.
What?
You heard.
Right. Come on now,
I am a bit preoccupied today.
Wait a minute.
One of the teachers?
Of course!
There are other things
defending the Stone,
are not there?
Spells, enchantments.
That's right.
Waste of bloody time, if you ask me.
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy.
Ain't a soul knows how,
except for me and Dumbledore.
I should not have told you that.
Hagrid,
what exactly is that?
That? It's...
It's...
I know what that is!
But Hagrid,
how did you get one?
I won it.
Off a stranger I met down at the pub.
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it,
as a matter of fact.
Is that...
a dragon?
That's not just a dragon.
That's a Norwegian Ridgeback.
My brother Charlie works
with these in Romania.
Isn't he beautiful?
Oh, bless him.
Look, he knows his mummy.
Hello, Norbert.
Norbert?
Yeah well, he is got
to have a name, don't he?
Don't you, Norbert?
He will have to be trained up a bit,
of course.
Who is that?
Malfoy.
Oh, dear.
Hagrid always wanted a dragon.
He told me so the first time I met him.
It's crazy.
And worse, Malfoy knows.
I don't understand.
Is that bad?
It's bad.
Good evening.
Nothing, I repeat, nothing...
gives a student the right
to walk about the school at night.
Therefore, as punishment for your actions,
50 points will be taken.
50?
Each.
And to ensure it doesn't happen again...
all four of you will receive detention.
Excuse me professor,
perhaps I heard you wrong.
I thought you said the four of us.
No, you heard me correctly, Mr. Malfoy.
You see, honorable as your intentions were,
you too were out of bed after hours.
You will join your classmates
in detention.
A pity they let
the old punishments die.
There was a time detention would find you
hanging by your thumbs in the dungeons.
God, I miss the screaming.
You will be serving detention
with Hagrid tonight.
He is got a little job to do...
inside the Dark Forest.
A sorry lot this Hagrid.
Oh, good God, man, you are not still on
about that bloody dragon, are you?
Norbert is gone.
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania,
to live in a colony.
Well, that's good, isn't it?
He will be with his own kind.
Yeah, but what if he don't like Romania?
What if the other dragons
are mean to him?
He is only a baby, after all.
Oh, for God's sake,
pull yourself together, man.
You are going into the Forest, after all.
Got to have your wits about you.
The Forest?
I thought that was a joke.
We can't go in there.
Students are not allowed.
And there are...
werewolves.
There is more than werewolves
in those trees, lad.
You can be sure of that.
Nightynight.
Right.
Let's go.
Hagrid, what is that?
What we are here for.
See that?
That's unicorn blood, that is.
I found one dead a few weeks ago.
Now,
this one is been hurt bad by something.
So,
it's our job...
to go and find the poor beast.
Ron, Hermione, you will come with me.
Ok.
And Harry,
you will go with Malfoy.
Ok. Then I get Fang.
Fine.
Just so you know,
he is a bloody coward.
You wait till my father hears about this.
This is servant's stuff.
If I didn't know better, Draco,
I would say you were scared.
I am not scared, Potter.
Did you hear that?
Come on, Fang.
Scared!
What is it, Fang?
Harry Potter, you must leave.
You are known to many creatures here.
The Forest is not safe at this time.
Especially for you.
What was that thing you saved me from?
A monstrous creature.
It is a terrible crime to slay a unicorn.
Drinking the blood of a unicorn will keep
you alive even if you are an inch from death.
But at a terrible price.
You have slain something so pure...
that from the moment the blood touches
your lips,
you will have a halflife.
A cursed life.
But who would choose such a life?
Can you think of no one?
Do you mean to say...
that thing that killed the unicorn...
that was drinking its blood,
that was Voldemort?
Do you know what is hidden in the school
at this very moment, Mr. Potter?
The Sorcerer's Stone.
Harry!
Hello there, Firenze.
See you have met our young Mr. Potter.
You alright there, Harry?
Harry Potter,
this is where I leave you.
You are safe now.
Good luck.
You mean You-Know-Who
is out there right now in the Forest?
But he is weak.
He is living off the unicorns.
Don't you see?
We had it wrong.
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself.
He wants the stone for Voldemort.
With the Elixir of Life,
Voldemort will be strong again.
He will...
come back.
But if he comes back...
you don't think he will try to...
kill you, do you?
I think if he would had the chance,
he might have tried to kill me tonight.
And to think,
I have been worrying
about my Potions final.
Hang on a minute.
We are forgetting one thing.
Who is the one wizard
Voldemort always feared?
Dumbledore.
As long as Dumbledore is around Harry,
you are safe.
As long as Dumbledore is around,
you can't be touched.
I had always heard Hogwarts'
end of the year exams
were frightful but,
I found that rather enjoyable.
Speak for yourself.
Alright there Harry?
My scar.
It keeps burning.
It's happened before.
Not like this.
Perhaps you should see the nurse.
I think it's a warning.
It means danger is coming.
Of course!
What is it?
Don't you think it's a bit odd,
that what Hagrid wants more
than anything is a dragon...
and a stranger turns up who
just happens to have one?
I mean, how many people wander around
with dragon eggs in their pockets?
Why didn't I see it before?
Hagrid, who gave you the dragon egg?
What did he look like?
I don't know, I never saw his face.
He kept his hood up.
The stranger though.
You and he must have talked.
Well he...
he wanted to know what sort
of creatures I looked after.
I told him. I said after Fluffy,
a dragon is gonna be no problem.
And did he seem interested in Fluffy?
Well, of course he was interested in Fluffy.
How often do you come across
a three headed dog,
even if you are in the trade?
But I told him. I said...
I said the trick with any beast,
is to know how to calm him.
Take Fluffy, for example.
Just play him a bit of music
and he falls straight to sleep.
I should not have told you that.
Where are you going? Wait!
We have to see Professor Dumbledore.
Immediately!
I am afraid Professor Dumbledore is not here.
He received an urgent owl from the
Ministry of Magic
and left immediately for London.
He is gone? Now?
But this is important!
This is about the Sorcerer's Stone!
How do you know?
Someone is going to try and steal it.
I don't know how you three
found out about the stone,
but I assure you it is
perfectly well protected.
Now would you go back
to your dormitories?
Quietly.
That was no stranger Hagrid
met in the village. It was Snape.
Which means he knows
how to get past Fluffy.
And with Dumbledore gone...
Good afternoon.
Now, what would three young
Gryffindors
such as yourselves be doing inside...
on a day like this?
We were just...
You ought to be careful.
People will think you are...
up to something.
Now what do we do?
We go down the trap door.
Tonight.
Trevor.
Trevor!
Go! You should not be here!
Neither should you.
You are sneaking out again, are not you?
Now Neville, listen.
We were...
No.
I won't let you!
You will get Gryffindor into trouble again.
I... will fight you.
Neville, I am really
really sorry about this.
Petrificus Totalus.
You are a little scary sometimes,
you know that?
Brilliant,
but scary.
Let's go.
Sorry.
It's for your own good, you know.
You stood on my foot!
Sorry.
Alohomora.
Wait a minute. He is...
snoring.
Snape is already been here.
He is put a spell on the harp.
It's got horrible breath.
We have to move its paw.
What?
Come on!
Ok.
Push.
I will go first.
Don't follow until I give you a sign.
If something bad happens,
get yourselves out.
Does it seem a bit...
quiet to you?
The harp.
It's stopped playing.
Jump!
Lucky this plant thing is here, really.
Stop moving, both of you.
This is Devil's Snare.
You have to relax.
If you don't,
it will only kill you faster.
Kill us faster?
Oh, now I can relax!
Hermione!
Now what are we gonna do?
Just relax!
Hermione, where are you?
Do what I say!
Trust me.
Harry?
Are you ok?
Yeah, yeah I am fine.
He is not relaxing, is he?
Apparently not.
We have got to do something.
What?
I remember reading something
in Herbology.
Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare.
It's deadly fun...
but will sulk in the sun!
That's it!
Devil Snare hates sunlight.
Lumus Solem.
Ron you ok?
Yeah.
Lucky we didn't panic.
Lucky Hermione pays attention
in Herbology.
What is that?
I don't know.
Sounds like wings.
Curious.
I have never seen birds like these.
They are not birds.
They are keys.
And I will bet one of them
fits that door.
What's this all about?
I don't know.
Strange.
Alohomora!
Well, it was worth a try.
What're we going to do?
There must be a thousand keys up there.
We are looking for a big old fashioned one.
Probably rusty like the handle.
There! I see it!
The one with the broken wing.
What's wrong Harry?
It's too simple.
Oh go on Harry!
If Snape could catch it
on that old broomstick, you can.
You are the youngest Seeker
in a century.
This complicates things a bit.
Catch the key!
Hurry up!
I don't like this.
I don't like this at all.
Where are we?
A graveyard.
This is no graveyard.
It's a chessboard.
There is the door.
Now what do we do?
It's obvious, isn't it?
We have got to play
our way across the room.
Alright.
Harry, you take
the empty bishop's square.
Hermione, you will be
the queenside castle.
As for me,
I will be a knight.
What happens now?
Well, white moves first.
And then...
we play.
Ron,
you don't suppose
this is going to be like...
real wizard's chess, do you?
You there, D5.
Yes, Hermione.
I think this is gonna be...
exactly like wizard's chess.
Castle to E4!
Pawn to C3!
Wait a minute.
You understand right, Harry.
Once I make my move,
the queen will take me.
Then you are free, to check the king.
No. Ron, no!
What is it?
He is going to sacrifice himself.
No, you can't!
There must be another way!
Do you wanna stop Snape
from getting that Stone or not?
Harry, it's you that has to go on.
I know it.
Not me. Not Hermione.
You.
Knight to H3.
Check.
Ron!
No, don't move!
Don't forget,
we are still playing.
Checkmate.
Take care of Ron.
Then go to the owlery.
Send a message to Dumbledore.
Ron is right.
I have to go on.
You will be ok, Harry.
You are a great wizard.
You really are.
Not as good as you.
Me?
Books and cleverness.
There are more important things.
Friendship and bravery.
And Harry, just be careful.
You?
No,
it can't be.
Snape, he
He was the...
Yes,
he does seem the type, doesn't he?
Next to him, who would suspect...
Po-po-po-poor,
stu-stu-stuttering Professor Quirrell?
But, that day,
during the Quidditch match,
Snape tried to kill me.
No, dear boy.
I tried to kill you!
And trust me,
if Snape's cloak had not caught
fire and broken my eye contact...
I would have succeeded.
Even with Snape muttering
his little countercurse.
Snape was trying to save me?
I knew you were a danger
to me right from the off.
Especially after Halloween.
Then you, then you let the troll in!
Very good Potter, yes.
Snape, unfortunately, was not fooled.
While everyone else was running about dungeon,
he went to the third floor to head me off.
He, of course,
never trusted me again.
He rarely left me alone.
But he doesn't understand.
I am never alone.
Never.
Now,
what does this mirror do?
I see what I desire.
I see myself holding the Stone.
But how do I get it?
Use the boy.
Come here, Potter!
Now!
Tell me,
what do you see?
What is it? What do you see?
I am shaking hands with Dumbledore.
I have won the house cup.
He lies.
Tell the truth!
What do you see?
Let me speak to him.
Master, you are not strong enough.
I have strength enough for this.
Harry Potter...
we meet again.
Voldemort.
Yes.
You see what I have become?
See what I must do to survive?
Live off another.
A mere parasite.
Unicorn blood can sustain me...
but it cannot give me
a body of my own.
But there is something that can.
Something that conveniently enough,
lies in your pocket.
Stop him!
Don't be a fool.
Why suffer an horrific death...
when you can join me...
and live?
Never!
Bravery.
Your parents had it too.
Tell me...
Harry...
would you like to see
your mother and father again?
Together...
we can bring them back.
All I ask...
is for something in return.
That's it, Harry.
There is no good and evil.
There is only power...
and those too weak to seek it.
Together,
we will do extraordinary things.
Just give me the Stone!
You liar!
Kill him!
What is this magic?
Fool, get the Stone!
Good afternoon, Harry.
Tokens...
from your admirers?
Admirers?
What happened down
in the dungeons between you
and Professor Quirrell
is a complete secret.
So,
naturally,
the whole school knows.
I see that your friend Ronald
has saved you the...
trouble of opening your...
Chocolate Frogs.
Ron was here?
Is he alright?
What about Hermione?
Fine.
They are both just fine.
What happened to the Stone?
Relax dear boy.
The Stone has been destroyed.
My friend Nicholas and I
have had a little chat...
and agreed...
it was best...
all around.
But then Flamel,
he will die, won't he?
He has enough...
Elixir to set his affairs in order.
But yes,
he will die.
How is it I got the Stone, sir?
One minute I was staring
in the mirror and the next...
You see,
only a person...
who wanted to find the Stone,
find it...
but not use it,
would be able to get it.
That is one of my more brilliant ideas.
And between you and me,
that is saying something.
Does that mean,
with the Stone gone that is,
that Voldemort can never come back?
I am afraid...
there are ways in which he can return.
Harry,
do you know why...
Professor Quirrell could not bear
to have you touch him?
It was because of your mother.
She sacrificed herself for you.
And that kind of act leaves a mark.
No,
this kind of mark cannot be seen.
It lives, in your very skin.
What is it?
Love, Harry.
Love.
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans.
I was most unfortunate in my youth
to come across a vomit flavored one.
And since then, I am afraid,
I have lost my liking for them.
But I think...
I could be safe...
with a nice toffee.
Alas!
Earwax.
Alright there, Ron?
Alright. You?
Alright.
Hermione?
Never better.
Another year gone.
And now as I understand it,
the house cup needs awarding.
And the points stand thus.
In fourth place,
Gryffindor with 312 points.
Third place,
Hufflepuff...
with 352 points.
In second place...
Ravenclaw,
with 426 points.
And in first place...
with 472 points,
Slytherin house.
Nice one, mate.
Yes, yes, well done Slytherin.
Well done Slytherin, however...
recent events,
must be taken into account.
And I have a few...
last minute points to award.
To Miss...
Hermione Granger,
for the cool use of intellect...
while others were in grave peril...
50 points.
Good job.
Second,
to Mr. Ronald Weasley,
for the best played game of chess...
that Hogwarts...
has seen these many years,
50 points.
And third...
to Mr. Harry Potter...
for pure nerve
and outstanding courage...
I award Gryffindor house...
60 points.
We are tied with Slytherin!
And finally,
it takes a great deal of bravery
to stand up to your enemies...
but a great deal more
to stand up to your friends.
I award...
10 points...
to Neville Longbottom.
Assuming that my calculations
are correct I believe...
that a change of decoration...
is in order.
Gryffindor wins...
the house cup.
Yes!
Come on, now.
Hurry up, you will be late.
Train is leaving. Go on. Go on.
Come on, hurry up.
Come on, Harry.
One minute.
Thought you were leaving
without saying goodbye, did you?
This is for you.
Thanks, Hagrid.
Go on. On with you. On with you now.
On with you.
Oh, listen Harry.
If that dolt of a cousin of yours,
Dudley, gives you any grief...
you could always...
threaten him...
with a nice pair of ears to go with that,
tail of his.
But Hagrid,
we are not allowed to do magic
away from Hogwarts.
You know that.
I do.
But your cousin don't, do he?
Feels strange to be going home,
doesn't it?
I am not going home.
Not really.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections May 2022