[inhales]
[shrill scream]
- WHERE ARE THEY?
- [distantly]
DAD! UNCLE MERRILL!
- DAD!
- MORGAN!
[birds crying]
- BO? BO, BO.
WHERE'S MORGAN?
BO.
- ARE YOU IN MY DREAM TOO?
- THIS IS NOT A DR--
- DAD!
- HEY!
- HONEY...
- MORGAN?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
- THE DOGS WERE BARKING--
WOKE US UP.
- ARE YOU HURT?
- I THINK GOD DID IT.
- DID WHAT, MORGAN?
[dogs barking distantly,
birds screeching]
[barking, whimpering]
LOOK, LEE, I DON'T EVEN CARE
IF IT WAS HIM.
AND YOU CAN JUST
HAVE A WORD WITH HIM,
AND THAT'D BE ENOUGH FOR ME.
SEE, IT WAS STRANGE FINDING
THE CROPS THAT WAY.
THE KIDS WERE CONFUSED BY IT,
AND, UH,
IT'D SURE TAKE
THE STRANGENESS AWAY
IF I KNEW IT WAS JUST LIONEL
AND THE WOLFINGTON BROTHERS
MESSING AROUND, THAT'S ALL.
AT THE MOVIES?
ARE YOU SURE?
[sighing]
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
UH, THANKS FOR
YOUR PATIENCE, LEE.
YEAH.
BYE.
[beep]
- HOUDINI PEED.
I THINK HE'S SICK.
- WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE HIM OUTSIDE?
I'LL CALL DR. CRAWFORD.
- HE DOESN'T TREAT ANIMALS.
- WELL, HE'LL KNOW WHAT TO DO.
OH.
THAT WAS QUICK, CAROLINE.
I ONLY CALLED YOU FOLKS
TWO HOURS AGO.
- OLD MRS. KENDLEMAN TWISTED
HER ANKLE, AS SHE PUTS IT,
DIVING FOR HER LIFE
WHEN A BUNCH OF SCHOOL KIDS
RODE DOWN THE SIDEWALK
ON SKATEBOARDS.
SHE WENT DOWN TO THORNTON'S
STORE THIS MORNING
AND STARTED SPITTING
ON THE NEW SKATEBOARDS.
SPITTING!
BY THE TIME I GOT THERE,
MRS. KENDLEMAN HAD SPRAYED
THE WHOLE DAMN PLACE.
AND SHE MUST HAVE HAD
A COLD OR SOMETHING.
I'M TELLING YOU,
I WON'T EAT FOR A WEEK.
SO WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR CROPS?
- DAD'S GONNA BURN THESE AGAIN.
- IT'S CONTAMINATED.
- YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT THAT WORD MEANS.
IT'S NOT CONTAMINATED.
IT'S JUST TAP WATER.
POUR IT IN HIS BOWL.
- IT TASTES FUNNY.
- IT DOES NOT.
AND BESIDES,
HE LICKS HIS BUTT EVERY DAY.
I DON'T THINK HE'LL MIND.
[barks, growls]
HOUDINI?
BO, DON'T RUN.
WHAT'S WRONG, BOY?
STOP IT, HOUDINI.
[barks, growling]
- LOOK AT WHERE IT'S BENT OVER,
FATHER.
- IT'S NOT BROKEN.
- NOW, WHAT KIND OF MACHINE
CAN BEND A STALK OF CORN OVER
WITHOUT BREAKING IT?
- CAN'T BE BY HAND.
IT'S TOO PERFECT.
- IT DOESN'T SOUND MUCH
LIKE LIONEL PRICHARD
AND THE WOLFINGTON BROTHERS.
THEY CAN'T TAKE A PISS
WITHOUT WETTING
THE FRONT OF THEIR PANTS.
I DON'T THINK ANYONE ELSE AROUND
HERE HAS HAD ANY PROBLEMS.
I WAS OVER AT THEO HENRY'S FARM
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON,
AND HE WOULD HAVE MENTIONED
SOMETHING.
- WHY WERE YOU AT THEO'S PLACE?
- SOME ANIMALS AROUND THE COUNTY
HAVE BEEN ACTING FUNNY...
AND SOME OF THEM VIOLENT.
- WHAT IS IT, A VIRUS?
- I DON'T THINK SO, FATHER.
THEY'RE MORE EDGY.
YOU KNOW, ON ALERT.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE THEY ACT WHEN
THEY SMELL A PREDATOR AROUND--
PEEING ON THEMSELVES
AND EVERYTHING.
- CAROLINE...
PLEASE STOP CALLING ME
"FATHER."
- WHAT'S WRONG?
- I DON'T HEAR MY CHILDREN.
[sniffling]
- HE FELL ON ME.
HE WANTED TO KILL BO.
[exhales]
- DID HE HURT YOU?
- NO.
- I'M SO SORRY, MORGAN.
- WHERE WERE YOU?
- HOUDINI'S SICK.
- TIE ISABELLE UP TO THE BACK
OF THE SHED, PLEASE,
AND MAKE SURE THE KNOT'S
VERY TIGHT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
- THERE'S A MONSTER
OUTSIDE MY ROOM.
CAN I HAVE A GLASS OF WATER?
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH THE WATER
NEXT TO YOUR BED?
- IT TASTES OLD.
- WHAT ARE YOU THINKING ABOUT?
- WHY DO YOU TALK TO MOM
WHEN YOU'RE BY YOURSELF?
- MAKES ME FEEL BETTER.
- DOES SHE EVER ANSWER BACK?
- NO.
- SHE NEVER ANSWERS ME EITHER.
- WHAT?
- LIONEL PRICHARD AND THE
WOLFINGTON BROTHERS ARE BACK.
- IT'S TIME FOR AN ASS-WHUPPING.
- THIS IS NOT AN INTELLIGENT WAY
TO APPROACH THIS.
LEE IS A FRIEND OF MINE.
THIS IS HIS SON.
- YEAH, WE'LL BE DOING LEE
A FAVOR.
ALL RIGHT, LISTEN,
WE BOTH GO OUTSIDE,
MOVE AROUND THE HOUSE
IN OPPOSITE DIRECTIONS.
WE ACT CRAZY,
INSANE WITH ANGER,
MAKE THEM CRAP IN THEIR PANTS,
FORCE THEM AROUND TILL
WE MEET UP ON THE OTHER SIDE.
- EXPLAIN "ACT CRAZY."
- YOU KNOW, CURSE AND STUFF.
- YOU WANT ME TO CURSE?
- YOU DON'T MEAN IT.
IT'S JUST FOR SHOW.
WHAT?
- WELL, IT WON'T BE CONVINCING.
IT DOESN'T SOUND NATURAL
WHEN I CURSE.
- JUST MAKE NOISES, THEN.
- EXPLAIN "NOISES."
- ARE YOU GONNA DO THIS OR WHAT?
- NO, I'M NOT.
ALL RIGHT, YOU WANT THEM
STEALING SOMETHING
IN THE HOUSE NEXT TIME?
ON THE COUNT OF THREE.
1...
- ALL RIGHT.
- 2...3!
- AAH!
I'M INSANE WITH ANGER!
- WE'RE GONNA BEAT YOUR ASS,
BITCH!
[garbage cans clattering]
WE'RE GONNA TEAR YOUR HEAD OFF!
- I'M LOSING MY MIND!
IT'S TIME FOR
AN ASS-WHUPPING!
I CURSED.
- I HEARD.
HOW DID HE GET...
ARE YOU SURE
THIS IS LIONEL PRICHARD?
[thud]
- YOU LIKE THAT?
YOU GOT AN OLD
BABY MONITOR AROUND?
- BO HAD AN OLD BABY MONITOR.
- YOU CAN USE BO'S BABY MONITOR
AS A WALKIE-TALKIE.
- YOU CAN?
- MM-HMM.
IT ONLY WORKS ONE WAY,
BUT THAT'LL DO FINE.
THAT IS, UNTIL SOMEONE
GETS YOU AN OLD WALKIE-TALKIE
LEFT OVER AT THE STATION.
- STOP, STOP!
IT'S HIDEOUS!
- GET IT OFF, GET IT OFF!
- I-I KNOW WHAT TO DO.
- HEY, BO...
TURN THAT DOWN
TILL OFFICER PASKI LEAVES.
- DOY-DA!
- YOU'RE TOO OLD
TO STILL BE DOING THIS.
YOU TAKE A GLASS OF WATER,
AND YOU FINISH IT.
NOW,
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THIS ONE?
- IT HAS DUST IN IT.
- THIS ONE?
- A HAIR.
- MORGAN TOOK A SIP,
AND IT HAS HIS AMEBAS IN IT.
- MY TURN.
- SO HOW ARE YOU, MERRILL?
- FINE.
- HOW IS WORK
AT THE GAS STATION?
- STIMULATING.
- I NEVER GOT A CHANCE
TO TELL YOU,
BUT I-I THOUGHT YOUR MOVING IN
HERE WITH YOUR BROTHER AFTER--
IT WAS A NICE THING TO DO.
- WELL, I DON'T THINK
I'M HELPING MUCH.
- YOU ARE.
- SORRY.
- OKAY, SO FAR I HAVE,
"IT WAS VERY DARK."
- YES, IT WAS.
- YOU CAN'T DESCRIBE HIM
AT ALL?
DON'T YOU THINK
THAT'S KIND OF ODD?
- A LITTLE.
- I DON'T KNOW WHETHER TO LOOK
FOR A GIANT OR A MIDGET.
- NO, HE DEFINITELY
WASN'T A MIDGET.
- OKAY.
SO HE WAS TALL?
- I-I WOULD SAY SO, YES.
- PROBABLY.
- OVER 6 FEET?
- IT WAS VERY DARK.
- YES, IT WAS.
- HOW CERTAIN ARE YOU
THAT THIS WAS A MALE?
- OH, I DON'T--
I DON'T KNOW ANY GIRLS
WHO COULD RUN LIKE THAT.
- I DON'T KNOW, MERRILL.
I'VE SEEN SOME OF THOSE WOMEN
ON THE OLYMPICS.
THEY CAN RUN LIKE THE WIND.
- THIS GUY GOT ON OUR ROOF IN,
LIKE, A SECOND.
O-OUR ROOF IS 10 FEET HIGH.
- THEY HAVE WOMEN'S HIGH JUMPING
IN THE OLYMPICS.
THEY GOT THESE
SCANDINAVIAN WOMEN
WHO CAN JUMP CLEAN OVER ME.
- CAROLINE, I KNOW
YOU'RE MAKING A POINT HERE.
I JUST DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT IS.
- AN OUT-OF-TOWN WOMAN
STOPPED BY THE DINER
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON
AND STARTED YELLING AND CUSSING
BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T HAVE
HER FAVORITE CIGARETTES
AT THE VENDING MACHINE.
AND SHE SCARED
A COUPLE OF THE CUSTOMERS.
NO ONE'S SEEN HER SINCE.
AND MY POINT IS,
WE DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THE PERSON YOU SAW,
AND WE SHOULD JUST KEEP
ALL POSSIBILITIES AVAILABLE.
- DAD, WHERE'S THE REMOTE?
- I DON'T KNOW, BABY.
WHY DON'T YOU CHECK
IN THE SOFA CUSHIONS?
- EXCLUDING THE POSSIBILITY
THAT A FEMALE
SCANDINAVIAN OLYMPIAN
WAS RUNNING AROUND OUTSIDE
OUR HOUSE LAST NIGHT,
WHAT ELSE
MIGHT BE A POSSIBILITY?
- I'M NOT DONE ASKING QUESTIONS,
AND I DON'T APPRECIATE SARCASM.
DO YOU TWO HAVE ANYONE
WHO MIGHT HAVE A GRUDGE
OR SOMETHING AGAINST YOU...
MAYBE A-A CHURCH MEMBER WHO--
WHO MIGHT NOT HAVE LIKED THE
FACT THAT YOU LEFT THE CHURCH?
- I DON'T THINK SO.
- OKAY, I WAS OUT OF LINE
WITH THE WHOLE "FEMALE
SCANDINAVIAN OLYMPIAN" THING.
IT'S JUST...I'M PRETTY STRONG,
AND I'M PRETTY FAST.
AND I WAS RUNNING
AS FAST AS I COULD,
AND THIS GUY, HE WAS...
HE WAS JUST TOYING WITH US.
- THERE'S ONLY FOOD
UNDER THE SOFA.
- BABY, WHY DON'T YOU
JUST CHANGE THE CHANNEL
ON THE TELEVISION?
- I DID.
- AND?
- SAME SHOW'S ON EVERY STATION.
- EVERY STATION?
BO, TURN UP THE VOLUME.
- CROP SIGNS FIRST EMERGED
IN THE LATE '70s
WITH RENEWED INTEREST
IN EXTRATERRESTRIAL LIFE.
THEY DIED OUT BY THE EARLY '80s,
DISMISSED AS HOAXES.
THIS NEW RESURGENCE
IS WHOLLY DIFFERENT.
THE SPEED AND THE QUANTITY
IN WHICH IT HAS APPEARED
IMPLIES THE COORDINATION
OF HUNDREDS OF INDIVIDUALS
OVER MANY COUNTRIES.
THERE ARE ONLY A LIMITED
NUMBER OF EXPLANATIONS.
EITHER THIS IS ONE OF THE MOST
ELABORATE HOAXES EVER CREATED,
OR BASICALLY...
IT'S FOR REAL.
- EXTRATERRESTRIALS.
- WHAT IN GOD'S NAME
IS GOING ON?
I DID SOME RESEARCH
AFTER I SAW YOUR CROPS.
TWO OR THREE GUYS
CAN MAKE A DESIGN
THE SIZE OF THE ONE
IN YOUR FIELD OVERNIGHT
USING JUST BOARDS AND ROPES.
- REALLY.
- WELL, THAT'S HOW THESE THINGS
HAVE BEEN DONE IN THE PAST.
BUT THERE'S SO MANY NOW.
HOW COULD SO MANY PEOPLE
BE IN ON IT?
I CAN'T THINK STRAIGHT.
I'M--I'M GONNA
GO BACK TO THE STATION
AND HAVE A CUP OF EDGAR'S COFFEE
AND--AND TRY TO THINK CLEAR,
AND AFTER THAT, I'LL...
I MIGHT MAKE SOME CALLS.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING--
WHAT I SAID IN THERE,
IT STILL GOES.
YOUR--YOUR FAMILY
HAS BEEN THROUGH A LOT.
AND THE LAST THING
THESE CHILDREN NEED TO DO
IS WORRY ABOUT SOME CRAZY THINGS
HAPPENING IN THE WORLD.
NOW, TAKE THEM INTO TOWN
AND GET THEIR MINDS AND YOUR
MIND ON EVERYDAY THINGS, HMM?
GOOD MEDICINE.
- THAT'S GOOD ADVICE.
- AND YOU TAKE CARE OF
YOURSELF...
GRAHAM.
- THE FOOTAGE YOU'RE WATCHING
WAS SHOT YESTERDAY AFTERNOON
BY A 34-YEAR-OLD
LOCAL CAMERAMAN IN BANGALORE,
A SOUTHERN CITY OF INDIA.
IT'S THE 18TH REPORTED CROP SIGN
FOUND IN THAT COUNTRY
IN THE LAST 72 HOURS.
- UNCLE MERRILL,
WILL YOU TURN ON THE RADIO?
- THEY ARE SIGNS INTENDED TO BE
SEEN FROM THE SKY--
- NO RADIO EITHER.
JUST FOR A WHILE.
- BOOK MONEY?
- SURE.
[paper rustling]
JUST ONE.
BE BACK FOR PIZZA IN 15.
- IT'S JUST A BUNCH OF CROCK.
THEY'RE TRYING TO SELL SODAS.
IT'S PLAIN AND SIMPLE.
BEEN WATCHING THESE REPORTS
SINCE MORNING.
I HAVE SEEN 12 SODA COMMERCIALS
SO FAR--12!
- YOU HAVE ANY BOOKS
ON EXTRATERRESTRIALS?
- NOW, DON'T TELL ME YOU BELIEVE
THIS HORSE MANURE.
- AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I THINK WE HAVE ONE.
CAME BY MISTAKE IN A SHIPMENT--
DECIDED TO KEEP IT
FOR THE CITY PEOPLE.
LAST ROW, THIRD BOOK
ON THE LEFT, HONEY.
- WHY IS NO ONE SAYING
THE OBVIOUS?
THESE ARE JUST COPYCATS.
SOMEONE SOMEWHERE
DOES THE FIRST ONE...
- IT WAS ASTHMA MEDICINE,
RIGHT, FATHER?
- FOR MORGAN HESS.
AND IT'S NOT "FATHER" ANYMORE.
- IN LESS THAN AN HOUR,
A COUPLE HUNDRED PEOPLE
GET THE SAME BRILLIANT IDEA,
AND HERE WE ARE,
ON THE VERGE OF MASS HYSTERIA.
- CAN I ASK YOU A FAVOR,
FATHER?
I NEED TO CLEAR MY CONSCIENCE.
WILL YOU LISTEN TO ME?
- TRACEY...
I AM NOT A REVEREND ANYMORE.
I HAVEN'T BEEN FOR SIX MONTHS.
YOU KNOW THIS.
- ALL THIS STUFF ON TV--
JOE GILLS CAME IN HERE TALKING
ABOUT THE END OF THE WORLD--
I'M JUST A LITTLE SCARED.
[sniffles]
PLEASE, I NEED TO CLEAR
MY CONSCIENCE.
- I'VE GOT IT FIGURED.
- YOU DO?
- I'VE HAD TWO SEPARATE FOLKS
TELL ME
THERE HAVE BEEN STRANGERS AROUND
THESE PARTS LAST COUPLE NIGHTS.
CAN'T TELL WHAT THEY LOOK LIKE
'CAUSE THEY'RE STAYING
IN THE SHADOWS--COVERT-LIKE.
NOBODY'S BEEN HURT, MIND YOU,
AND THAT'S THE GIVEAWAY.
- I SEE.
- IT'S CALLED "PROBING."
IT'S A MILITARY PROCEDURE.
YOU SEND OUT A RECONNAISSANCE
GROUP, VERY SMALL,
CHECK THINGS OUT.
NOT TO ENGAGE BUT TO EVALUATE
THE SITUATION...
EVALUATE THE LEVEL OF DANGER,
MAKE SURE THINGS ARE ALL CLEAR.
- CLEAR FOR WHAT?
- FOR THE REST OF THEM.
- YEAH?
YOU GOT A PAMPHLET OR SOMETHING
I CAN READ?
- SURE.
- THANKS.
- YOU DIDN'T USED TO PLAY
BASEBALL, DID YA?
SHIT, I KNOW YOU.
YOU'RE MERRILL HESS.
I WAS THERE THE DAY YOU HIT
THAT 507-FOOTER
OVER THE LEFT-FIELD WALL,
SET THE RECORD.
MAN, THAT THING
HAD A MOTOR ON IT.
IT'S STILL THE RECORD, RIGHT?
- GOT THE BAT AT HOME
O-ON THE WALL.
- YOU'VE GOT TWO MINOR-LEAGUE
HOME-RUN RECORDS, DON'T YA?
- [softly] FIVE.
- WHY AREN'T YOU IN THE PROS
MAKING STACKS OF CASH
AND GETTING YOUR TOES LICKED
BY BEAUTIFUL WOMEN?
- 'CAUSE HE HAS ANOTHER RECORD
MOST PEOPLE DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
HE HAS THE MINOR-LEAGUE
STRIKEOUT RECORD.
- HELLO, LIONEL.
- MERRILL'S A CLASS-A
SCREW-UP.
HE WOULD JUST SWING THAT BAT
AS HARD AS HE COULD EVERY TIME.
DIDN'T MATTER
WHAT THE COACHES SAID,
DIDN'T MATTER WHO WAS ON BASE.
HE WOULD JUST WHIP THAT BAT
THROUGH THE AIR
AS HARD AS HE COULD.
LOOKED LIKE A LUMBERJACK
CHOPPING DOWN A TREE.
MERRILL HERE HAS MORE STRIKEOUTS
THAN ANY TWO PLAYERS.
- YOU REALLY GOT
THE STRIKEOUT RECORD?
- FELT WRONG NOT TO SWING.
- IT'S CONTAMINATED.
- CARL, THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG
WITH OUR WATER.
- YOUR WATER'S FINE.
BO HAS THIS THING
ABOUT HER DRINKING WATER.
SHE HAD IT HER WHOLE LIFE.
IT'S LIKE A TICK PEOPLE HAVE,
EXCEPT IT'S NOT A TICK.
- IS THAT RIGHT?
- [man shouts] 13!
- * DON'T GIVE ME
THAT SO-SO SODA *
* THE SAME OLD COLA
* I WANT A POW POW
- I'LL TAKE IT.
- I CURSED 37 TIMES LAST WEEK.
I SAID THE "F" WORD
A COUPLE TIMES,
BUT MOSTLY...[whispers] "SHITS"
AND...[whispers] "BASTARDS."
[Muzak playing in background]
IS "DOUCHE BAG" A CURSE?
- I SUPPOSE THAT WOULD DEPEND
ON ITS USAGE.
- HOW ABOUT, "JOHN, YOU'RE A
DOUCHE BAG FOR KISSING BARBARA"?
- IT'S A CURSE.
- THEN IT'S NOT 37.
IT'S 71.
- PHARMACY CROWDED?
- I DON'T WANT ANY ONE OF YOU
SPENDING TIME WITH TRACEY
ABERNATHY ALONE.
IS THAT UNDERSTOOD?
- IS THAT HIM?
- YEAH.
- WHO IS HE?
[tires squealing]
[static buzzing]
- WHAT IS IT?
- IT'S BO'S BABY MONITOR.
- I FOUND IT IN THE BASEMENT.
I'M GONNA USE IT
AS A WALKIE-TALKIE.
[humming, droning]
WHAT IF IT'S CATCHING
A SIGNAL FROM THEM?
- IT'S NOT.
- BUT IT WASN'T WORKING.
- MORGAN, THIS CROP STUFF
IS ABOUT A BUNCH OF NERDS
WHO NEVER HAD A GIRLFRIEND
IN THEIR LIVES.
THEY'RE, LIKE, 30, AND THEY WORK
UP LITTLE CODES TOGETHER,
AND THEY ANALYZE GREEK MYTHOLOGY
AND MAKE UP SECRET SOCIETIES
WHERE OTHER GUYS WHO NEVER HAD
GIRLFRIENDS BEFORE CAN JOIN IN.
THEY DO STUPID CRAP
LIKE THIS TO FEEL SPECIAL.
IT'S A SCAM.
NERDS WERE DOING IT
25 YEARS AGO,
AND NEW NERDS
ARE DOING IT AGAIN.
- IT'S JUST STATIC, MORGAN,
ALL RIGHT?
TURN IT UP.
SEE.
[whining, eerie droning]
- IT'S A CODE.
- WHY CAN'T
THEY GET GIRLFRIENDS?
- CAN I SEE THAT, PLEASE?
[static whining, droning]
[fades away]
- IT'S NOISE.
- IT'S BROKEN, MORGAN.
IT'S JUST GONNA KEEP DOING THIS.
MAYBE SOME NEW BATTERIES...
- WE MIGHT LOSE THE SIGNAL.
- THIS IS EXACTLY
WHAT THE NERDS WANT.
- I'M GETTING OUT NOW.
[louder droning,
eerie sounds]
- NOBODY MOVE.
VOICES.
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
NOT ENGLISH, THOUGH.
YOU HEARD THE VOICES, RIGHT,
UNCLE MERRILL?
- I HEARD THEM, MORGAN.
[clicking sound
under droning]
- PROBABLY PICKING UP
ANOTHER BABY MONITOR.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
[soft clicking, popping]
- LET ME SEE IT.
[sounds increase]
- STOP!
[clicking, popping continues
under eerie droning]
- SEE, THIS IS WHY
WE'RE NOT WATCHING TV.
PEOPLE GET OBSESSED.
I'M LETTING GO NOW.
- NO, DAD!
- DON'T DO IT!
- YOU'LL LOSE THE SIGNAL.
- DON'T LET GO.
IT GETS CLEARER
THE HIGHER YOU HOLD IT.
- I GOT HIM.
- BO, HONEY, I DON'T WANT YOU
CLIMBING ON THE CAR.
- STOP!
[clicking, popping sounds,
eerie droning]
THERE'S TWO OF THEM TALKING.
[clicking, popping continues]
[static]
[Isabelle barking]
[Isabelle whimpering]
[Isabelle continues barking]
[snarls loudly]
- [gasps]
[Isabelle whimpering
and barking]
ISABELLE, YOU'RE GONNA FEEL
VERY SILLY
WHEN THIS TURNS OUT
TO BE ALL JUST MAKE-BELIEVE.
[Isabelle continues whimpering
and barking]
[clicking and chattering]
[gasps]
YOU'RE WASTING YOUR TIME HERE!
I'M NOT GONNA REPORT THIS
OR ANYTHING YOU DO TO MY CROPS
TO THE NEWS OR TV OR ANYBODY.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO GET FAMOUS!
[clicking and chattering]
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[door opens, closes]
[exhales deeply]
OKAY.
LET'S TURN ON THE TV.
[television humming
and whirring]
- ...FIRST APPEARED
52 MINUTES AGO.
MEXICO CITY OFFICIALS,
AS WELL AS U.S. OFFICIALS,
HAVE CONFIRMED
THAT THESE ARE NOT AIRCRAFT
FROM EITHER GOVERNMENT'S
AIR FORCE.
THE FIRST SIGHTING WAS MADE
BY AN AIR MEXICO 747
EN ROUTE
FROM MAZATLAN TO NEW YORK.
AS THE UNIDENTIFIED CRAFTS
ENTERED MEXICO CITY AIRSPACE,
THEY WERE NOT DETECTED BY RADAR
BY EITHER COUNTRY.
- THE NERDS WERE RIGHT.
- WE HAVE TO TAPE THIS.
- MY BALLET RECITAL.
- LISTEN, BO,
THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT.
EVERYTHING PEOPLE HAVE WRITTEN
ABOUT IN SCIENCE BOOKS
IS GOING TO CHANGE.
THE HISTORY
OF THE WORLD'S FUTURE
IS ON THE TV RIGHT NOW.
WE NEED TO RECORD THIS,
SO YOU CAN SHOW
YOUR CHILDREN THIS TAPE
AND SAY YOU WERE THERE...
FOR YOUR CHILDREN, BO.
- MY BALLET RECITAL.
- DAD.
- FIND ANOTHER TAPE.
- UNCLE MERRILL,
I'M USING YOUR TAPE.
- YOU ARE SEEING A LIVE FEED
FROM OUR AFFILIATE
DOWN HERE IN MEXICO CITY.
THIS IMAGE HAS NOT BEEN ADJUSTED
OR ENHANCED IN ANY WAY.
WHAT YOU'RE SEEING IS REAL.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
EVERYTHING THEY WROTE
IN SCIENCE BOOKS
IS ABOUT TO CHANGE.
- I TOLD YOU.
[inhales deeply]
- SOME PEOPLE
ARE PROBABLY THINKING
THIS IS THE END OF THE WORLD.
- THAT'S TRUE.
- DO YOU THINK IT COULD BE?
- YES.
- HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT?
- THAT WASN'T
THE ANSWER YOU WANTED?
- COULDN'T YOU PRETEND
TO BE LIKE YOU USED TO BE...
[chuckles]
GIVE ME SOME COMFORT?
- PEOPLE...
BREAK DOWN INTO TWO GROUPS.
WHEN THEY EXPERIENCE
SOMETHING LUCKY,
GROUP NUMBER ONE
SEES IT AS MORE THAN LUCK,
MORE THAN COINCIDENCE.
THEY SEE IT AS A SIGN...
EVIDENCE THAT THERE IS
SOMEONE UP THERE
WATCHING OUT FOR THEM.
GROUP NUMBER TWO
SEES IT AS JUST PURE LUCK,
A HAPPY TURN OF CHANCE.
I'M SURE THE PEOPLE
IN GROUP NUMBER TWO
ARE LOOKING AT THOSE 14 LIGHTS
IN A VERY SUSPICIOUS WAY.
FOR THEM,
THE SITUATION ISN'T 50-50.
IT COULD BE BAD.
IT COULD BE GOOD.
BUT DEEP DOWN...
THEY FEEL
THAT WHATEVER HAPPENS,
THEY'RE ON THEIR OWN.
AND THAT FILLS THEM WITH FEAR.
YEAH, THERE ARE THOSE PEOPLE.
BUT THERE'S
A WHOLE LOT OF PEOPLE
IN THE GROUP NUMBER ONE.
WHEN THEY SEE THOSE 14 LIGHTS,
THEY'RE LOOKING AT A MIRACLE.
AND DEEP DOWN, THEY FEEL
THAT WHATEVER'S GOING TO HAPPEN,
THERE'LL BE SOMEONE THERE
TO HELP THEM.
AND THAT FILLS THEM WITH HOPE.
SEE, WHAT YOU HAVE TO ASK
YOURSELF IS,
WHAT KIND OF PERSON ARE YOU?
ARE YOU THE KIND
THAT SEES SIGNS,
SEES MIRACLES?
OR DO YOU BELIEVE
THAT PEOPLE JUST GET LUCKY?
OR LOOK
AT THE QUESTION THIS WAY--
IS IT POSSIBLE THAT THERE
ARE NO COINCIDENCES?
- I WAS AT THIS PARTY ONCE.
I'M ON THE COUCH
WITH RANDA MCKINNEY.
[exhales sharply]
SHE WAS JUST SITTING THERE,
LOOKING BEAUTIFUL,
STARING AT ME.
I GO TO LEAN IN AND KISS HER...
[laughing] AND I REALIZE
I HAVE GUM IN MY MOUTH.
SO I TURN, TAKE OUT THE GUM,
STUFF IT IN A PAPER CUP
NEXT TO THE SOFA,
AND TURN AROUND.
RANDA MCKINNEY THROWS UP
ALL OVER HERSELF.
[chuckles]
I KNEW THE SECOND IT HAPPENED,
IT WAS A MIRACLE.
I COULD'VE BEEN KISSING HER
WHEN SHE THREW UP.
THAT WOULD'VE SCARRED ME
FOR LIFE.
I MAY NEVER HAVE RECOVERED.
[laughing]
I'M A MIRACLE MAN.
THOSE LIGHTS ARE A MIRACLE.
- THERE YOU GO.
- SO WHICH TYPE ARE YOU?
- DO YOU FEEL COMFORTED?
- YEAH, I DO.
- THEN WHAT DOES IT MATTER?
I NEVER TOLD YOU THE LAST WORDS
THAT COLLEEN SAID
BEFORE THEY LET HER DIE.
SHE SAID, "SEE."
THEN HER EYES GLAZED A BIT.
AND THEN SHE SAID,
"SWING AWAY."
YOU KNOW WHY SHE SAID THAT?
'CAUSE THE NERVE ENDINGS IN HER
BRAIN WERE FIRING AS SHE DIED,
AND SOME RANDOM MEMORY OF US
AT ONE OF YOUR BASEBALL GAMES
JUST POPPED INTO HER HEAD.
THERE IS NO ONE WATCHING OUT
FOR US, MERRILL.
WE ARE ALL ON OUR OWN.
[sirens wailing]
- WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
- WELL, THERE WAS AN ACCIDENT,
DRUNK DRIVING.
THEY WEREN'T SURE--
- HE WASN'T DRUNK.
RAY FELL ASLEEP AT THE WHEEL.
- IS HE OKAY?
- YEAH.
THAT WAS THE FIRST THING
COLLEEN ASKED TOO.
- SHE'S TALKING.
WHAT AMBULANCE IS SHE IN?
- SHE'S NOT
IN AN AMBULANCE, FATHER.
[television humming
and whirring]
- FOR THE KIDS' PROTECTION.
ALL THEY WERE DOING
WAS WATCHING TV FROM 5:00 A.M.
I FELT LIKE THEY WERE GETTING
OBSESSED, LIKE YOU SAID.
THEY SHOULD BE PLAYING
FURRY, FURRY RABBIT
OR TEA PARTY OR SOMETHING.
- WHAT'S FURRY, FURRY RABBIT?
- IT'S A GAME, ISN'T IT?
ANYWAYS,
THEY CLOSED THE SCHOOLS.
AND THERE'S BEEN
SOME INTERESTING DEVELOPMENTS.
- WHAT TIME IS IT?
- 11:00 A.M.
THEY'RE GONE...
BUT THEY'RE NOT REALLY GONE.
WE JUST CAN'T SEE THEM.
EARLY THIS MORNING,
A BIRD FLEW INTO THE AREA
WHERE THE LIGHTS
WERE HOVERING LAST NIGHT.
IT STOPPED DEAD IN THE AIR
AND FELL STRAIGHT DOWN.
THEY CAUGHT IT ON TAPE.
THEY'VE BEEN PLAYING IT
ALL MORNING.
THE FOOTAGE LOOKS LIKE THE BIRD
FLEW INTO A WALL IN THE SKY.
THEY FOUND THE BIRD.
HIS--HIS HEAD WAS CRUSHED IN.
THEY THINK THEY HAVE SOME KIND
OF INVISIBLE-SHIELD THING GOING,
L-LIKE AN OPTICAL ILLUSION.
THEY'RE STILL THERE...
HOVERING.
SOME PEOPLE THINK
THERE'S MORE OF THEM NOW...
ALL OVER THE PLACE,
OVER US, EVEN.
THERE'S A THEORY
ABOUT THE CR--CROP CIRCLES.
THEY COULD BE SOME KIND OF--
SOME KIND OF LANDMARK,
VISUAL MAPPING SYSTEM
SO THEY COULD NAVIGATE,
COORDINATE.
MAKES SENSE.
[wind chimes clinking]
[indistinct chatter]
- IS IT TRUE?
- SO THE ALIENS
CAN'T READ OUR MINDS.
- OH.
OH, OF COURSE.
- THEY TELL YOU EVERYTHING
IN THIS BOOK.
IT SAYS THEY'RE PROBABLY
VERY SMALL, LIKE MY HEIGHT,
BECAUSE
AS THEIR BRAINS DEVELOPED,
THERE WAS NO USE
FOR PHYSICAL DEVELOPMENT.
IT ALSO SAYS
THEY'RE PROBABLY VEGETARIANS,
BECAUSE THEY WOULD'VE REALIZED
THE BENEFITS OF SUCH A DIET.
- WHO WROTE THIS BOOK?
- SCIENTISTS WHO HAVE BEEN
PERSECUTED FOR THEIR BELIEFS.
- THAT MEANS
THEY'RE UNEMPLOYED.
- IF YOU'RE GONNA MAKE FUN
OF IT, THEN FORGET IT.
- THIS IS SERIOUS.
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT GOT INTO ME.
- THERE ARE PICTURES.
DR. BIMBU, ONE OF THE AUTHORS
OF THE BOOK--
- BIMBU?
- DAD.
- I JUST ASKED HIS NAME.
- YOU HAD A TONE.
HE SAID THERE ARE TWO REASONS
WHY EXTRATERRESTRIALS
WOULD VISIT US--
TO MAKE CONTACT
IN THE SPIRIT OF EXPLORATION
AND FURTHERING THE KNOWLEDGE
OF THE UNIVERSE,
OR THE OTHER REASON--
THEY'RE HOSTILE.
THEY'VE USED UP ALL
THE RESOURCES ON THEIR PLANET,
AND THEY'RE LOOKING TO HARVEST
OUR PLANET NEXT.
- HERE.
LOOKS A LITTLE LIKE OUR HOUSE,
DOESN'T IT?
- SAME WINDOWS.
- THAT'S WEIRD.
[telephone rings]
- AAH!
- [gasps]
- YEAH.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S ENOUGH
FROM DR. BIMBU FOR NOW.
EVERYBODY IN THIS HOUSE
NEEDS TO CALM DOWN
AND EAT SOME FRUIT
OR SOMETHING.
[ringing continues]
HELLO?
- FATHER?
- HELLO?
HELLO?
[line beeping]
[footsteps descending stairs]
I'M GOING OUT
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
NO ONE LEAVES THIS HOUSE--
NO ONE.
- WHERE YOU GOING?
- RAY REDDY'S HOUSE.
- WHY?
- I THINK HE JUST CALLED HERE.
[door opens, closes]
- YOU DON'T THINK
SOMETHING BAD WILL HAPPEN,
DO YOU, MORGAN?
- WHY?
YOU HAVE ONE
OF YOUR FEELINGS AGAIN?
IS IT BAD?
I WON'T LET ANYTHING BAD
HAPPEN TO YOU.
- I DON'T WANT YOU TO DIE.
- WHO SAID I WAS GONNA DIE?
WHO SAID I WAS GONNA DIE?
[knocking at door]
[door creaking]
- HELLO, RAY.
WHAT HAPPENED?
- I WROTE YOUR NUMBER DOWN
TO CALL YOU.
IT'S BEEN SITTING NEXT
TO THE PHONE FOR SIX MONTHS.
WHEN I KNEW
IT WAS INSIDE THE HOUSE...
I COULDN'T THINK
OF ANY OTHER NUMBER TO CALL.
I PANICKED.
THANK YOU FOR COMING, FATHER.
- YOU'RE WELCOME, RAY.
- I WORKED SO LONG THAT NIGHT.
I'VE NEVER FALLEN ASLEEP
DRIVING BEFORE...
NEVER SINCE.
- DON'T.
- MOST OF THE RIDE HOME,
THERE WASN'T A CAR IN SIGHT
IN EITHER DIRECTION.
IF I'D HAVE FALLEN
ASLEEP THEN,
I WOULD'VE ENDED UP
IN A DITCH WITH A HEADACHE.
IT HAD TO BE
AT THAT RIGHT MOMENT--
THAT 10, 15 SECONDS
WHEN I PASSED HER WALKING.
IT WAS LIKE
IT WAS MEANT TO BE.
I GUESS IF THIS
IS THE END OF THE WORLD,
I'M SCREWED, RIGHT?
PEOPLE WHO KILL
REVERENDS' WIVES
AREN'T EXACTLY USHERED TO
THE FRONT OF THE LINE IN HEAVEN.
[engine turning]
- WH--WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- TO THE LAKE.
THE WAY I SEE IT...
THESE PLACES
MARKED IN CROPS AND SUCH--
NONE OF THEM
ARE REALLY NEAR WATER.
I DON'T THINK
THEY LIKE WATER.
CAN'T BE ANY WORSE THAN HERE.
- DID YOU SEE SOMETHING, RAY?
- I KNOW
WHAT I'VE DONE TO YOU.
I MADE YOU QUESTION
YOUR FAITH.
I'M TRULY SORRY FOR WHAT
I'VE DONE TO YOU AND YOURS.
- [breathes deeply]
ALL RIGHT.
- AND DON'T OPEN
MY PANTRY, FATHER.
I FOUND ONE OF THEM IN THERE
AND LOCKED HIM IN.
- THE STARTLING FOOTAGE
WE'RE ABOUT TO SHOW YOU
WAS PHOTOGRAPHED
BY A 42-YEAR-OLD,
ROMERO VALADAREZ.
THIS VIDEO
WAS TAKEN YESTERDAY AFTERNOON
AT HIS SON'S 7TH BIRTHDAY
IN THE CITY
OF PASSO FUNDO, BRAZIL.
IT WAS SENT
TO THE LOCAL NEWS BUREAU THERE
AND SENT TO US VIA SATELLITE
JUST A FEW MINUTES AGO.
ALL INITIAL OPINIONS
ARE THIS IS GENUINE.
WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT TO SEE
MAY DISTURB YOU.
[children shouting
in Portuguese]
- MOVE, CHILDREN!
VAMONOS!
- [speaking Portuguese]
IT'S BEHIND!
[screaming]
- OH!
[screaming continues]
- [speaking Portuguese]
IT'S BEHIND!
- HELLO?
THE POLICE ARE HERE.
I'M WITH THEM.
I AM A POLICE OFFICER.
I JUST WANT TO TALK WITH YOU.
WE KNOW ALL ABOUT THE HOAX.
WE ALREADY TOOK
SOME OF YOUR FRIENDS DOWNTOWN
IN A PADDY WAGON.
[mouths words]
JUST TELL US YOUR NAME
AND WHY YOU DID IT,
AND WE'LL GIVE YOU THE SAME DEAL
WE GAVE THE OTHERS.
DON'T THROW
YOUR LIFE AWAY, SON.
[gasps, grunting]
- AAH!
[door locks]
- THEIR SKIN CHANGES COLORS.
THAT'S WHY WE COULDN'T SEE THEM
THAT NIGHT.
- TELL ME SOMETHING,
MORGAN, UH...
IN THIS BOOK OF YOURS...
DID THEY HAPPEN TO DETAIL
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF THEY WERE HOSTILE?
- YES.
IT SAID
THEY WOULD PROBABLY INVADE.
THEY WOULD USE GROUND TACTICS,
HAND-TO-HAND COMBAT.
THEY WOULDN'T USE
THEIR TECHNOLOGY
OR FIGHT AN AIRBORNE BATTLE,
'CAUSE THEY KNOW EVENTUALLY
WE WOULD USE NUCLEAR WEAPONS.
THEN THE PLANET
WOULD BE USELESS TO THEM.
- HOW COULD ANYONE POSSIBLY KNOW
THAT INFORMATION?
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
WHAT ELSE DID IT SAY?
- THEY SAID THERE ARE ONE
OF TWO OUTCOMES OF AN INVASION.
ONE, THEY FIGHT
AND ARE DEFEATED
AND HAVE TO RETURN AGAIN
WITH FULL FORCES
HUNDREDS MAYBE EVEN THOUSANDS
OF YEARS LATER.
- WHAT'S TWO?
- THEY WIN.
- I'M SORRY,
WHAT--WHAT BOOK IS THIS?
- IS THIS REALLY HAPPENING?
I HEARD A THEORY THAT, UH...
THEY DON'T LIKE PLACES
NEAR WATER.
MAYBE WE'D BE SAFE FROM THEM
NEAR A LAKE OR SOMETHING, BUT...
- SOUNDS MADE UP.
- I SAW ONE OF THEM
AT RAY REDDY'S HOUSE.
I CAN'T BE SURE,
BUT I GOT THE DISTINCT FEELING
IT WANTED TO HARM ME.
SO...
WE CAN CHOOSE TO BELIEVE
THIS LAKE IDEA,
PACK UP, AND GO...
OR WE CAN STAY HERE,
HIDE INSIDE OUR HOME,
WAIT IT OUT.
WE MIGHT BE OVERREACTING,
BUT I'M WILLING TO LIVE
WITH THAT.
EITHER WAY,
AT LEAST WE'LL BE TOGETHER.
ALL THOSE IN FAVOR OF
THE LAKE IDEA, RAISE YOUR HAND.
ALL THOSE IN FAVOR OF HOME,
RAISE YOUR HAND.
OKAY.
MY VOTE COUNTS AS TWO.
- THAT'S BULLSHIT!
YOU'RE CHEATING!
- MORGAN, CALM DOWN.
I GET TWO VOTES BECAUSE
I REPRESENT TWO PARENTS HERE.
- WE DON'T KNOW ANYTHING YET.
WE'LL BE SAFE HERE ANYWAY.
I DON'T WANT TO LEAVE HOME.
THIS IS WHERE
WE LIVED WITH MOM.
- THAT'S GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH THIS.
- I CHANGE MY VOTE.
- YOU CAN'T CHANGE YOUR VOTE.
- ALL THOSE IN FAVOR OF HOME,
RAISE YOUR HAND.
- THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
- YOU LOSE, THREE TO TWO.
- WE'RE GOING TO BOARD UP
EVERY WINDOW IN THIS HOUSE.
- HOW DO WE KNOW BOARDS
WILL DO ANYTHING?
- BECAUSE THEY SEEM TO HAVE
TROUBLE WITH PANTRY DOORS.
[sighs]
[wind chimes clinking]
- THE INFORMATION
WE'RE RECEIVING
COMES FROM OUR AFFILIATES
ACROSS THE WORLD.
[hammer pounding]
- DAD, UNCLE MERRILL!
- AMMAN JOINS NAIROBI,
BEIJING, AND JERUSALEM
AS THE LATEST TO CONFIRM
THE APPEARANCE OF LIGHTS.
- THERE ARE LIGHTS
IN OVER 274 CITIES.
THEY THINK IT'LL BE 400
WITHIN THE HOUR.
THEY'RE APPEARING AT OR
WITHIN ONE MILE OF CROP SIGNS.
- THEY WERE FOR NAVIGATION.
THEY MADE A MAP.
THEY'RE GONNA BE WITHIN
A MILE OF US.
- DAD?
- YES?
- THEY THINK THESE ARE STAGES
IMMEDIATELY PRECEDING
AN ATTACK MANEUVER.
I WAS WRONG.
THEY'RE HOSTILE.
- IT'S LIKE
WAR OF THE WORLDS.
- GROUND FORCES HAVE BEEN
ASSEMBLED IN COUNTRIES
THROUGHOUT THE GLOBE.
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
HAVE FLOCKED
TO TEMPLES, SYNAGOGUES,
AND CHURCHES.
[church bell tolling]
GOD BE WITH US ALL.
[military equipment rumbling]
- I'M GOING TO GET
BACK TO THE WINDOWS.
- HEY, YOU GUYS OKAY?
- SOME GUY HAD A SIGN SAYING IT
WAS THE END OF THE WORLD.
- DON'T WORRY.
- YOU WON'T LET ANYTHING HAPPEN
TO US, RIGHT?
- NO WAY.
- I WISH YOU WERE MY DAD.
- WHAT DID YOU SAY?
DON'T YOU EVER SAY ANYTHING
LIKE THAT AGAIN, EVER.
[wind chimes clanging]
THERE'S TOO MANY WINDOWS
IN THE BEDROOMS.
WE DON'T HAVE ENOUGH BOARDS.
- WE'LL BOARD UP
THE BEDROOM DOORS.
- WHERE ARE WE GONNA SLEEP?
- IN THE FAMILY ROOM.
- WHAT ABOUT ISABELLE?
- WE'LL TIE HER UP IN THE GARAGE
AFTER DINNER.
- I'LL MAKE SOME SANDWICHES.
- I WANT SPAGHETTI.
- WE'LL JUST EAT FAST, BO.
- SPAGHETTI SOUNDS GREAT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT, MORGAN?
- ANYTHING?
FRENCH TOAST...
AND MASHED POTATOES.
- NOW WE'RE TALKING.
HOW ABOUT YOU, MERRILL?
- CHICKEN TERIYAKI.
- GOOD CHOICE.
I'M GOING TO HAVE
A CHEESEBURGER WITH BACON.
EXTRA BACON.
[water dripping]
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH EVERYONE? EAT.
- MAYBE WE SHOULD SAY A PRAYER.
- NO.
- WHY NOT?
- WE'RE NOT SAYING A PRAYER.
- BO HAS A BAD FEELING.
- I HAD A DREAM.
- WE AREN'T SAYING A PRAYER.
EAT!
- I HATE YOU.
- THAT'S FINE.
- YOU LET MOM DIE.
- MORGAN.
- I AM NOT WASTING ONE MORE
MINUTE OF MY LIFE ON PRAYER.
NOT ONE MORE MINUTE.
UNDERSTOOD?
[Bo crying]
NOW, WE ARE GOING
TO ENJOY THIS MEAL.
NO ONE CAN STOP US FROM
ENJOYING THIS MEAL, SO ENJOY IT!
STOP CRYING!
- GRAHAM...
- DON'T YELL AT HER!
[Bo sobbing]
- ALL RIGHT,
SINCE YOU'RE ALL NOT GONNA EAT,
I'M GONNA TRY
SOME OF EVERYTHING.
[Bo crying]
- [crying]
[static]
[beeping]
[test signal beeping]
IT'S HAPPENING.
[crickets chirping]
- GRAHAM, HURRY.
- DID I EVER TELL YOU
WHAT EVERYONE SAID
WHEN YOU WERE BORN, BO?
YOU CAME OUT OF YOUR MAMA,
AND YOU DIDN'T EVEN CRY.
YOU JUST OPENED YOUR EYES,
AND YOU LOOKED
AROUND THE ROOM AT EVERYBODY.
[laughs] YOUR EYES WERE
SO BIG AND GORGEOUS.
ALL THE LADIES
IN THE ROOM JUST GASPED.
I MEAN, THEY LITERALLY GASPED.
AND THEY GO,
"OH, SHE'S LIKE AN ANGEL,"
AND THEY SAID, "WE'VE NEVER
SEEN A BABY SO BEAUTIFUL."
AND THEN,
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED?
THEY PUT YOU ON THE TABLE
TO CLEAN YOU UP,
AND YOU LOOKED UP AT ME,
AND YOU SMILED.
THEY SAY BABIES THAT YOUNG
CAN'T SMILE.
YOU SMILED.
LET'S GO DOWN NOW.
[board thuds]
[dog barking]
- WE FORGOT ISABELLE.
[dog yelps, crying]
[clock ticking]
[wind chimes clanging]
- [whispering]
SHOULD WE TURN OFF THE LIGHTS?
- THEY ALREADY KNOW WE'RE HERE.
[footsteps]
[wind chimes clanging]
[floorboards creaking]
[hurried footsteps]
[loud thud]
[thud]
[boards creaking]
- DAD...
[boards creaking,
hurried footsteps]
- DO YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN YOU WERE BORN, MORGAN?
YOU CAME OUT,
AND YOUR MAMA KEPT BLEEDING,
SO THE DOCTORS
RUSHED YOU OUT OF THE ROOM
BEFORE I EVEN
HAD TIME TO SEE YOU.
[thuds]
- THEY'RE ON THE ROOF.
- WHILE THEY WERE
FIXING HER UP,
ALL SHE KEPT
ASKING ABOUT WAS YOU.
[clanking]
- THEY'RE IN THE HOUSE.
- I WANTED YOUR MAMA
TO SEE YOU FIRST,
BECAUSE SHE HAD DREAMED
ABOUT YOU HER WHOLE LIFE.
AND SHE GOT FEELING BETTER,
THEY BROUGHT YOU IN,
AND THEY PLACED YOU
IN HER ARMS,
AND SHE LOOKED AT YOU,
AND YOU LOOKED AT HER,
AND YOU JUST STARED AT
EACH OTHER FOR THE LONGEST TIME.
AND THEN SHE SAID REAL SOFT,
"HELLO, MORGAN.
"I'M YOUR MAMA.
YOU LOOK JUST HOW I DREAMED."
- [crying]
[hurried footsteps]
- THE ATTIC DOOR.
LET'S GO. COME ON.
- WE FORGOT OUR FOIL HELMETS.
- HAVE WE GOT ANYTHING TO WEDGE
AGAINST THE DOORKNOB?
- THEY'LL READ OUR MINDS.
- YOU'RE SCARING YOUR SISTER.
- I'M ALREADY SCARED.
[clicking and chattering]
- MERRILL.
- I'M LOOKING!
- THEY'LL KNOW
OUR SECRET THOUGHTS.
- I'M NOT READY.
[loud thuds]
MERRILL!
- GOT IT!
[light bulb shatters]
- DAD!
[loud thuds]
[pounding]
- WHERE'S BO?
- I'M OKAY.
[footsteps]
[dial clicks]
[static hissing]
- WHAT'S HAPPENING OUT THERE?
- I CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE.
- HOPE THEY'RE DOING BETTER
THAN WE ARE.
WE DON'T EVEN HAVE HELMETS.
[loud thud]
[thud]
- THEY'RE ONLY MAKING NOISES.
THEY'RE NOT TRYING TO GET IN.
[thud]
WHY WOULD THEY DO THAT?
- THEY WANT OUR ATTENTION
ON THE DOOR?
[thud]
- THEY'RE DISTRACTING US.
- FROM WHAT?
- THE BOOK SAYS THEY'RE PROBABLY
VERY GOOD PROBLEM-SOLVERS.
THEY'LL FIND A WAY IN.
[pounding]
- MORGAN,
GIVE ME YOUR FLASHLIGHT.
THEY USED TO POUR COAL
DOWN IN THIS BASEMENT.
THERE'S A COAL CHUTE IN HERE.
[thud]
I CAN FEEL AIR.
- ME, TOO!
- IT'S GETTING STRONGER.
- I'M CLOSE.
[draft of air whistling]
- WHAT?
- HOLD HIM!
- I GOT HIM!
- DID YOU GET HIM?
HOLD HIM!
- I GOT HIM! I GOT HIM!
- HOLD HIM!
- [gasping]
- WE DON'T HAVE HIS MEDICINE.
DON'T BE AFRAID, MORGAN.
WE'LL SLOW THIS DOWN TOGETHER.
FEEL MY CHEST.
FEEL IT MOVING IN AND OUT.
BREATHE LIKE ME.
COME ON.
- I DREAMED THIS.
- STAY WITH ME.
I KNOW IT HURTS.
BE STRONG, BABY.
IT'LL PASS.
[Morgan wheezing]
DON'T DO THIS TO ME AGAIN.
NOT AGAIN.
I HATE YOU.
THE FEAR IS FEEDING IT.
DON'T BE AFRAID
OF WHAT'S HAPPENING.
BELIEVE IT'S GOING TO PASS.
BELIEVE IT.
JUST WAIT.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
THE AIR IS COMING.
BELIEVE.
WE DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID.
IT'S ABOUT TO PASS.
HERE IT COMES.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
HERE COMES THE AIR.
[deep breath]
DON'T BE AFRAID, MORGAN.
FEEL MY CHEST.
BREATHE WITH ME.
TOGETHER.
THE AIR IS GOING IN OUR LUNGS.
WE'RE THE SAME.
- WE SHOULD
SAVE THE FLASHLIGHTS.
[siren wailing]
- RAY'S TRUCK
SWERVED OFF THE ROAD
AND HIT COLLEEN
AND THEN A TREE,
AND SHE WAS PINNED
BETWEEN THE TWO.
- WHAT DOES THAT MEAN--PINNED?
- THE TRUCK--THE TRUCK HAS
SEVERED MOST OF HER LOWER HALF.
- WHAT DID YOU SAY?
- SHE WON'T BE SAVED.
HER BODY IS PINNED
IN SUCH A WAY
THAT IT'S ALIVE
WHEN IT SHOULDN'T BE ALIVE,
AND THE TRUCK IS HOLDING HER
TOGETHER.
NOW, SHE DOESN'T FEEL MUCH,
AND SHE'S--
SHE'S TALKING
ALMOST LIKE NORMAL,
AND WE DIDN'T PULL THE TRUCK OUT
'CAUSE WE--
WE WANTED YOU
TO COME DOWN HERE
AND BE WITH HER
AS LONG AS SHE'S AWAKE,
AND THAT WON'T BE VERY LONG.
NOW, FATHER, DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'VE TOLD YOU?
- CAROLINE...
IS THIS THE LAST TIME
I'M GONNA TALK WITH MY WIFE?
- YES, IT IS.
- PEOPLE THINK THEY CAME HERE
TO TAKE OVER THE PLANET.
THAT'S BULL.
I DON'T THINK THAT.
MY FRIEND AND I SAW THEM.
[radio crackling]
- FOUND A PACK OF LIGHT BULBS.
- THEY POISONED HIS FAMILY.
THEY DRAGGED THEM AWAY.
NOBODY BELIEVES IT, BUT THEY
DIDN'T COME HERE FOR OUR PLANET.
THIS IS A RAID.
THEY CAME HERE FOR US,
TO HARVEST US.
[radio crackling]
LUCKY AS HELL THEY'RE LEAVING.
- THEY'RE LEAVING?
- THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE SAYING.
- HOW LONG
HAVE WE BEEN SLEEPING?
- 12 HOURS OR SO.
[turns off radio]
HE SAID THEY HAD POISON GAS...
THEY SECRETE IN SMALL AMOUNTS.
A LOT OF PEOPLE DIED.
- BUT THEY'RE LEAVING.
- THEY LEFT REAL FAST
THIS MORNING,
LIKE SOMETHING SCARED
THEM OFF.
THEY LEFT SOME
OF THEIR WOUNDED BEHIND.
- WHY ARE THEY GOING?
- PEOPLE MUST HAVE FIGURED OUT
A WAY TO BEAT THEM.
EVERYONE HAS
A WEAKNESS, RIGHT?
YOU DIDN'T THINK WE'D MAKE IT
THROUGH THE NIGHT, DID YOU?
- NO.
- LISTEN...
THERE'S THINGS I CAN TAKE
AND A COUPLE THINGS I CAN'T.
ONE OF THEM I CAN'T TAKE
IS WHEN MY OLDER BROTHER,
WHO'S EVERYTHING I WANT TO BE,
STARTS LOSING FAITH IN THINGS.
I SAW YOUR EYES LAST NIGHT.
I DON'T WANT TO EVER SEE
YOUR EYES LIKE THAT AGAIN.
'KAY?
I'M SERIOUS.
- OKAY.
- HE'S BEEN LIKE THAT
FOR A WHILE.
HE NEEDS HIS MEDICINE.
- HAVE THEY SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT OUR AREA?
- PHILADELPHIA AND ITS
OUTLYING COUNTIES ARE CLEARED...
BUT WHO KNOWS FOR SURE?
- HE'S NOT STRONG ENOUGH.
IF HE HAS ANOTHER ATTACK
RIGHT NOW--
- I KNOW.
WE'D HAVE TO BE SURE BEFORE
WE OPENED UP THAT DOOR, GRAHAM.
[static hissing]
IT'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
- ME, TOO.
[news report
playing on TV]
- GET THE SYRINGE AS WELL.
WE MAY NEED TO GIVE HIM
AN EPINEPHRINE SHOT.
[door creaks]
- THE ATMOSPHERE HERE
IS CAUTIOUSLY OPTIMISTIC.
- THEY'RE DOING THIS ON TV.
- THERE'S
A GREAT SENSE OF RELIEF.
- THEY'RE DANCING?
- YEAH, LIKE THIS.
- AS WE BEGIN EVALUATING
THE LOSS OF LIFE--
- YOU WANT TO SEE IT?
I'LL BRING THE TV IN HERE.
- I SEE THE SAME EXPRESSION
ON EVERY FACE.
WE KNOW THE BATTLE TURNED
AROUND IN THE MIDDLE EAST.
THREE SMALL CITIES THERE
FOUND A PRIMITIVE METHOD
TO DEFEAT THEM.
WE HAVE NO FURTHER DETAILS
AT THIS TIME.
[TV turns off]
- [clicking and chattering]
- MERRILL, WAIT.
- HI, SWEETIE.
- HI, BABY.
- I WAS JUST TAKING A WALK
BEFORE DINNER.
- YOU LOVE WALKS.
- IT WAS MEANT TO BE.
- DOES IT HURT?
- I DON'T FEEL MUCH.
- GOOD.
- TELL MORGAN...
TO PLAY GAMES.
IT'S OKAY TO BE SILLY.
- [crying] I WILL.
- TELL BO
TO LISTEN TO HER BROTHER.
HE'LL ALWAYS TAKE CARE OF HER.
- I WILL.
- AND TELL GRAHAM--
- I'M HERE.
- TELL HIM...
SEE.
TELL HIM TO SEE.
AND TELL MERRILL
TO SWING AWAY.
- SEE, WHAT YOU
HAVE TO ASK YOURSELF IS,
WHAT KIND OF PERSON ARE YOU?
ARE YOU THE KIND
THAT SEES SIGNS, SEES MIRACLES?
OR DO YOU BELIEVE
THAT PEOPLE JUST GET LUCKY?
IS IT POSSIBLE...
THERE ARE NO COINCIDENCES?
- [clicking and chattering]
- SWING AWAY, MERRILL.
MERRILL...
SWING AWAY.
- [screaming]
[thud]
- [hissing]
[groaning]
[clicking and hissing]
- AAH!
- [gasping]
- THAT'S WHY HE HAD ASTHMA.
IT CAN'T BE LUCK.
HIS LUNGS WERE CLOSED.
NO POISON GOT IN.
DON'T TOUCH HIM.
GIVE HIM A MINUTE.
- GRAHAM? [crying]
- GIVE HIM A SECOND.
- DADDY?
- DON'T TOUCH HIM.
- GRAHAM.
- DON'T...DON'T.
- DAD?
WHAT HAPPENED?
DID SOMEONE SAVE ME?
- YEAH, BABY,
I THINK SOMEONE DID.
[Bo and Morgan laughing]
[Merrill speaking indistinctly]