S
St
Sty
StyL
StyLi
StyLis
StyLish
StyLishS
StyLishSa
StyLishSaL
StyLishSaLH</font
(PANTING)
(MOANING)
(SNORTING)
(COUGHING)
RON: How much
do you want, Daddy?
CLINT: Twenty time.
Fifty? Yeah, 50.
D'ya hear Rock Hudson
was a cock sucker?
Where d'ya hear that shit?
It's called a newspaper. Right there.
It's a shame, ain't it?
All that fine Hollywood
pussy just all being wasted
on a guy who smokes
his fucking friends.
Rog, this ain't the sandbox.
Twenty minimum. C'mon.
Shit. God damn.
Cheap son of a bitch.
I'm tryin'.
I got it, I got it.
Who the hell's
Rock Hudson anyway?
He's an actor, dumb-ass! You
ever seen North by Northwest?
(COUGHING)
MAN ON PA: Hey, I've got a question for
everybody, who wants to bull ride? Hey!
(CONTINUES COUGHING)
One more time, make some noise!
Clap your hands,
stomp your feet!
It's bull ride time!
Let's bull ride!
You're sitting there at America's
number one spectator event.
The spills, the thrills,
the bumps, the bruises.
It's all part of America's number
one spectator event, bull riding!
All right.
Calm the nerves, brother.
This is your day,
I can feel it.
Shit, I don't know, Ron.
Well, I do.
Eight seconds,
and look at this. Hey! Hey!
$640, all right? You do that,
and you're going to get blown
by a hundred dollar
hooker before you can
scrape the bull shit
off your boots, brother.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Eat that motherfucker! Mmm?
Clap your hands, stomp your
feet, make some noise!
It's bull ride time!
Ready?
Nine to five,
come on, make some noise!
Yeah!
Four one thousand.
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
Fuck!
My God!
MAN 1: Hold it!
MAN 2: You get back here,
you motherfucker!
Everyone get with
that man, c'mon!
Tucker!
I need you to arrest me!
Fuck off, Wood roof!
C'mon man! No shit!
Looks like you got a bunch
of pissed off customers.
Fuck you!
You gonna cuff me or not?
No! Figure it out yourself.
MAN: Son of a bitch!
C'mon! Back off!
Or I'll arrest all of you!
Son of a bitch!
TUCKER: They're gonna kick the shit outta
you someday, Woodroof. Maybe worse.
RON: Yeah,
you gotta die somehow.
Handle your business, huh?
Get your shit together.
Shit, Tuck, you're starting to
sound like a goddamn old man.
How's he doing anyway?
There's good days and bad.
(COUGHS)
Oh, he's a tough old outlaw.
Just can't imagine
how disappointed he must be
in having a cop for a son.
Get the fuck outta my car.
Thanks for the lift, man.
(GRUNTS)
Fuck! You okay?
You rattled my brain.
What brain?
(COUGHING)
Arright, Clinto,
that shit is purer than a preacher's
daughter's pussy right there.
Not after you've just coughed
your lungs all over it.
One dollar.
I got your dollar.
There we go.
Hey, you thinking anymore
about Saudi Arabia?
They need guys over there.
Fuck, no.
Why d'you wanna go work for a bunch
of sand niggers anyway, huh?
'Cause they pay five times
as much, that's why.
Mmm-hmm. That's right.
I'm signing up.
They got hot ass over there?
It's a Muslim country.
Can't fuck the women.
That takes me right out, then.
Woodroof! There's been
an accident on platform 5.
They need an
electrician right away.
Yes, sir!
All right, check ya later.
All right.
Adios! Get to work,
lazy fucker!
Let me see that
preacher's daughter's pussy.
Dumbass spic. How'd ya get
your leg in there?
Ambulance coming?
He's illegal.
Call a fucking ambulance.
Call it! Fuck!
I need an ambulance.
I'mma shut it down.
Platform 5, ASAP. There's a man down.
Repeat, man down.
His leg's caught in the drill.
M r. Wood roof?
I see you found our stash!
(CHUCKLES)
I'm Dr. Sevard.
Why don't you go ahead
and hop up here for me,
if you don't mind. Thank you.
(SIGHS)
I like your shoes.
We saw something which concerned
us on your initial blood work,
so we ran some
additional tests.
Some blood tests.
What kind of blood tests?
I don't use drugs.
We didn't test
your blood for drugs.
Well good. 'Cause it ain't
any y'all business anyway.
SEVARD: That's right.
Um...
You've tested positive for HIV.
Which is the virus
that causes AIDS.
You fucking kidding me?
Telling me that fucking Rock
cock sucking Hudson bullshit?
Mr. Woodroof, have you ever
used intravenous drugs?
Have you ever engaged
in homosexual conduct?
Homo? Did you say homo?
Yep! That's what
you said isn't it?
Shit, you fucking kidding me'?
I ain't no faggot,
motherfucker!
I don't even know
no fucking faggots.
Look at me.
What d'you see, huh?
The goddamn rodeo's
what you see!
SEVARD: Mr. Woodroof.
A'ight, so fucking watch it.
Mr. Woodroof, could you just...
No, I can't do shit, you speak
fucking English, motherfucker.
Call me a motherfucking faggot.
I'll whip your
fucking ass, boy.
Your T-cell count
is down to nine.
A healthy person has
between 500 and 1,500.
So frankly, we're surprised
you're even alive.
Surprise is, you made
a fucking mistake.
Must have mixed up
my blood samples
with some daisy puller
or something,
'cause that shit ain't me.
We ran the blood test
several times.
Here's some information
about HIV and AIDS
that you might
find informative,
and these are
your test results.
Mr. Woodroof, if you could
listen to me for a moment.
I know this can be
a very scary thing,
I know you're probably feeling
overwhelmed right now,
but we would like to impress upon
you the gravity of your situation.
Based on your health, on your
condition, on all the evidence we have,
we estimate you have 3O days left
to put your affairs in order.
Thirty days?
I'm sorry.
Fuck this. This is shit.
Fucking 30 day motherfuckers. Let
me give y'all a little newsflash.
There ain't nothing out there that
can kill Ron Woodroof in 3O days.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHING)
(SNIFFLES)
T.J.: Shit, damn doctor
cut your balls off?
Shit, tell 'em you got a cold,
man, they give you two weeks off.
You should try it. (SNORTS)
Well, you didn't
miss nothing at work.
Shit, I'd take
disability any day.
I tell them I got
a fucking cough,
and they tell me I got some
kind of HIV virus. Shit.
Fuck. Like I got AIDS.
(SCOFFS)
Fucking hospitals man,
mixed up my blood samples.
Shit. I went to
the doctor's one time,
and they tell me
I had chlamydia.
I get back home,
I had fucking crabs.
It's what the fuck
I'm saying, man.
You tell 'em you
got a headache,
they tell ya
you got brain cancer.
Mmm-hmm. Shit, I hear
you can get that
just by touching someone,
or queers get it.
Fucking faggots.
That's it,
exactly why it's a mistake.
Well, what if it ain't?
What if what ain't?
A mistake.
(LAUGHING)
Fucker.
Shit, I know you got a pussy
addiction, motherfucker.
Yeah.
Hey, Salt, hello, Pepper.
God damn.
Mmm.
We going?
Yeah, we going.
Hey, you wanna take
these ladies for a twirl?
You all head out man, I'm good.
I'll catch up with
you all, all right?
T.J.: Yeah? You all right, brother?
You cool?
I'm cool.
All right. See you there.
All right, see ya in a little
bit, Miss Alaska, Miss Louisiana.
KELLY: Bye, cowboy.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SNIFFLES)
Azidothymidine, or AZT,
was originally developed
as a treatment for cancer.
With the onset of HIV, however,
we at Avonex Industries
began a trial,
in which we administered AZT
to infected lab animals.
Initial findings suggested
increased CD4 counts,
restored T-cell immunity...
Isn't it also the case
that there were some
troubling side effects
with the animal tests?
Significant decreases in the red and
white blood cells in the animals?
Yes, but its effect
on the virus
is better than anything
else that's been tested.
Well, in '64, when AZT was
developed as a cancer treatment,
it was shelved clue to lack of
anti-cancer efficacy and toxicity.
Right.
We believe those problems
were dosage based.
So, you're gonna conduct
another animal study?
Actually, the FDA's
given us permission
to go straight to human trials.
Which is what
brings me here today.
We're conducting
a double-blind,
placebo-controlled
randomized trial
throughout the United States.
Dallas Mercy is one
of the proposed sites.
How long do you see
the trial going on?
We're hoping to fast track it.
Within a year?
During which time, the hospital
and its
administering physicians
will be very well compensated
for their efforts.
Sadly, the AIDS crisis will only
get worse before it gets better.
And I know I speak for
everyone at Avonex when I say
this is a unique opportunity.
A chance to be on the
forefront in finding a cure.
Does it not drive you
just a little bit crazy
to see these guys talking
about curing the sick
when they flash
their gold Rolexes?
What do they know about
treating a sick patient?
Hey, they're big pharma
reps, they're not doctors.
And like it or not,
this is a business.
How'd they get permission to
go straight to human trial?
People are desperate.
People are dying.
There's nothing else out there.
(COUGHING)
(CLEARING THROAT)
Fuck!
I need to see Dr. Sevard.
Dr. Sevard's not here today.
I can't wait 'til tomorrow.
If you tell me what the problem
is, maybe I can help you.
You want a list of
my problems, huh?
My lungs are bleeding,
my skin's crawling,
I got a fucking
jackhammer in my head,
and that's the least of
my fucking problems, lady.
EVE: Mr. Wood roof?
No. No, no, no, no.
I don't want a nurse.
I want a doctor. I want
a goddamn doctor now.
Well, how can I help you?
You fucking deaf, lady? Hmm?
No, I'm a fucking doctor!
If you want to discuss
your list of problems,
you can meet me in my office
in 20 minutes.
Okay?
I like your style, Doc!
(KNOCKS)
M r. Wood roof.
Can you get me AZT?
Avonex Industries say they've
just released it for testing.
I wanna buy some.
Now.
That isn't how it works.
For about a year,
a group of patients
gets either the drug
or a placebo.
It's totally left up to chance,
not even doctors
are allowed to know.
So, you're giving
dying people sugar pills?
It's the only way to
know if a drug works.
Can you get some for me?
I got cash.
I can go a month, a week,
however you want to do it.
I hear you.
Unfortunately, no.
But when the drug
is proven to work,
and if you fit the
profile, then yes.
So, you're tellin' me
I'm as good as a horse
being sold for dog food, huh?
Okay.
Look here, how 'bout this
stuff overseas, huh?
Germany, they got this
Dextran Sulfate, a'ight?
And they got
this DDC in France,
supposed to keep
the healthy cells you got
from getting the HIV.
And they got
AL721 over in Israel.
How can I get some of this?
None of those drugs have
been approved by the FDA.
Screw the FDA.
I'm gonna be DOA.
I gotta sue the hospital
to get my medicine?
Mr. Woodroof, I assure you that that
would be a waste of your precious time.
There is a support group that
meets daily in Draddy Auditorium.
I suggest you try it out
and maybe go talk about your
feelings, your concerns.
I'm dying.
You telling me to go get a
hug from a bunch of faggots?
Good day.
Hey, Neddie Jay!
Gimme a shot of cactus
and a Bud back.
God damn.
Hard to say how much
I missed y'alls ugly mugs.
Hey, say Clinto, where are you
hanging your pants these days?
Get me another beer
will you, sweetheart?
Fuck you say?
I said grab me a cold
one, sugarcakes.
You looking to
get your ass kicked?
Nah, I don't want none of
that faggot blood on me.
Hey, Ron, c'mon! God damn it!
Fucker!
Hey, c'mon. We don't want
any trouble, all right?
It's that motherfucker
who's got the fucking problem.
The fuck's your problem, huh?
Hey, Ron, I don't want
no trouble, all right?
(SPITTING)
Fuck y'all, man.
Fuck all y'all!
Goddammit, he spit on my face.
You got any soap?
Gimme a towel. C'mon!
Jesus fucking Christ.
So as I stand here tonight,
clinical trials are underway
with an eye toward
fast-tracking AZT
and making it available for the
public as soon as possible.
In short, I'm happy to say that
help may finally be on the way.
WOMAN: How long before
the drug's approved?
MAN: Yeah.
The FDA's standard procedure to approve
a new drug is eight to 12 years.
(PEOPLE GRUMBLING)
Hey, it's your
first time, right?
Back the fuck off, Tinkerbell.
I'll knock your teeth so
far in your goddamn throat
you're gonna be chewing
through your asshole.
MAN: What about
Dextran Sulfate?
We're working
closely with the FDA
to make sure every effort
is made to fast-track...
WOMAN: We don't have time.
RICK FERRIS: It's both our job and the
FDA's to make sure the drug is safe.
MAN 1: We don't have that long.
MAN 2: We're dead, right?
RICK FERRIS: We're going as
fast as possible, believe me.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Just need to slow it down
a little bit.
Just gimme time to catch
my breath, will you?
I ain't ready to crawl in a corner.
I just ain't fucking ready.
So, you better be
listening, all right?
If I got one fucking
chance, show me a sign.
Just show me a fucking sign.
If you're not gonna look or buy a
dance, you could at least tip me.
Here's $20.
The dance, it ain't for me.
You just keep on
shaking it, he'll see ya.
(COUGHING)
MAN ON RADIO: A beautiful
day in Dallas, Texas.
Just hope you had your coffee. Sunshine today.
It's gonna be mid 80$...
(TURNS ENGINE OFF)
(STARTING ENGINE)
Right here, motherfuckers!
There ain't no more.
They started locking it up.
I got the cash!
Here.
The fuck is this?
In Mexico,
a doctor, he has some.
The fuck is this bullshit?
You don't think I know what
you're fucking doing man? Huh?
EVE: Mr. Woodroof? Ron?
Ron?
Hi.
Beautiful.
You're in the hospital.
You almost died.
I bet that didn't
surprise anybody.
What is that, a smile?
EVE: You've had
a blood transfusion.
M r. Wood roof.
I'm Dr. Sevard.
Yeah. Hey, I remember you.
I need you to tell me where
you obtained AZT from.
How it got in your blood.
(SIGHS)
I don't know what
you're talking about.
(SCOFFS)
Dealing in pharmaceutical
drugs is illegal.
Yep.
Get some rest.
Where you goin'?
Hang on a second. We were
just getting somewhere.
MAN: Honey, you don't have
the slightest chance.
I'm Rayon.
Congratulations.
Fuck off and go back
to your bed.
Relax, I don't bite.
I guess you're handsome in a Texas
hick, white trash, dumb kinda way.
Get the fuck outta here,
whatever you are, before I
kick you in the fucking face.
God damn.
Fine, be an asshole.
You wanna play cards?
You got cash?
How's that strike your fancy?
You mind if I snuggle?
Stay at the end of the bed.
$10 minimum?
Be my guest.
All right,
Miss Man, what you got?
Full house. Jacks over threes.
Well, I'd have figured you for queens.
Motherfucker!
Sorry, damn' .
God damn it.
(GROANING)
You all right? Wait, relax.
Where's it at? I got you,
don't worry, just relax.
Relax. Breathe. Breathe.
Right there. Right there.
That's it, that's it. Breathe.
Get it. Get it.
I got it. I got it. That's it.
Here, let me
get you some water.
Here, drink this, darlin'.
Drink this.
Oh, you gotta stay hydrated, or
else your muscles will cramp.
(EXHALING)
Is that better?
Yeah.
It's better, I got it. It's good.
I'll work that for you.
It's good. It's good.
God, you got nice feet.
Jesus Christ, I'm straight.
All right?
What the fuck
you in here for, anyway?
The AZT trial.
My friend is paying me
to split my dose with him,
that way, we'll both get some.
How much he paying you?
Five grand. What?
I coulda charged him 20.
Hey!
If I want in,
will you sell me some?
I'm sorry, sweetie.
I can't split my dose
in thirds.
Besides, I made a deal.
Anyone who plays cards like you
ain't got five grand, anyhow.
Yeah, right here.
(SIGHS) My Lord, sometimes you can't
get a moment's rest around here.
This guy,
and if you could just...
Mr. Wood roof!
Where are you going?
I signed myself out.
You're too sick to leave here.
Worst case scenario being what?
We can make you comfortable.
What? Hook me up to the morphine
drip, let me fade on out?
Nah. Sorry lady, but I prefer
to die with my boots on.
I still live here, you hear me?
I still fucking live here!
Fuck you!
(COUNTRY MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(SHUTS OFF ENGINE)
(sesame)
(COUGHING)
"RON". I'm looking for Dr. Vass.
Speak UP-
I'm looking for AZT.
You won't find that shit here.
Looking to poison yourself?
(COUGHS)
Jesus fucking Christ. Maria?
Check him in.
Cocaine, alcohol,
methamphetamine,
AZT?
Well, that's what I call
a recipe for disaster.
This place is a shithole, Doc.
Who said I was a doctor?
They revoked my license to
practice three years ago.
That's why I'm
down in this shithole.
Why? What did you do?
These drugs you're doing, they're
breaking down your immune system.
Making you susceptible
to infection.
You're saying cocaine's
givin' me pneumonia?
No, I'm saying cocaine
made you more susceptible,
as did the AZT.
Nah, the AZT's
what was helping me.
The only people AZT helps
are the people who sell it.
It kills every cell it
comes in contact with.
I'm gonna prescribe a regimen of
vitamins as well as the mineral zinc,
it'll build up
your immune system.
You'll also be taking aloe
and essential fatty acids.
Sound fun?
You missed your last
trial appointment, Ray.
Where were you?
Do you like this dress, 'cause I think
the neckline's a little plunging.
Rayon, the whole
purpose of this study
is to determine
if AZT is helping people.
C'mon, Evey, you know there
ain't no helping me.
That doesn't mean
I'm gonna stop trying.
Why are you so good to me?
Bless your little heart.
Shut up.
Just promise me you'll show
up for the rest of the trial.
I promise you that
I will try my very best.
I want you to mean it.
Okay.
Is that Marcus from Home Ec?
I swear to God!
He has grown up, my Lord!
A little too plunging
by the way, I think, yes.
I appreciate your honesty.
Damn it.
(MAN COUGHING)
RON: Well?
Better. T-cell
count's improving.
I Still got HIV?
You'll always test
positive for HIV.
And now you've got AIDS
'cause of all the toxic shit
you've been putting in your body.
You shot your immune system.
Now you got chronic pneumonia,
among other things.
It can cause memory loss,
mood swings, aching joints.
If it sucks, I got it.
Yeah.
I can't get my cock up,
all that shit.
If it is shit,
I got it, don't I?
Yeah, well, let's not start
a pity party too soon.
That is DDC.
It acts as an antiviral, similar
to AZT, but less toxic.
And this is Peptide T.
It's a protein,
totally non-toxic.
Early studies have shown that
this can help with all that.
It's what I've been giving
you since you got here.
You can't buy this in the USA?
Not approved.
Shit.
Look at this place.
Fucking chinks, homos,
herbs, hot nurses.
You got a regular New World
Order going on here, Vass.
You could be making
a fortune off of this.
VASS: You get caught,
don't say you got AIDS.
They'll never let you back in.
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH ON RADIO)
(TURNS ENGINE OFF)
And a blessed day to you, sir.
Have a blessed day.
Whoa.
(URINATING)
Anything to declare?
WOMAN: No, nothing.
Have a good day. Thank you.
And a blessed day to you, sir.
Father, passport please.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Anything to declare?
No, sir, nada.
You're a priest? Yes, I am.
I'm Richard Barkley from the Food
and Drug Administration office.
How can I help you,
Mr. Barkley?
Well...
You have over 3,000 pills here.
You're only allowed to
bring in a 90-day supply.
Yes, as I was telling
the gentleman earlier,
I'm a sick man.
I happen to have cancer.
I take 33 pills a day.
These are my vials of vitamins,
that is a non-toxic
protein serum.
This is my 90-day supply.
Vitamins?
You do realize that importing
illegal drugs for sale,
it's a very serious offense.
Well, of course it is,
and as I said,
they're not for sale,
nor are they illegal.
Merely unapproved.
If we get the slightest
indication that
you're selling
these drugs for profit,
you could be thrown in jail
for a very long time, Father.
Hand to God, I promise to take every
single one of these pills myself.
My life depends on them, son.
Cowboy, you coming in?
Fuckin' kiddin' me?
This man also
had a transfusion.
The AZT, we can tell who's
on it by the symptoms.
Most of them need new blood.
He's actually getting worse.
So why are they
stopping the trial?
What d'you mean?
Avonex Industries.
You didn't see the memo?
Claim most people are feeling
better, and fewer people are dying.
Transfusions always make
patients feel better.
Give the placebo patients new
blood, they'll feel better, too.
I have questions about
the drug's safety, David.
It's dropping white blood cells
in a lot of my patients.
Yeah, well,
it's their call, Eve,
so we can get the drug to the
people who actually need it.
But after eight months?
Well, the test results were
overwhelmingly positive. AZT works.
We don't know what the long-term effects are.
It's irresponsible.
These people die, Eve.
There are no long-term effects.
Can I read a copy of the study?
Still being written.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Jesus fucking Christ,
you fucking idiot!
I've been looking
for you, Lonestar.
Know I coulda killed you, huh?
I feel better,
I wanted to thank you.
Well, good for you, now get
the fuck outta my car.
I need more of that
cocktail shit you got.
Listen, Tinkerbell, unless you
got more cash or new clients,
I'm busy, now get
the fuck outta my car.
Let's just do this quickly
so I can get the fuck out.
You got enough for 20 of us?
Yep!
You know what?
You don't deserve our money,
you homophobic asshole.
(SLAMS DOOR)
Toodaloo!
(SIGHS) Am I fuckin'
dreamin' or what?
I got your 20 in the trunk.
Find me 2O more, cut you in.
Five percent.
Adios, cowboy.
Fuck's your problem?
I can handle your insults,
but five percent?
A'ight, 10.
Twenty five,
take it or leave it.
I don't have all day.
God damn it.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Deal?
Deal.
We'll take care of y'all.
Two T's, one Vit.
How much is on each bottle.
Rayon!
Where the fuck you going?
C'mon in, it's a fucking
bore out here!
God damn it.
(CLUB MUSIC PLAYING)
He with the most honey
attracts the most bees.
Yep.
Lots of customers
here, darling.
A little smile
would go a long way.
Ever hear of Peptide T?
(CHEERING)
Thank you.
Fuck off.
RAYON: Ronnie, where you going?
You've got to be kiddin' me.
This place is perfect. We wanna
lay low, not get busted.
Besides, I got a plan.
Well, it's very in, turquoise.
Right up your alley-
This place is disgusting.
We have got to disinfect.
Do not use the word "we."
Now, you wanna put your apron
on, start cleaning shit up.
I wouldn't know where to start.
Well, howdy, Counselor.
Hi, I'm Rayon.
That's my partner.
Business partner.
Your office is next door.
Have fun, boys.
(READING IN SPANISH)
Now, this is all
for your personal use?
Oh, absolutely.
I got you the paperwork
for your corporation.
I do not wanna know
what that is for.
Well, I ain't selling
drugs no more, Counselor.
I'm givin' them away, for
free by selling memberships.
Four hundred dollars
a month in dues,
and you get all
the meds you want.
You son of a bitch.
Bitches. Plural.
There's a bunch of
faggots up in New York
runnin' a hell of
a racket just like this.
It's where I got the idea.
Welcome to the
Dallas Buyers Club.
WOMAN ON TV: Avonex
Industries announced today
that AZT has been approved as
the first drug to treat AIDS.
At the cost of $10,000
per year, per patient,
AZT is the most expensive
drug ever marketed.
Avonex stock jumped a whopping
12 percent today on the news.
I know. I hope he's okay, too. It's been too long.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNOCKING)
Oh, my Lord,
I'll call you back.
Michael and Ian, the happiest
couple in the entire universe.
Oh, my God. Gimme some sugar.
Ian, you look like
a two dollar bill.
Hold on, you just
stay right here, okay?
I'm so glad that you came.
We're gonna fix you up.
Ronnie, we got
two new customers.
You call me Ronnie again,
I'm gonna use this to give you that
sex change you've been hopin' for.
Send them in.
RAYON: Meet the big boss.
C'mon in.
Oh, shit, sorry.
C'mon, sit down.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Rayon, turn that shit down!
Meds and the
treatments are free,
but membership is $400 a month.
All right? You're gonna
hafta sign a waiver.
We are not responsible for
the drugs that we give you.
You croak, you croak. It's
not our problem. It's yours.
We have some AZT,
and it helped Ian a
little in the beginning.
All right, first off, flush
that shit down the toilet.
It's bad news.
Secondly, stay away from anything
that's gonna cook your insides.
You gotta stay clean.
Third, if your brain's broke,
your wires are crossed,
I got a little something called Peptide
T, it's gonna fix you right up.
Clear? I got a starter pack.
I'll have more in a week.
Until then, watch what you eat
and who you eat.
$400.
Rayon, give me some coffee.
RAYON: Coming up, Ronnie.
EVE: He didn't call,
leave a message?
No, nothing.
He did change his
address recently.
Thanks.
Shohu Okaiku? Uh-huh.
Interferon.
How much can I buy from you?
Yes, Mr. Yamata.
Let me figure out
how much I can
take off your hands.
Listen, I'm gonna
hafta call you back.
Mr. Yamata, I have to go, I'm gonna
call you back, okay? Yes. Arigato.
What are you doing here?
Well, I live here.
Where's Rayon?
You roommates?
Not exactly.
What are you doing here?
Roger Thompson?
This is my patient.
You treating these people?
They're treatin' themselves.
With what?
Vitamins, Peptide T, DDC, anything
but that poison you're hawkin'.
Say, you ever wear any color?
Seems like every time I see
you, all I see is white.
You have a white coat,
white shoes, white...
Tell Rayon I was
looking for him,
and I'm telling my patients
to stay away from here.
(KNOCKING)
Excuse me.
Say you wanna go grab a steak
sometime, I know it's red, but...
That's the shit
that'll rot your insides.
What a surprise. FDA approved.
The fuck is potassium benzoate?
Preservative.
You kiddin' me? Hey, don't pollute
me with this processed crap.
I'm eatin' healthy,
and you should too.
It's protein,
it's good for you.
It's processed, put it back.
You can't tell me what to do.
Such a bully!
Hey, Ron.
Hey, what say, T.J.?
How you doin', man?
Oh, just trying to make a
livin', you know how it is.
Yeah, I do.
Jesus, fucking
faggots everywhere.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, T.J., this is Rayon.
Rayon, T.J.
Hey.
He said hi to you,
shake his hand.
C'mon, buddy,
what's your problem?
Fuck you.
(GRUNTING)
Shake his hand, T.J. C'mon.
Shake his hand, T.J.
Give him a good one.
All right? All right.
Now, will you fuck off?
Go on back to
your miserable life.
Hmm?
What?
Put 'em back.
All right, guys, hang in there,
we'll get you
hooked up shortly.
Fifty bucks?
No. A'ight? You ain't got the
money, you don't join the club.
Hey, everybody!
Let's get this straight.
Membership, 400 bucks.
If you're a member,
you get the meds.
If you're not a member,
you don't. Got it?
I'm not running
a goddamn charity.
You need $350 more.
(SNIFFLES)
Your bags are all packed
and here's your ticket.
(SNIFFLING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, Ray!
Fuckin' high?
None of your business.
Well, when it concerns
my business,
it sure the fuck
is my business.
If I can't trust you,
it is my business.
You motherfucker.
Denise, get in here!
You're in charge.
No! You can trust me. Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Fucking junkie,
look at you,
you're a fucking mess!
Oh, God.
Get your shit straight.
Or I'll chunk you to the curb along
with your 25 fuckin' percent.
Quit acting like
a little bitch!
Have my new Caddy at the
airport for when I get back,
and watch over
that fucking monkey.
M r. Wood roof.
Mmm.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Regarding your order. Mmm-hmm.
I am so sorry but we
are no longer allowed
to export interferon
to United States.
Well, what d'you mean, Doc?
We discussed this two weeks
ago on the telephone.
I was not aware of the
regulation two weeks ago.
I am sorry. I know
you've come a long way.
Fourteen hours on a plane
but, hey, who gives
a shit though, right?
Look, if it's about money. I could
make it worth your while, all right?
I've got a briefcase
full of cash right here.
Please, understand.
Japanese doctors would be the only
ones who can make the purchase.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Slow drip.
Interferon?
Very strong.
God damn, I like
your style, Hiroshi.
Okay, prepare the sedation.
Ten milligrams of Propofol.
Can I have your
passport please?
Yes, have Dr. Sevard
proceed until I get there.
I've gotta go.
Where you coming from?
Oh, excuse me, um, Japan.
Medical research.
Good to be back in the USA.
Thank you, sir.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
SEVARD: We don't know what the drugs are.
He's got HIV,.
Wood roof?
AIDS. I got AIDS.
Won't you come on in,
join the party.
Ah, Mr. Wood roof.
Dr. See-vard.
I'll bet you're
surprised to see me.
Well, you nearly
killed yourself,
so we need to know where
you acquired the drugs.
Well, I need to know
just exactly
what you're pumping into
my bloodstream here, Doc.
All right, this is
a combination of AZT,
and you've also got
a full spectrum of...
Don't! Don't!
I'm suing you for
attempted murder.
Where's my stuff, Barkley?
Your stuff gave you
a heart attack.
Go to hell.
I'll say what goes
in my body, not you.
That decision, like it or not, is left
up to the people in this hospital.
What d'you think, I'm one of your
goddamn guinea pigs, Sevard, huh?
I look like a rodent to you?
Mr. Woodroof,
you think you're clever?
You shoot your body
full of an unknown drug
and you smuggle
in a two year supply.
Well, hear this.
I will bust you.
I will take your drugs and I
will burn them. You're done.
SEVARD: You're a fool if you
think you're helping yourself.
That's right, fucking
fooled you, didn't I?
You said I'd be dead in 30 days,
well, howdy fuckin' doody,
because it's a year later,
and look who's still here.
I'm done with you.
RAYON: Ronnie!
You have anything
left to say to me,
you say it to my real doctor,
Dr. Eve Saks,
and you,
you bring a fucking army.
Mr. Woodroof,
please get back in the bed.
Enjoy the view!
The hell is goin' on in here?
Dr. Eve's good though, right?
Talk straight to
my fucking face.
You're his physician, and you can't
tell me what medications he's on?
He came in here once for advice
and I have no idea what he
does outside this hospital.
Well, the FDA just confiscated
2,000 vials of alpha interferon,
which he was about to sell to
AIDS patients, to our patients.
Actually, I've been reading
a lot about Buyers Clubs.
They've been
having some success
eliminating symptoms with
some of these new drugs.
Yeah, and without controlled trials,
we're not gonna find a cure
because we're not gonna
have any legitimate data.
So tell your patients
to stay away from him.
Yes, sir.
RAYON'. No.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Hold on, I said hold on!
This guy says that the Florida
Buyers Club is cheaper.
Well, tell him to go back to
the fucking Sunshine State!
DAVID: That's what I'm telling
you, I can't get it back.
What d'you mean you can't get it back?
It was authorized by a doctor!
The FDA said it was a Japanese
doctor with no legal standing.
What can I say?
They make it up as they go.
God damn it!
All right, check Amsterdam,
China and Israel,
'cause that's
where the fuck I'm going!
RON: I like your style, Doc!
Good doing business with you.
If I don't trust the white coat
who's trying to
sell me the drugs,
I FedEx it to Seattle to my lab
there, and they test it for me.
Then I test it all on myself
before I give it to anyone.
I respect that you're
learning about your illness,
but some of these people
need to be in the hospital.
Why? All they want
to serve up is AZT.
AZT helps eradicate the virus.
Fuck the virus! Dr. Saks,
you know this.
Once you got the virus, you're
married to it. AZT or not.
I'm talking about
symptoms and survival.
Look, I'm no scientist,
but shit...
(LAUGHING) You're not 'cause
you sound so scientific.
Are you fuckin' high again?
Uh...
Nope.
Why are my fucking
walls painted red?
It's cranberry mocha,
it's for the holidays.
All right, look, people can
live with this disease
longer than they're
saying, right?
Ninety six percent of the people
in the USA who have AIDS today
are gonna die
within six months.
I know the statistics.
Then use them.
You don't give AZT to somebody with
a broken immune system, it's toxic.
If you're abusing it
like you did,
and you're just taking it without
any medical surveillance,
of course it is.
Yeah, I did abuse it.
But I'm off it now, look at me.
I'm here. Feeling great.
And I'm not the only one.
Why is Boy George's mug
all over my fucking room?
It's Marc Bolan, silly.
It's another babe
for your wall of shame.
Get out, both of you.
Take your sunflower
and get the fuck out.
Oh, c'mon, I'm not finished yet.
Now. Get out.
Isn't he cute?
Where the hell are
my trial patients?
We need you to
fill out this form.
We need your name, your
address, phone number,
your complete medical history
and bring it back to me.
RON: Denise!
Excuse me.
Who's the girl?
She's a customer.
She's HIV positive?
She's got full blown AIDS.
Need your phone numbers,
and here I'm gonna need your
complete medical history,
because we need to know
what's going on before you...
(MOANING)
No, no, off the Caddy.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Oh, for fuck's sake.
No, you stick it in, pussy.
Who d'you think's gonna do
that when I'm not here?
Don't.
Stick it in!
I swear, Ray,
God sure was
dressing the wrong doll
when he blessed you
with a set of balls.
Gimme that.
Now, look, it's one thing
for me not to like ya,
but why can't you be
a better friend to yourself?
If I really thought you were
interested, I'd tell you.
What you doin' here?
The IRS. You're being audited.
Oh, fuck.
Now here's a couple of the
government's finest right there, huh?
Good job, boys, great stuff. It's
how they got Al Capone isn't it?
Don't piss 'em off. If there's
a fine, we'll pay it.
Well, if there's a fine,
no, you wanna fine me, huh?
How much you want?
Ten grand? Twenty grand?
You think that's gonna stop me?
What's your
fucking number, huh?
What is it? Huh?
Take this, motherfucker!
Operations are expected to
return to normal today
at FDA headquarters
outside Washington,
a day after the arrest
of 175 demonstrators.
The protesters, some of
whom are dying from AIDS,
blocked the entrances
to the FDA complex.
They were demanding
faster action
on new drugs to
treat the deadly virus.
(HUMMING)
You don't have a snowball's chance
in hell wearing that thing.
Rayon, I can assure you
that I do not need help picking
up ladies from your sorry ass.
Trailer trash and rodeo groupies
do not count as ladies.
You get her flowers?
Oh, hell! Mmm-hmm.
Have a good time, girls.
Oh, Ron.
(LAUGHS)
Wildflowers, Texas style.
That's for you. Really?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, that's beautiful.
I don't even hafta water them.
Nope. Thank you.
Thanks for coming.
Sure.
Guess who paid me a
little visit today. Who?
IRS. They're trying
to run me out of town.
Got any idea who might
have tipped them off?
You don't believe
that I would actually...
No, no, not you. That snake you work
for, that's my prime candidate.
I gotta ask you if you can
watch what you say around him,
I mean, 'cause he's
got a hard-on for me.
As a matter of fact, if you heard
anything, hear anything in his office
that might concern me or the
business, I'd sure appreciate
you share with me.
Appreciate it.
Hello sir, bring us your
best bottle of Cabernet.
(SIGHS)
Nice restaurant,
beautiful woman,
swear I feel
like a human again.
Why are we here?
Well just for this, wine, dine,
have a good time,
enjoy ourselves.
Right.
It's as simple as that, I promise you, doll.
C'mon, try it with me.
Breathe.
Relax, smell the steak.
If you need more inspiration,
just look at the handsome man
sitting across the table from you,
paying for your dinner tonight.
(LAUGHING)
Huh? All right.
Why d'you become a doctor?
Really?
Why'd I become a doctor? Um...
I was good at science
and my dad said that studying
history was a waste of time,
so I went to med school.
Your dad sounds like a practical man.
He was.
Your turn, what about you?
Why did you become...
Electrician. An electrician?
Right.
My dad was an electrician,
pretty darn good one, too.
He was a hell of
a lot better drinker.
I can imagine.
Anyway, I was around it a
lot, the electrician part.
Got kinda good at it.
Liked to open shit up,
check out the insides,
put it back together,
hell, somebody thought
I was good enough at it
to pay me
a little money for it,
so I kept some change in my
pocket and I ended up being
the proud owner
of a Texaco card.
What about your mom?
Mom was a painter.
Um...
Kind of a gypsy woman.
She got tired of the bullshit and
all that, you know how it is?
She paint this? Yep.
Your mom?
Yep.
You ain't gotta
hang it or nothin',
I mean, I know, like,
you like everything perfect.
I do not.
I will hang this.
I'm gonna hang this.
Good.
Don't you wanna keep it?
You enjoy your life,
little lady.
You only got one.
Yes, sir, that's
my favorite grape juice.
Hey, thanks for coming.
To wild flowers!
And bottle and rib eyes.
(SHALLOW BREATHING)
I'm gonna kill him.
(KNOCKING)
See you next week.
RICHARD: I have a court order
permitting me to confiscate...
RAYON: You all are handsome,
but if you don't have a search
warrant, you ain't coming in.
Ron!
RON: The hell is this?
Sorry, Ron.
Gentlemen, I'm gonna need y'all
to leave the premises in
an orderly fashion, please.
Mr. Woodroof, I have a court order
permitting us to confiscate
any and all non FDA-approved
drugs or supplements.
My entire inventory.
That's aloe vera, sir.
It's a plant.
How the shit d'you
care if people eat plants?
It's improperly labeled.
That's a violation
of FDA regulations.
That's a bullshit technicality,
and you know it.
Rayon, get my lawyer on the phone.
Yeah!
We're concerned with preventing
a market for illegal drugs.
What's illegal about a bunch
of vitamins and minerals, huh?
Vitamins and minerals that gave
you a heart attack, remember?
No, I ain't selling
them no more,
you confiscated them, remember?
What, you got
Alzheimer's, Richard?
Take some of that Peptide T.
Fixes that, too.
No, I remember these.
Yeah, it's a fuckin' protein.
For dementia, which I have.
And for the hundredth time, just
take a fucking look at my research.
Mr. Woodroof,
I wouldn't want you
to spend your
last days in jail.
If you have a product
that you want tested,
fill out an application
and go through the process.
Don't threaten me,
motherfucker.
The process. An FDA bullshit to pay up.
I know what the fuck that is.
You'll be getting your
fine for non-compliance
and improper labeling.
Yeah, shove it up your ass!
RAYON: Ron.
Your lawyer.
David!
David, listen.
These fuckers are coming
at me, man, from all angles.
I wanna file
a restraining order.
Against who?
Against the government and
the fucking FDA, that's who.
DO it!
WOMAN ON TV: Now the FDA is proposing a
permanent change in its regulations.
These new
regulations specifically
will have special criteria
that would apply to
immediately
life-threatening conditions,
recognizing that such patients
are willing to accept
the greater risk
than that which
normally would be the case.
WOMAN: The drugs may only be
purchased by individuals
who have been prescribed
the medication by a physician.
Now, what the hell
does that mean?
Means we were unapproved,
now we're illegal.
RAYON: You put the seat down?
Right!
Mmm-hmm.
Yep!
Now, I gotta get these MDs
to write some goddamn scripts
so we can keep dealing.
Mmm-hmm.
Look, I'm gonna stay on the
domestic side, all right,
I need you to check out
the internationals.
All right,
start with Amsterdam.
Right. There's a Dr. Bradley
out in Alberta.
He'll play ball with us.
All right, call me back.
Hey, Chelsea!
Get them smokies a round
of beers, will you?
The credit cards are maxed,
pharmacy bills are due.
You better hang on to your
money, honey. Mmm-hmm.
How 'bout that size, huh?
I think they'd look nice on me.
You ain't getting tits, Rayon.
Now look here, memberships
are high, so is demand,
so all we need is more members,
and where do we get those?
Uh...
Support groups. Exactly.
In the meantime,
we could try the bank.
Yeah! Bonnie and Clyde
coming in for a loan.
Would ya stop
staring at her tits, Rayon?
You're starting to look normal.
Oh, you keep the change,
honey, you deserve it.
What you got?
RON: Sorry to hear about
your dad's Alzheimer's, Tuck.
This stuff will help. Woodroof.
There we go.
This place is a shithole.
I'll give you $150 a month,
plus 20% off your memberships
for four months.
Mr. Wood roof. Now
don't try and con me.
We don't want money.
What the fuck you want?
The house is free.
We wanna help.
Well, that's good news.
Deal.
You fucking with me?
"RON". We got a club,
just down the street,
where you can get the meds
that I'm talking about.
We treat more than five times
the amount of patients
as large AIDS clinics,
and get this.
We got only
one-tenth the death ratio.
So, you wanna
be here some more?
Check us out,
here's my information.
Step on up,
let's do some business.
We're open 24/7.
She looks great.
I guess I didn't make the cut.
You made that choice yourself.
It wasn't a choice, Dad.
What do you want, Raymond?
Oh, I'm fine, thanks, and you?
Long time, no see.
I suppose I should thank you
for wearing men's clothes?
Not embarrassing me?
Are you ashamed of me, 'cause
I hadn't realized that.
(SIGHS) God help me.
He is helping you, I have AIDS.
(SNIFFLES)
I'm sorry, Dad.
I met somebody who's
been very kind to me
and I'd like to
repay that debt,
but I need help.
(SIGHS)
Please.
How's Mom?
Raymond.
Look, we're gonna
have to recoup it
under a different
name or something.
MAN: I understand
what you're saying,
even with this new
rule from the FDA.
I'm sorry. Mr. Woodroof,
I'm not changing my mind.
God damn it.
RAYON'. God, when I meet you,
I'm gonna be pretty,
if it's the last thing I do.
I'll be a beautiful angel.
(SIGHS)
Dr. Browning,
I understand, all right,
but do you understand
where I'm coming from? You...
Doc?
Not one fucking MD
will write me a script.
Not one. Motherfuckers.
Well, maybe this will help.
Where d'you get this?
D'you sell your ass?
Really,
where d'you get it?
I sold my life
insurance policy.
Not like I'm
gonna need it anyway.
Thank you.
(RON SINGING)
Guess who's going to Mexico
looking for a hot date, huh?
What d'you say?
Do I look like someone
who takes vacations?
Well, a little tequila, sunshine
and tacos never hurt anybody.
Sounds nice.
Is that a no? Mmm.
I kinda figured you
might rain on my party,
but I had to take a shot,
didn't I?
Listen, I'm onto something new.
Looks real promising, and I
need to ask you a favor.
I need you to write
me some 'scriptions
for when I come
back across the border.
Now I may not need 'em, but
if I do, then I'll have 'em.
You know this law the FDA just
passed is total bullshit.
It's all lip-service.
I know. You're right.
And I can't either, I'm sorry.
We can't write scripts for
random people, random drugs.
Plus, what if something goes
wrong with these drugs'?
We could be sued,
lose our license.
I know, I know.
I hear you.
Well, had to give it a shot.
Speaking of, I'll be taking one
this afternoon thinking about you.
Señor?
Nah, you keep that,
Nurse Ratched.
(SINGING WITH STEREO)
Life is strange.
Sing to me, baby.
(STEREO TURNS OFF)
Okay, I'm taking
you to the hospital.
No, no, no. Rayon.
No! Rayon! Trust me you need...
No!
I don't wanna die.
You're not gonna die.
You're not gonna die, now
just come trust me, c'mon.
C'mon!
(CAR HORN HONKS)
VASS: The secretions
the caterpillar uses
to protect itself during
the incubation period
act as a non-toxic
antiviral for humans.
The answer to a question.
Check this out.
This is The Lancet
medical review,
and they published this study
that was conducted in France
and it proves that AZT alone is
too toxic for most to tolerate,
and has no lasting effect
on HIV blood levels.
Now, of course, Avonex
Industries and the NIH,
they didn't include this study
in their press release.
Fuck no, they didn't.
The anti-fungal? Yeah.
Yeah, I read about this.
Want to take some home?
As much as I can carry.
You can come in if you want.
Oh, no.
I took him off it
as you instructed.
He's just on morphine now.
Good.
I'll be in my office.
Thanks for calling.
WOMAN ON PA: Ladies and gentlemen,
we've just been cleared to land
at the Dallas-Forth Worth
International Airport.
Please make sure your seat
belt is securely fastened.
The flight attendants are currently
passing around the cabin
to make a final
compliance check
and pick up any
remaining cups and glasses.
Walker, Dorsett, Blount,
Newsome, Jeff coat.
These are patients?
Yes, sir.
They're also the names of
players on the Dallas Cowboys.
No shit?
That's a hell of a
coincidence, isn't it?
Ain't this a little ridiculous?
You said it.
Can you prove
these are patients?
Can you prove they're not?
RON: How you doin', Denise?
All right.
These are the emergencies.
Where's the idiot?
I thought you knew.
The hospital.
(SLAMMING)
I need security on the
fourth floor right away.
What d'you say? I can't hear you.
(LAUGHING)
Mr. Woodroof.
You need to wait outside.
You son of a bitch.
You murdered him.
Excuse me,
you need to wait outside.
Murderer. You're a murderer!
Security!
You call yourself
a doctor? Huh?
You're a fucking murderer!
Let go of me!
Don't let him kill you! Don't
let him fucking kill you!
You're killing them!
SEVARD: Take him
out of this hospital.
Don't let him pump
that shit in you!
You're a fucking murderer!
(MOANING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(sesame)
Hey?
Mister?
Jesus.
MAN: I got the money.
Excuse me.
Ron, I got two from
Austin, both on AZT.
Their insurance is
paying for their treatment,
but they don't know if
they can afford to switch.
Hook 'em up.
We're pretty cash poor.
Sell the car.
Anemia, cancer,
bone marrow depletion,
seizures,
fever, hearing loss,
impotence, neuropathy.
Sound like AIDS to you?
Nah, that there comes in a box of
AZT, a list of the side effects.
No wonder Rayon is dead.
Rayon was a drug addict.
He didn't die
from one day of AZT,
he died from
the disease as a whole.
And you stole my
prescription pad, Ron,
so don't accuse me of
acting irresponsibly.
Rayon came to
the hospital on his own.
He got dragged out
in a goddamn garbage bag!
He was my friend, too!
"RON". Read that.
(SIGHS)
I want all my HIV patients
on the asymptomatic study
to have their AZT doses
lowered to the minimum.
Six hundred milligrams.
RON: I got over 3,000 people who need
to get their hands on Peptide T,
all right, including me.
I understand. They shut your lab down.
What can I say?
Look, if I don't get it by the end
of the week, I wanna file a lawsuit.
C'mon, Ron.
You lost the restraining
order, remember?
This is Texas.
The court system's
your final resort.
Well, then find a place
where it fucking ain't.
Go to San Francisco.
Get me a goddamn sissy judge.
Just figure it out.
Ten thousand of 'em.
Perfect.
I would like to turn it over to my colleague
from the CDC to talk about prevention.
M r. Wood roof.
Would you kindly tell us
what you're doing?
Oh, I'm just givin' people
information, Richard,
about this trial I'm in.
Wanna make sure they
know what's goin' on.
And what is going on?
Why d'you cut off
Peptide T, Richard, huh?
Non-toxic drug that
I got proof works,
and that the National
Institute of Mental Health,
your own people,
say is completely safe.
Pass this down.
Mr. Woodroof, I'm afraid
that you are nothing more
than a common drug dealer, so if
you'll excuse us, we would like...
Oh, I'm the drug dealer?
No, you're
the fucking drug dealer.
I mean, God damn,
people are dying,
and y'all are
all up there afraid
that we're going to find
an alternative without you.
See, the pharma companies pay
the FDA to push their product.
So, fuck no, they don't
wanna see my research.
All right! It's enough!
I don't have enough cash in my
pocket to make it worth their while.
Tell you what, I'm gonna be a pain in
your ass until I'm six feet under!
Maybe one day, you'll get off
your ass and do your fucking job!
I need you to leave, let's go.
Here, pass these around,
would you?
Come on, sir. Let's go.
Don't listen to
those cocksuckers.
We think it is in everyone's
best interest that you resign.
I won't.
You'll have to fire me.
Eve!
Y'all go fuck yourselves!
(SLAMS DOOR)
Well...
One left.
That took some balls.
Hey, nice warm hug?
Yeah.
That's what you need,
that and a day of
watching bull riding.
(CHUCKLES)
Dr. Wood roof's orders.
You ever miss
your regular life?
Regular life?
What is that?
It doesn't exist.
Yeah, I guess.
No, no, I just...
I just wanna...
What?
Ice cold beer, bull ride again.
Take my woman dancing,
you know?
I want kids.
I mean, I got one
life right? Mine.
But I want somebody
else's sometimes.
Sometimes I feel like I'm fighting
for a life I ain't got time to live.
I want it to mean somethin'.
It does.
(CAR HORN HONKS)
(HONKING)
MAN: Get out
of the road, jackass!
(HONKING)
Sir! You're in
the middle of the street.
Step over by your
vehicle right now.
Step over by your car.
Hey, I got ya!
Sir, step out of the road.
Hey! I got it!
Ron, what the hell
is going on, huh?
D'you understand me?
C'mon. I'll get you home.
JUDGE: The constitution,
specifically the Ninth Amendment,
does not state that
you have the right
to be mentally healthy
or physically healthy.
It does state
that you have a right
to choose your
own medical care,
but that is interpreted as
medical care that is approved
by the Food and
Drug Administration.
Regarding the FDA, the court is highly
disturbed by its bullying tactics
and direct interference with
a drug whose own agency
has found to be non-toxic.
The FDA was formed
to protect people,
not prevent them
from getting help.
The law doesn't seem to make
much common sense sometimes.
They ought to be able to take just
about anything they feel will help,
but that's not the law.
Mr. Woodroof, I'm moved to
compassion by your plight,
but what is lacking here is
legal authority to intervene.
I'm sorry, this case
is hereby dismissed.
DAVID: We lost. (SIGHS)
WOMAN ON PA:
Ladies and gentlemen.
(SHUSHING)
What?
MAN ON PA: Yes, indeed, the
number one spectator event.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Let me hear you, c'mon.
Whoop it up.
Make some noise! It's your
event, the one you paid to see.
It's bull-riding time!
We've got a live one!
The great jawbreaker!
Number 43, Ron Woodroof!
Give the man a helping hand.
And now, here's one
of those top bulls,
the one the cowboys
all wanna ride.
Ain't no denying,
this one means business.
It's all about the mind.
An eight second ride.
Let's go, cowboy!
Pull that rope!
(INAUDIBLE)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Clap your hands, stomp your feet!
Make some noise!
It's bull ride time!